<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slowcooked on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/slowcooked/</link><description>Recent content in slowcooked on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/slowcooked/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dulce de Leche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</guid><description>Delicious milk toffee used on desserts or as a spread. Substitute for Nootella or similar &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;. It is very demanding, so i only recommend you make it if you either can&amp;rsquo;t buy industrial dulce de leche (It will be way more natural than other sweets anyway), or have the time and interest to go through the process. It can be made more easily with sweetened condensed milk, but if you have access to it, you can get DDL anyways.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🍳 Cook time: 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 can (29 ounces) tomato puree 1-1/2 cups plain yogurt 1/2 large onion, finely chopped 2 tablespoons olive oil 4-1/2 teaspoons minced fresh gingerroot 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 tablespoon garam masala 2-1/2 teaspoons salt 1-1/2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 teaspoon paprika 3/4 teaspoon pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2-1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 1-1/2-inch cubes 1 jalapeno pepper, halved and seeded 1 bay leaf 1 tablespoon cornstarch 1 cup heavy whipping cream Hot cooked basmati rice Chopped fresh cilantro, optional Directions In a 5-qt.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Pork Carnitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</guid><description>This recipe makes a lot and is super easy. A whole roast usually makes enough for a few meals (depending on how many people will be eating it). Leftovers can be refrigerated for 4-5 days.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hr 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-11 Ingredients 2 ½ lbs. boneless pork shoulder 6 cloves of garlic, cut into slivers 1 ½ teaspoons cumin ½ teaspoon sazon ¼ teaspoon dry oregano ¾ cup low sodium chicken broth 2-3 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce 2 bay leaves ¼ teaspoon dry adobo seasoning Directions Season pork with kosher salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Chicken Tacos</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients chicken breasts two or three onions (preferably red) seasoning: adobo seasoning paprika cheese (either shredded Mexican blend or crumbling cheese) small tortillas lime cilantro, tomato, lettuce, other desired taco contents Directions Quarter two onions and spread on the bottom of a slow-cooker. Place chicken breasts on top of onions. Season slow-cooker contents liberally with adobo seasoning, paprika and any other desired seasonings, squeeze half of a lime too if desired.</description></item></channel></rss>