<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tortilla on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/tortilla/</link><description>Recent content in Tortilla on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/tortilla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spanish-tortilla.webp" alt="Spanish Tortilla">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 free-range eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 kg of potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potato slices already salted and let them cook for approximately 20 minutes over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the potatoes are frying, beat the eggs in a bowl. Peel and cut the onion as finely as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add olive oil in another frying pan and slowly fry the onion until it gets a slightly golden color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the onion and add it to the bowl with the beaten egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the potatoes from the pan with a slotted spoon, draining the oil away as much as possible, and add them to the bowl with the onion and egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the mixture rest for at least 5 minutes so all the flavors come together. Give it a very gentle stir from time to time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the oil from the pan you used to fry the potatoes. Use the pan to cook the mixture over medium-high fire for about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip it over with the help of a big plate and cook the other side for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Things like the slicing of the potato, the amount of salt and how curdled is the inner part of the tortilla depend on your own taste. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to experiment!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>