<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fry on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/fry/</link><description>Recent content in fry on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/fry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grostoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</guid><description>Very popular fritter in Italian colonies throughout South Brazil. Not to be mistaken with Venetian Crostoli or Chiacchiere, even though those are still made. My grandmother&amp;rsquo;s recipe is more like Castagnole with Crostoli shape, with some post-Italian adaptations.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: A batch like this will last for two days in a family of four. Ingredients A cup of sugar 800g of flour A tablespoon of baking powder A pinch of salt 4 eggs 3 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>Torta Frita Criolla (Argentinian frybread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</guid><description>A &amp;ldquo;merienda&amp;rdquo; (afternoon meal) that is intertwined with the history of colonization on the River Plate region. Never have it by yourself, instead with friends or family, and a cup/gourd of Mate.
⏲️ Prep time: 1h 10min or 2h 10min, (depending on how long you leave it to rest.) 🍳Cook time: 10 minutes. 🍽️ Servings : 10. Ingredients 1.1 pound (1/2 kilo) of all-purpose flour. 4 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tenders Airfried</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Raw chicken strips Flour Egg wash Bread crumbs Olive oil Seasoning: salt and pepper with cayenne or paprika (optional) Directions In a plate, mix a little over a table spoon of spices into your flour. Dip the chicken into the flour one strip at a time coating the entire surface. Dip the floured chicken into the eggwash.</description></item><item><title>Quarkbällchen – Fried curd balls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</guid><description>“Quark” is a type of fresh dairy product. It&amp;rsquo;s usually translated as curd cheese or cottage cheese.
Ingredients 420ml quark (plain yoghurt can be used as a replacement) 2 eggs 6 or 7 tbsp of sugar 2 packets of vanilla sugar 400g flour (500g if using yoghurt) 2 packets of baking powder 1L sunflower oil for frying (Optional) icing sugar (Optional) Alcohol by eye so that they do not soak up so much oil Directions Mix ingredients (quark, eggs, sugar, flour, baking powder) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Pan-seared Chicken Fillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</guid><description>This is a quick and easy recipe to prepare delicious chicken fillets that are juicy on the inside, and crisp on the outside.
Ingredients For this recipe I don&amp;rsquo;t use any exact proportions, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of cooking it one time to get a sense of what the ideal proportions for you are.
Chicken fillet(s); I normally use chicken breasts Wheat flour Paprika Garlic powder Herbes de Provence Directions Rinse the chicken fillets.</description></item></channel></rss>