<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mediterranean on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/mediterranean/</link><description>Recent content in Mediterranean on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/mediterranean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zaatar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a traditional Palestinian-Lebanese way of making Zaatar.
It can be then eaten by dipping bread in olive oil and in the Zaatar or as part of another recipe.
Will hold for a long time in the pantry.
This recipe scales for larger amounts so long you preserve the ratios.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Cup Zaatar leaves (without the stalks), cleaned and dried.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cup sesame (optionally roasted).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cup Sumac.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional: citric acid salt, for extra kick if the Sumac wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough for you.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Lightly roast the sesame in a wide pan until it get a golden brown color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the sesame to completely cool down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix everything together, starting from the Zaatar and sesame while adjusting the Sumac (optionally citric acid) and salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Store in an airtight jar or container.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 Chicken Breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Bulghur Wheat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 oz Mixed Olives, drained&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Roma Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp White Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot. Cover and bring to a boil over high heat. While water comes to a boil, cut tomato into 1/4&amp;quot; pieces. Zest and juice the lemon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garlic and bulghur to the boiling water. Stir to combine, remove pot from heat, cover, and let stand until bulghur is tender and liquid is absorbed (15 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While bulghur rehydrates, pat chicken dry and season with Za&amp;rsquo;atar spice blend, salt, and pepper. Heat a large non-stick pan over medium-high heat. Add 1/2 tsp oil, then the chicken. Sear until golden-brown. Transfer chicken to a sheet and bake on the middle rack in the oven until chicken is cooked through (10-12 mins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, whisk together vinegar, lemon juice, lemon zest, 1 tsp oil, and 1/2 tsp salt in a small bowl. Set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When bulghur is done, fluff with a fork. Add olives, spinach, tomatoes, and half the dressing to the pot. Season with salt and pepper, then stir to combine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thinly slice chicken. Divide bulghur salad between plates, then top with chicken. Sprinkle with feta and drizzle remaining dressing over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tabouleh</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 12&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 cups Cracked Wheat (bulghur)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups Very Hot Water (or as directed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cucumber, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 small Tomatoes, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bunch Green Onions, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Mint (fresh), chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cup Parsley (fresh), chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove Garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Lemon Juice (fresh)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Soak the cracked wheat in the hot water until the water is absorbed, about 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain any excess water, if necessary, and squeeze dry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine the salad ingredients (all but the oil, lemon juice, salt and pepper dressing ingredients) in a medium bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the dressing ingredients together and stir into the salad mix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve chilled or at room temperature.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4-6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 Tbsp Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp dill weed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Parsley, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the small bowl, whisk together oil, vinegar, herbs, spices, and the lemon juice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drizzle dressing over the salad.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle cheese over and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 50 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6-8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="pasta-layer">Pasta layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>600g penne rigate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>salted water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="meat-layer">Meat layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 large onion, finely diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>700g lean ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.5 TB ground allspice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.5 TB ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.25 TSP ground clove (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>340g tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="béchamel-layer">Béchamel layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>226g butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>226g flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1L cold milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>237ml chicken stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>freshly grated nutmeg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grated cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 190°C&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions. Drain and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook onion in a bit of oil until soft. Add meat and cook until browned, breaking meat into small pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain any excess grease and add spices. Stir together and cook ~30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix tomato paste with enough water to create a viscous tomato sauce. Add sauce to meat and simmer 2-3 minutes before setting aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a saucepan melt the butter and add the flour. Cook 2-3 mins until no longer starchy, whisking frequently. Add milk gradually and whisk continuously. Add stock and cook until sauce is thickened. Add nutmeg and season to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add thin béchamel layer to bottom of casserole dish and assemble as follows: half pasta, all the meat sauce, 2nd half of pasta, rest of béchamel and cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake covered for 45 minutes, removing lid last 5-10 minutes to brown top. Let cool 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon.webp" alt="Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll need a good-sized lidded pot that can go in the oven for this. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that then you can use a large roasting tray with sides and cover it with foil, sealing it as best you can. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent celebration or Sunday meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lamb shoulder, or something similar, like lamb shank, preferably on the bone. Get something that will fit in your pot, with room for vegetables around it. For example, I usually get half a shoulder, 2 – 3 lbs, 1 – 1.5kg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a whole head of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 leek&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 lemons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>potatoes (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>yoghurt (optional, to serve)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fresh bread (optional, to serve)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;em>On the night before:&lt;/em> Mix up some olive oil, the juice of half a lemon, the oregano, the rosemary, and some salt and pepper. Rub this mixture into the meat and leave it in the fridge overnight to marinate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>The next day:&lt;/em> Heat the oven to 375°F/190°C/gas mark 5.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Break apart the garlic. You can leave the skin on the cloves, or you can peel them, as you prefer. Chop the carrots, leek, onion, the remaining lemon, and the potatoes into chunks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the meat in the pot with the vegetables underneath and around it. Pour in any marinating juices, as well as a cup of water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for 2½ – 3 hours. Half way through it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to check and see if it needs some more water to keep things from burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the lid and let the meat brown for a few minutes if you think it needs it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pull the meat apart and serve, with yoghurt and fresh bread. You can use the juices as a gravy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>author: skipper-davies
Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 cups red lentils&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 cups water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large red onion, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 medium zucchini, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cups Swiss chard, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bunch of cilantro, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a pan, sauté onions until pink, about 5 minutes. Add chopped Swiss chard and sauté together until chard is wilted, 2-3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After lentils have cooked about 8 minutes, add onion chard mixture, along with diced potatoes and zucchini to the boiling water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to medium-low, cover the pot, and cook until the potatoes and lentils are completely cooked, about 12 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the chopped cilantro. Stir and cook for about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add lemon juice and cumin before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Lemon and oregano chicken traybake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake.webp" alt="Lemon and oregano chicken traybake">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (in 10 minute intervals)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 60 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 chicken thighs (skin on)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g new potato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g bacon lardon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 shallots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 oregano sprigs / heavy sprinkle of oregano leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 lemons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml chicken stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100ml white wine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat oven to 220C/200C with fan/gas 7. While oven is heating up cut the new potatoes into 0.5cm - 1cm slices and tip them into a roasting tray. Drizzle 1tbsp of olive oil on the sliced potatoes, season well and toss to ensure a good coating. Then put the roasting tray into the oven for 20 minutes, or however long until the potatoes start to crisp.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a separate, temporary, tray place the chicken thighs and season them. Cut up the shallots into 1/8 parts, then the lemons into 1/4 wedges. Once this is done, take out the roasting tray and transfer the chicken, challots, lemon wedges and bacon lardons into it, with a final drizzle of 1tbsp of olive oil over the tray&amp;rsquo;s items. Cook for another 20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare the chicken stock and wine to take out the roasting tray for the last time before serving. Pour 200ml of chicken stock and 100ml of white wine over the tray&amp;rsquo;s contents and return it to the oven for a final 20 minutes of cooking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 White onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Eggplant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Egg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg. If it breaks just scramble it, the recipe doesn&amp;rsquo;t call for anything fancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can serve the dish with that oil (provided it is not burnt) or keep it for cooking other stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Aljotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aljotta (&amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;Yo!&amp;rdquo;) is a traditional Maltese light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; white fish that don&amp;rsquo;t turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock. There are a some variants; restaurant versions could very well include lemon juice and shellfish which I don&amp;rsquo;t associate with aljotta. Rice eventually became a staple with it and how much you put in is up to you. I recommend just a little. In fact, there are no ingredient amounts; the picture should give you an idea of the density you&amp;rsquo;re going for. &lt;strong>Fresh herbs are a must&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>