<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mediterranean on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/mediterranean/</link><description>Recent content in mediterranean on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/mediterranean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zaatar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</guid><description>This is a traditional Palestinian-Lebanese way of making Zaatar. It can be then eaten by dipping bread in olive oil and in the Zaatar or as part of another recipe. Will hold for a long time in the pantry. This recipe scales for larger amounts so long you preserve the ratios.
Ingredients 1 Cup Zaatar leaves (without the stalks), cleaned and dried. 1 Cup sesame (optionally roasted). 1 Cup Sumac.</description></item><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Chicken Breasts 1 cup Bulghur Wheat 1 oz Mixed Olives, drained 4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped 2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend 2 Roma Tomatoes 1 Lemon 1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated 2 Tbsp White Vinegar 1 tsp Sugar Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot.</description></item><item><title>Tabouleh</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 2 cups Cracked Wheat (bulghur) 2 cups Very Hot Water (or as directed) 1 Cucumber, chopped 2 small Tomatoes, chopped 1 bunch Green Onions, sliced 1/2 cup Mint (fresh), chopped 2 cup Parsley (fresh), chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 1/2 cup Lemon Juice (fresh) 3/4 cup Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Pepper 2 tsp Salt Directions Soak the cracked wheat in the hot water until the water is absorbed, about 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn 4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced 1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced 1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced 1 small Onion, sliced 1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped 3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 6 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar 1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp dill weed 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper 2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh Directions Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 Ingredients Pasta layer 600g penne rigate salted water Meat layer 1 large onion, finely diced 700g lean ground beef .5 TB ground allspice .5 TB ground cinnamon .25 TSP ground clove (optional) 340g tomato paste Béchamel layer 226g butter 226g flour 1L cold milk 237ml chicken stock freshly grated nutmeg (optional) grated cheese (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 190°C In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need a good-sized lidded pot that can go in the oven for this. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that then you can use a large roasting tray with sides and cover it with foil, sealing it as best you can. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent celebration or Sunday meal.
Ingredients Lamb shoulder, or something similar, like lamb shank, preferably on the bone. Get something that will fit in your pot, with room for vegetables around it.</description></item><item><title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</guid><description>author: skipper-davies Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 3 cups red lentils 12 cups water 1 large red onion, diced 2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced 1 medium zucchini, diced 4 cups Swiss chard, chopped 1 bunch of cilantro, chopped ¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste 1 teaspoon cumin Directions In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.</description></item><item><title>Lemon and oregano chicken traybake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (in 10 minute intervals) 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 8 chicken thighs (skin on) 500g new potato 100g bacon lardon 8 shallots 5 oregano sprigs / heavy sprinkle of oregano leaves 2 tbsp olive oil 2 lemons 200ml chicken stock 100ml white wine Directions Heat oven to 220C/200C with fan/gas 7. While oven is heating up cut the new potatoes into 0.</description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 White onion 1 Eggplant Olive oil Egg (optional) Directions Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring) Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long (Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top (Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg.</description></item><item><title>Aljotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</guid><description>Aljotta (&amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;Yo!&amp;quot;) is a traditional Maltese light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; white fish that don&amp;rsquo;t turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock.</description></item></channel></rss>