<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>italian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/italian/</link><description>Recent content in italian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grostoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</guid><description>Very popular fritter in Italian colonies throughout South Brazil. Not to be mistaken with Venetian Crostoli or Chiacchiere, even though those are still made. My grandmother&amp;rsquo;s recipe is more like Castagnole with Crostoli shape, with some post-Italian adaptations.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: A batch like this will last for two days in a family of four. Ingredients A cup of sugar 800g of flour A tablespoon of baking powder A pinch of salt 4 eggs 3 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>One-Pot Chicken Tetrazzini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Butter 8 oz Mushrooms, sliced 1 small Red Pepper, chopped 1 small Onion, finely chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 4 cups Milk 2 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 8 oz Extra Broad Egg Noodles 5 oz Boursin Garlic and Fine Herbs 3 cup Deli Chicken, cooked and cut into bite-size pieces 1/2 cup Frozen Peas 1/2 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped Small Fresh Basil Leaves (optional) Parmesan, grated Directions Melt butter in a large saucepan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Winter Risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3/4 cup Arborio Rice 1 cup Baby Spinach 2 Garlic Cloves 4 1/2 cup Vegetable Broth 1/4 cup Parmesan Cheese, shredded 1/2 lb Baby Tomatoes 1 Tbsp White Wine Vinegar 1/4 cup Walnuts, chopped 1/2 cup Leek, sliced 1 cup Mushrooms 3 Tbsp Unsalted Butter Directions Combine vegetable broth in a medium pot. Cover and bring to a gentle boil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Chipolata Sausage in Balsamic Vinegar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</guid><description>Easy to prepare Italian dish with lots of flavour great for a relaxing evening dipping bread and sipping wine.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 12 chipolata sausages 4 red onions 500g of cherry tomatoes (preferably mixed species) 4 garlic cloves Fresh basil leaves Black balsamic vinegar 1 loaf of ciabatta bread Directions Pre-heat the oven to 200c (400f) Put the chipolata sausages in an oven dish Cut 4 red onions into quarters spread them out in the oven dish.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter sauce.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min Ingredients spaghetti or fettucine butter heavy cream garlic oregano white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended) lemon/lemon juice (optional) red pepper flakes (optional) seafood, choose from: mussels squid shrimp clams lobster Directions Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow these instructions. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook slightly once we add the sauce.</description></item><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</guid><description>One serving should be enough to cover a pizza. The sauce can be stored in the refrigerator for ~16 days if put into a conserving jar.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 2 onions 3 garlic cloves olive oil 700g tomato sauce 6 spoon tomato concentrate 0.5 spoon sugar 1 spoon salt 1 spoon pepper 1 spoon thyme/rosemary (finely chopped) 1 spoon oregano (finely chopped) 2 spoon basil (finely chopped) Directions Finely chop onions and garlic into a pot.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</guid><description>This is a recipe combining two others and adding stuff on top. This is more of an example of possible ingredients, you can replace any of them with others.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 serving Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough 1 serving Easy Pizza Sauce ~80g mozzarella cheese ~40g Edam cheese ~40g Tilsitter cheese salami (optional) ham (optional) salsiccia (optional) aubergine (optional) zucchini (optional) mushrooms (optional) olives (optional) arugula salad (add after pizza is done) (optional) fresh basil leaves (add after pizza is done) (optional) Directions Cover a baking tray fully with a thin layer of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</guid><description>One serving(~200g dough) should be enough to make a pizza. The dough can be stored in the refrigerator for ~2 days. For it to last longer, it should be stored in the freezer.
⏲️ Prep time: 70 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g flour (Wholemeal Wheat Flour) 280ml lukewarm water 8g dry yeast 3.5 spoon olive oil 1.5 teaspoon salt Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp Fettuccine Alfredo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</guid><description>Shrimp fettuccine alfredo is one of the best tasting and low effort dishes. The recipe i give below yields an alfredo sauce that is a bit on the thicker side. If you want a thinner sauce, adding a touch or two more milk will thin out the sauce. This is a great meal for 3-4 people or you can eat one serving and freeze the rest for 2-3 more dinners.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Pasta Olive oil Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers Crushed garlic cloves Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta) Chopped parsley Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended) Directions Start heating up water for the pasta. Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat. Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Sausage Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</guid><description>A delicious spicy pasta dish, super easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a student and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap for how much food you get. I found it in a newspaper a while back and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it with you guys because it&amp;rsquo;s my favourite meal. I also like to drink the excess red wine while cooking which adds to the enjoyment of cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 red onions, chopped Olive oil 6 spicy Italian sausages 1 sprig rosemary, needles finely chopped 1 red chilli, deseeded and diced A large glass of red wine (approx.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</guid><description>The ricotta is an Italian cheese made by cooking the whey (liquid byproduct of the cheese production), by cooking it at an high temperature (80-90°C), hence the name &amp;ldquo;ricotta&amp;rdquo;, which means &amp;ldquo;cooked again&amp;rdquo;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s typically made from the whey, you can make it directly from the milk as well.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of whey 500ml of milk (or if not using whey, 2l of milk) 10g of table salt 6g of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Preparation Pour the milk (and/or whey) and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 80°C.</description></item><item><title>Ragu Napoletano</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid><description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 Ingredients Tomato Sauce 6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional) Aromatics and Herbs 8 cloves garlic 1.5 white onions 6-8 oz red wine 8 fresh basil leaves Dry oregano Red pepper Meat 1-2 lb pork tenderloin 1-2 lb sweet and or spicy Italian sausage 1 lb cubed stewing beef (chuck, short rib, or oxtail) Meatballs 1-2 lb total of ground beef chuck, veal, and pork 1 1/2 cups grated Pecorino Romano cheese 1 1/2 cups breadcrumbs (baked stale bread, oregano, salt and pepper pulsed in a food processor) 2-3 eggs Splash of milk Handfull of fresh parsley chopped Sprig of fresh basil chopped 1/2 onion minced 4-8 cloves garlic minced Directions If you already have tomato sauce skip to step 5 For fresh tomatoes, wash and cut out off the green stems of the tomatoes and cut them into a few chunks and lightly salt them over a collander or strainer so they release water and break down quicker For canned tomatoes, use your hands to crush the peeled tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t use a food processor) In a large stock pot cook down the tomatoes for approximately 30 mins then use a food mill or strainer to remove the skins and seeds to yield tomato sauce (this can be done beforehand and frozen / canned for months) Mix all the ingredients in the Meatballs section by hand and form equal sized meatballs Either bake the meatballs at 400°F until brown or fry them with the the other meats in step 7 Coat the bottom of a dutch oven or large stock pot with olive oil and sear each meat one by one, removing from the pot once browned on the outside (do not cook the meat all the way through) Sweat the onion and garlic, then deglaze the pan with the red wine Fill the pot with the seared meat, tomato sauce, add the fresh basil, then season with dried oregano, red pepper, salt, pepper, and a pinch of sugar to taste Cook on very low flame uncovered for 4-5 hours stirring making sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t burn Serve over cooked dry pasta such as ziti, penne, rigatoni Portion the sauce and meats and freeze in containers for up to 4-6 months</description></item><item><title>Ravioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</guid><description>
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Dough 4 eggs 400 g 00 flour Drizzle of olive oil Cheese Filling 1 lemon 50 g grated Pecorino Romano cheese 250 g ricotta 1 egg Seafood Fillings Chopped leftover lobster legs, lobster tail, or minced crab (optional) Directions The basic rule of thumb I use for pasta is 100g, 1 egg per person For this recipe you can go two ways, the old school &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; method or a kitchen aid mixer (skip to step 7) For the well method, pile the flour onto the counter and with your hand carve a hole or a well in the center Crack the eggs into the center of the well, and drizzle a bit of olive oil into the center With a fork, begin slowly breaking up, mixing, and incorporating the egg into the flour until there is no longer any loose egg that can escape the outer well border At this point use your hands to bring the sandy mixture together and knead the dough for about 5-10 minutes or until the dough is smooth For the stand mixer method just throw all the ingredients into the mixer with a dough hook and set it to level 4 for about 3-5 minutes and it will be done You might need to scrape the sides down and maybe hand knead the dough a bit longer after it&amp;rsquo;s done to make it into a nice smooth ball Cover the dough with plastic wrap and let it rest in the fridge a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to roll out (15-30 mins) While the dough is resting, make the filling by first mixing the ricotta and egg into a bowl Zest and juice a lemon peel into the bowl Optionally add seafood ingredients at this point Grate the Pecorino into the bowl, add salt and pepper to taste, and mix to distribute the ingredients evenly Take out the dough and cut it into 4 pieces, keeping the ones not currently being worked on covered so they don&amp;rsquo;t dry out Roll the dough out with a pasta machine down to the point where you can just barely see your hand through it (setting 2-3 out of 7) or roll it out with a rolling pin into a long sheet, maybe like 16 x 8 inches or so At this point you can either cut the sheet in half and make two sheets, a top and bottom, or one sheet, where you will fold the dough over and use the folded seam as one side of the ravioli Using a teaspoon, evenly space out the ricotta filling onto the sheets, leaving a few inches on each side for the seams As stated in step 16, either take the 2nd sheet and place it over top or fold over the dough and press down firmly, forcing out any air and making sure the two pieces of dough stick You may need to brush some water onto the dough if it is too heavily floured and not sticking Using a fancy pasta cutter, a knife, or even a pizza cutter, cut evenly between the seams of the raviolis to separate them If you used a pasta cutter, you are now done, store the raviolis on a floured wax paper sheet or freeze them for later If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a pasta cutter, use a fork to press down the dough around the edges of the cut raviolis to ensure they are firmly closed and no leaks or air bubbles are visible, or else they will explode when cooked To cook, throw them in salted boiling water and they will let you know when they&amp;rsquo;re done when they float to the top (1-2 minutes) Serve the seafood version with a simple fresh red sauce and basil, or spice it up a bit and go with a base of red sauce with some added heavy cream, and a pinch of red pepper flakes to make a pink sauce for the seafood version</description></item><item><title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g pasta 500g broccoli 4 eggs 200g scamorza cheese 400g béchamel sage (optional) parmesan cheese (optional) Directions Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside. Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes. While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan. Put a layer of béchamel. Put a layer of pasta.</description></item><item><title>Italian Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2.5 - 3.25 hr 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients 600g or 5 cups bread flour (or all-purpose if not available) 1 packet (appr. 2 1/4 tsp or 7g) active dry yeast olive oil for greasing Directions Follow directions on the packet to activate yeast in a bowl large enough for mixing the dough Add enough water for a total of 400g or 1 3/4 cups (i.</description></item><item><title>Basic Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid><description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste Directions Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</guid><description>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 5-6 Ingredients Ricotta cheese One large egg Parmesan cheese Oregano (Optional) Directions Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handful of finely grated parmesan. Add the oregano and the egg and mix. Add salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</guid><description>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&amp;rsquo;s all I had that day.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g) Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&amp;rsquo;d like) Extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup (40g) Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g) White wine 1/4 cup (60g) Tomato passata 10oz (300g) Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g) (optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan Directions Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.</description></item><item><title>Bolognese Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid><description>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours Ingredients extra virgin olive oil 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 large onion 2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional) 200 grams pancetta (optional) 300 grams beef mince 350 grams pork mince 350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork) 140 grams concentrated tomato paste 690 grams diced tomatoes water 1 can peeled tomatoes 1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open) 1 glass of milk (optional) 1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional) Directions Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Alla Norma</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid><description>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 aubergines (900g) 300g spaghetti 100ml olive oil 5 garlic cloves, minced 1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes) 2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon caster sugar Fresh basil Directions Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</description></item><item><title>Baked Mostaccioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</guid><description>Pasta baked in dish with spicy sauce
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 bowls Ingredients 24 oz or 1 jar of Fradiavolo Sauce (Victoria) 1 box Mostaccioli Rigati or Penne Rigati (Ronzoni) ~8 oz shredded Mozzarella Cheese (Poly-O) I&amp;rsquo;ve found that pre-shredded cheese doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good as shredding it right before cooking. 2x 2 quart (8&amp;quot;) baking dishes or 1 large baking dish (see picture below) Directions Bring a pot to a boil and cook pasta for 6 minutes (very al dente).</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential) 50g Butter 100g Flour 200ml Milk 400g Cheddar Cheese 6 Rashers of bacon (optional) Directions Grate the cheese. Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares. Start cooking the pasta. Start melting the butter in another saucepan. Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides.</description></item><item><title>Classic béchamel sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid><description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min Ingredients 5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg Directions Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description></item><item><title>Lasagna</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</guid><description>A nice recipe for amazing fully home-made lasagna.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients Parmesan cheese Emental cheese (optional) Dry mozzarella cheese Fresh Bolognese sauce or about 1 litre worth of store-bought sauce Béchamel sauce or ricotta lasagna filling Lasagna pasta sheets Directions Prepare the bolognese or jared pasta sauce. When the sauce is almost done cooking prepare your béchamel or ricotta filling.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20-30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Olive oil 1 shallot 4 cloves of garlic 300g button or crimini mushrooms 400g risotto rice (Arborio, Carnaroli or Vialone Nano) 1/2 cup white wine (optional) Mushroom or chicken stock Butter Grated Pecorino or Parmesan cheese Directions Finely mince the shallot and garlic and slice the mushrooms into large pieces. Heat a pan with some olive oil on medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti aglio e olio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</guid><description>Aglio e olio, pasta with garlic and olive oil, is one of the simplest yet greatest pasta dishes of all time. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, easy, and uses a lot of basic pantry ingredients which makes this a convenient weeknight meal.
🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound (500g) spaghetti (or similarly shaped pasta) 1/2 cup (110g) extra virgin olive oil 5-6 cloves of garlic 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes A bunch of fresh parsley Directions Heat a large skillet on medium-high heat, start cooking the pasta.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</guid><description>author: postbellum Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &amp;ldquo;Gaeta&amp;rdquo; olives, and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.
⏲️Prep time: ~18 min 🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min 🍽️Servings: 4 Ingredients Pot of water 320g italian spaghetti 2 garlic cloves 10g salted capers 25g anchovies in oil 800g peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo; 1 bunch of parsley 100g Gaeta olives 2 chopped chillies A pinch of salt Directions Wash capers from salt, then cut them Pit and crush Gaeta olives Wash and chop the bunch of parsley Start cooking the pasta until al dente.</description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups Tomato purée Parmigiano (grated) Parsley Directions Start cooking the pasta. Mix the cream with the purée and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down to medium and add the grated parmigiano.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula Directions Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste. Simmer for 3 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Red Sauce (Ragu all'Italiana)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</guid><description>My great-grandma&amp;rsquo;s red sauce. All purpose: good for pastas, lasagnas, subs, etc.
⏲️ Prep time: 12 mins 🍳 Cook time: Simmer all day 🍽️ Servings: 7 Ingredients 1/3 lb salt pork 2 lb chuck roast 3 Cloves of garlic Crushed hot red pepper Sweet onion Large carrot 2 Bay leaves 2 tbsp. Olive oil (she used mazola oil) 12 oz. Can tomato paste 29 oz. Diced tomatoes 29 oz. Tomato puree Directions Mince the garlic, peel the carrot, peel and cut the onion in half.</description></item><item><title>Frittata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid><description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6 Ingredients 4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6 Ingredients For the sauce ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional) For the meatballs 1 lb.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid><description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese. Directions Preheat oven to 400F/200C.</description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>Ingredients Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional) Directions Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs. Mix in and let eggs cook using heat from the pot and tortellini.</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour) Directions Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description></item><item><title>Caesar Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid><description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing Directions Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons. Grate Parmesan over salad.</description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional) Directions Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil Directions Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat. Add enough olive oil to gently fry the crumbles.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Parmesan</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</guid><description>The recipe that started this very site.
Ingredients chicken breasts tomatoes (San Marzano is best) mozzarella cheese parmesan cheese bread crumbs eggs flour pasta sauce Directions Slice the chicken breasts through their width so that they are as flat as possible. Pound breasts as flat as possible. Add flour to a bowl or basin large enough to fit a breast, add pepper. Crack eggs into another large bowl or basin and whisk them.</description></item><item><title>Gnocchi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</guid><description>Gnocchi is a pasta based on potato, making it a less bloating alternative to other kinds of pasta. They are substantial and can be roasted in butter and other ingredients.
Ingredients potatoes flour tomato parmesan butter sage or oregano or thyme Directions Boil potatoes (with their skins) until mashable. Slice potatoes in two and scoop them out of their skin. Mash with a potato-masher while adding kosher salt. Slowly begin to add flour while mashing and kneading until there are no lumps of potato and the potato/flour mixture takes on a dough-like consistency.</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea. Bring water to a rolling boil.</description></item><item><title>Pasta sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid><description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced) Directions Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crushed and sliced garlic until translucent. Add San Marzano tomatoes, include the liquids from the can if possible.</description></item><item><title>Tuscan Style Pork Roast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</guid><description>An herbaceous pancetta stuffed pork roast with a crispy exterior. Finished with a lemon vinaigrette. Adapted from Binging With Babish whose instructions are notoriously bad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 people Equipment Food processor Fine mesh strainer Cast iron skillet Butchers twine Ingredients 1 pork Roast 2-3 Tbsp fresh rosemary 8 cloves garlic, minced ⅓ cup high quality olive oil 1 lemon 4 oz pancetta or bacon 1 tsp fresh parsley Directions Preheat oven to 275°F (135°C) Butterfly the roast by cutting into three parts by cutting into the side starting a third of the way up the roast.</description></item></channel></rss>