<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicken on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/chicken/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chicken on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Biscuit Potpie Recipe</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1-2/3 cups frozen mixed vegetables, thawed 1-1/2 cups cubed cooked chicken 1 can (10-3/4 ounces) condensed cream of chicken soup, undiluted 1/4 teaspoon dried thyme 1 cup biscuit/baking mix 1/2 cup whole milk 1 large egg  Directions  Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). In a large bowl, combine the vegetables, chicken, soup and thyme. Pour into an ungreased deep-dish 9-in. pie plate. Combine the biscuit mix, milk and egg; spoon over chicken mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 6  Ingredients  3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter 1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs) 4 shallots, finely chopped 1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar 1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream Finely chopped parsley (optional)  Directions  Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6  Ingredients  16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</guid>
      <description>Hearty soup that is adaptable to customizing to your desired vegetables or other additions
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings:  Ingredients  2 chicken breasts 1 Onion 2 carrots 2 celery stalks 32 oz / 950ml Chicken Stock or Broth Pasta (Optional)  Directions  Cook chicken breasts, shred, and set aside in a bowl. Cut up carrots and celery, place in pot and saute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stock or Bone Broth</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</guid>
      <description>Chicken stock, or &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; is not a final dish in itself, but is used in many soups and other dishes to add great taste to something otherwise very simple. While it is easy to make, it sells for very expensive in the store, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to know to make by yourself since it can be done very cheaply.
Ingredients  a whole raw chicken with organs removed (Drumsticks or thighs alone might suffice if a whole chicken is unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Tenders Airfried</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min  Ingredients  Raw chicken strips Flour Egg wash Bread crumbs Vegetable oil Seasoning:salt and pepper with cayenne or paprika (optional)  Directions  In a plate, mix a little over a table spoon of spices into your flour. Dip the chicken into the flour one strip at a time coating the entire surface. Dip the floured chicken into the eggwash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Wings</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</guid>
      <description>Perfectly cooked fall off the bone buffalo wings.
Ingredients  Chicken wings and drums Enough Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot Sauce to marinate and top dress* Reynold&amp;rsquo;s Oven Bag  Directions  Soak your wings in Franks RedHot overnight Preheat your oven to 350°F (175°C) Transfer wings to the Reynold&amp;rsquo;s bag, seal it, and put it in the oven for an hour Crank up your grill† to high heat Throw the wings on the grill to char the skin and dress with a light top coat of Franks  * Not the &amp;ldquo;wing sauce&amp;rdquo; version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Very easy, high protein.
 Servings: 2  Ingredients  1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice 1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas 1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli) 2 chicken breasts 1 tbsp honey 1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce 1 tbsp minced garlic  Directions  Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in. While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>This is a very easy and simple Japanese style ramen noodle soup. This is very cheap to make, and you can really customise this however you wish with the garnish. This is my own spin inspired by other recipes that I found.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 20 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  750ml Chicken stock 4 Pork chops OR 4 Chicken Breasts Set honey 3 Garlic cloves Soy sauce Worcestershire sauce Ginger, sliced Chinese 5 Spice 1 Red Chilli, sliced and deseeded (Optional, but recommended) 375g Ramen Noodles (Medium Egg Noodles work well too) 100g Spinach (Optional) 4 Tbsp Sweetcorn (Optional) Sesame seeds (Optional) 4 Boiled Eggs (Optional) 1 Sheet of Dried Nori (Optional) Spring Onion, chopped (Optional)  Directions  For the broth, add 700ml of chicken stock to a large boiling pot with the garlic, ginger, soy sauce, chinese five spice, chili, and 300ml of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon and oregano chicken traybake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (in 10 minute intervals) 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  8 chicken thighs (skin on) 500g new potato 100g bacon lardon 8 shallots 5 oregano sprigs / heavy sprinkle of oregano leaves 2 tbsp olive oil 2 lemons 200ml chicken stock 100ml white wine  Directions  Heat oven to 220C/200C with fan/gas 7. While oven is heating up cut the new potatoes into 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nashville Chicken Sandwich</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</guid>
      <description>If you love spicy foods and chicken then this Nashville Hot Chicken sandwich recipe is just for you. It takes some time with prepping and process but when you take that first bite all the effort will be worth it. It’s unlike any other fried chicken recipe that includes double frying your chicken and using the same cooking oil from your fry as a sauce for the Nashville Hot Chicken spice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pan-seared Chicken Fillet</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick and easy recipe to prepare delicious chicken fillets that are juicy on the inside, and crisp on the outside.
Ingredients For this recipe I don&amp;rsquo;t use any exact proportions, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of cooking it one time to get a sense of what the ideal proportions for you are.
 Chicken fillet(s); I normally use chicken breasts Wheat flour Paprika Garlic powder Herbes de Provence  Directions  Rinse the chicken fillets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted chicken breast</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</guid>
      <description>How to roast chicken breast with a &amp;ldquo;leave-in&amp;rdquo; probe thermometer. The thermometer ensures the chicken comes out juicy and delicious.
Ingredients  Boneless skinless chicken breast(s) 1/4 stick of butter per chicken breast Seasoning (optional)  Directions  Fill a large bowl with enough water to submerge the chicken. Add salt to the water until it&amp;rsquo;s fully saturated. Put the chicken under the water and let it sit for 20-40 minutes at room temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Chicken Curry</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</guid>
      <description>An easy chicken curry recipe which scales very well (double it, triple it, etc.). Best served with rice.
Servings: 3-4
Ingredients Spices
 1 ½ tsp Coriander 1 tsp Cumin ½ tsp Turmeric ½ tsp Ground Fennel Seeds ½ tsp Cinnamon ½ tsp Black Pepper ½ tsp Ginger ¼ tsp Mustard ¼ tsp Ground Cloves Sriracha Sauce (optional)  Main Ingredients
 ¼ cup (½ stick) Butter 1 large Onion 4 cloves Garlic 2-3 cups Chicken Broth 2-3 cups Crushed or Pureed Tomatoes 1 ½ lbs Boneless Skinless Chicken Breasts  Directions  Mince the garlic and dice the onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow-cooked Chicken Tacos</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  chicken breasts two or three onions (preferably red) seasoning:  adobo seasoning paprika   cheese (either shredded Mexican blend or crumbling cheese) small tortillas lime cilantro, tomato, lettuce, other desired taco contents  Directions  Quarter two onions and spread on the bottom of a slow-cooker. Place chicken breasts on top of onions. Season slow-cooker contents liberally with adobo seasoning, paprika and any other desired seasonings, squeeze half of a lime too if desired.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
