<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dessert on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/dessert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dessert on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/dessert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description> ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients Filling  900 g (4-5) golden delicious apples 15 g (1 tbsp) lemon juice 50 g white sugar 65 g brown sugar 5 g (1 tsp) cinnamon 1-2 g nutmeg 15 g cornstarch 15 g ice water 226 g (2 sticks) cold butter, cut into slices  Crust  350 g flour 5 g salt 30 g white sugar 225 g butter 50-100 ml ice water  Egg Wash  1 egg (optional) 15 g water (optional)  Directions  Peel and cut the apples into 1-2 inch strips Put the apples in a bowl and mix in the lemon juice, sugar, cinnamon, nutmeg, and cornstarch and let it sit for 15 mins to release water Transfer the filling mixture to a sauce pan and reduce the liquid over medium to low heat for around 15 mins, stirring regularly, then turn off the gas While the filling is sitting / reducing, start the crust by putting the flour, salt, sugar, and pieces of butter in a food processor Run the food processor until it resembles a coarse sand (5-10 seconds) then start dripping in the ice water until the mixture starts to chunk together You&amp;rsquo;ll know when it&amp;rsquo;s done if you can pinch the dough with your hand and it sticks together Preheat oven to 350°F then start making the pie crust Cut the dough in half and roll both halves out with a rolling pin until they are big enough to cover your pie pan (around 9 inch diameter) Put the bottom half dough into the pie pan and cut off the excess dough with a knife Dump the sauce pan full of the filling into the pie pan and even it out Cover the pie filling with the top dough and fold over and tuck in the excess crust Use a fork or your fingers to pinch down the top crust to the bottom crust so you don&amp;rsquo;t have air gaps Optionally you can now brush on the egg wash to make the crust get a shiny golden brown color when it cooks Cut a few slits in the top crust with a knife to give it a nice design and allow for air to release Bake 45 minutes at 350°F or until the crust is brown to your liking and the apples are bubbling inside  Contribution  mfed3 - xmr: 48eEMdYtCQaV5wY7wvmxK6jCxKkia9dgpNTMNT1do7RLWXCwWDgSKjN3kiZ6yHbAuAXWgDGN6imnGT9NPeHWD7zX9hSyHu2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple strudel</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-strudel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-strudel/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 6  Ingredients  Puff pastry Apricot jam (about 300 g | 10 oz) 3 apples Ground cinnamon Breadcrumbs / crushed cookies Butter (optional) Powdered sugar (optional)  Directions  Peel and cut the apples in thin slices. Roll out the puff pastry with a rolling pin. Spread the jam over the puff pastry with a spoon. Arrange the apple slices over the jam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.
Ingredients  2 cups all purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda Spices:  1 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/4 teaspoon ginger   1/4 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas) 2 eggs 1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine) 1/2 cup butter or vegetable oil 1/4 cup crushed walnuts  Directions  Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C) Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, oil, sugar) in one bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min  Ingredients  3 bananas 100 g / ½ cups butter 150 g / ¾ cups sugar 2 eggs 1½ tsp. cooking powder 260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour 50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate 50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate some vanilla sugar (optional)  Directions  Peel the bananas and mush them together. Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolinhos de Coco</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid>
      <description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min  Ingredients  300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional)  Directions  Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brigadeiro</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</guid>
      <description>A very traditional Brazilian dessert that is present in every Brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.
Ingredients  One can of condensed milk. Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder. One spoon of butter (Actual butter and preferably unsalted. No margarine!) Sprinkles (Optional)  Directions  Add all ingredients into a pan. Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) until it stops sticking to the bottom of the pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies </title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description> ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  230 g melted butter (2 sticks) 330 g bread flour 5 g salt 5 g baking soda 100-200 g white sugar 100-200 g brown sugar 1 egg 15 g milk 5 g vanilla 225 g 50-70% dark chocolate chips or semi-sweet milk chocolate chips  Directions  Preheat oven to 375°F Mix the flour, baking soda, and salt in a bowl Using a mixer or whisk, beat the butter, sugar, eggs, and vanilla in a separate bowl for a few mins Combine and stir in the dry ingredients, then the chocolate chips Use an ice cream scooper or spoon to make uniform balls of cookie dough to the size you like and evenly space them out on a parchment paper lined baking sheet (you may need more than one sheet depending on the size of the cookies) Bake in the oven one baking sheet at a time for around 8-10 minutes, taking them out when they start to brown Cool for a few minutes then put them on a cooling rack  Contribution  mfed3 - xmr: 48eEMdYtCQaV5wY7wvmxK6jCxKkia9dgpNTMNT1do7RLWXCwWDgSKjN3kiZ6yHbAuAXWgDGN6imnGT9NPeHWD7zX9hSyHu2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Crêpes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid>
      <description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients  300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil  Directions  Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek Easter Cookies</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid>
      <description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies  Ingredients  1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more)  Directions  Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matcha Cookies</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
 115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut  Directions  Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients  2 eggs 40g sugar (3 tbsp) 20g honey (1 tbsp) 60ml milk (4 tbsp) (you can use water instead) 120g oat flour (1 cup) 1 tsp baking powder (or baking soda + some acid to activate it) Raspberry jam (optional)  Directions  Mix eggs, sugar, honey and milk. In another bowl mix oat flour and baking powder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scandinavian Coffee Cake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 cake  Ingredients  1/2 cup milk 1/2 cup shortening 1/2 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 package active dry yeast 1/4 cup warm (not hot) water 3 cup sifted enriched Flour 2 eggs, beaten melted butter, or margarine 2/3 cup firmly packed brown sugar 2 teaspoon cinnamon chopped walnuts  Directions  Scald milk. Add shortening, sugar, and salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torrijas</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid>
      <description>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter). It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min  Ingredients  Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf. Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.) Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
