<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peruvian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/peruvian/</link><description>Recent content in Peruvian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/peruvian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ceviche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/ceviche.webp" alt="tilapia ceviche on rice">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ceviche is a South American dish which originated in Peru. The following recipe will only cover
the bare minimum ingredients, so feel free to experiment by adding things like garlic, ginger, peppers
tomatoes, cilantro, other citrus juices, and anything else you feel might taste good in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Seafood&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lime Juice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Slice your onion as thinly as you can then let them all sit in a
bowl of cold water for a while. Soaking your onion slices like this
will make it so that their flavor is not as strong so that it won&amp;rsquo;t
overpower everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While your onion is soaking cut your chosen seafood into cubes.
Ceviche can be made with any type of seafood but fish with white
meat native to South America, or things like shrimp and octopus are best. Season your cubed seafood generously with salt
and pepper and place in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Squeeze the juice of several limes onto your seafood, remember when
shopping for limes the softer ones will have the most juice. You
want to get good coverage over all your meat but it is important to
remember that there is such a thing as too much lime.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the onion slices then cover and let sit in the fridge. You can
get away with eating it after only an hour but ceviche gets better
as it ages so it may be best to have more patience and let it sit
overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Arroz Chaufa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peruvian-chinese dish. Easy to cook just add and mix everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/arroz-chaufa-2.webp" alt="Arroz Chaufa">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bell Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chicken&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Welsh Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/arroz-chaufa-1.webp" alt="Ingredients">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the chicken into pieces and fry it. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook scrambled eggs. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the rice. If it is yesterday&amp;rsquo;s rice better, preferably without salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the welsh onion and bell pepper into small squares.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix everything over low heat, adding soy sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional: Add bacon, sesame oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If everything is salty, you can reduce it with just a teaspoon of sugar, especially if you cook the rice with salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>