<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italian on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/italian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italian on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  500g pasta 500g broccoli 4 eggs 200g scamorza cheese 400g béchamel sage (optional) parmesan cheese (optional)  Directions  Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside. Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes. While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan. Put a layer of béchamel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Meatballs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste  Directions  Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes
 ⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours  Ingredients  extra virgin olive oil 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 large onion 2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional) 200 grams pancetta (optional) 300 grams beef mince 350 grams pork mince 350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork) 140 grams concentrated tomato paste 690 grams diced tomatoes water 1 can peeled tomatoes 1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open) 1 glass of milk (optional) 1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional)  Directions  Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacio e Pepe</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid>
      <description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients  Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour)  Directions  Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar Salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid>
      <description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients  Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing  Directions  Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula  Directions  Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients make or break it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional)  Directions  Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential) 50g Butter 100g Flour 200ml Milk 400g Cheddar Cheese 6 Rashers of bacon (optional)  Directions  Grate the cheese. Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares. Start cooking the pasta. Start melting the butter in another saucepan. Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Parmesan</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</guid>
      <description>The recipe that started this very site.
Ingredients  chicken breasts tomatoes (San Marzano is best) mozzarella cheese parmesan cheese bread crumbs eggs flour pasta sauce  Directions  Slice the chicken breasts through their width so that they are as flat as possible. Pound breasts as flat as possible. Add flour to a bowl or basin large enough to fit a breast, add pepper. Crack eggs into another large bowl or basin and whisk them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6  Ingredients  16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinque Pi</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid>
      <description>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo
 ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups Tomato purée Parmigiano (grated) Parsley  Directions  Start cooking the pasta. Mix the cream with the purée and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down to medium and add the grated parmigiano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frittata</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid>
      <description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6  Ingredients  4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional)  Directions  Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnocchi</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>Gnocchi is a pasta based on potato, making it a less bloating alternative to other kinds of pasta. They are substantial and can be roasted in butter and other ingredients.
Ingredients  potatoes flour tomato parmesan butter sage or oregano or thyme  Directions  Boil potatoes (with their skins) until mashable. Slice potatoes in two and scoop them out of their skin. Mash with a potato-masher while adding kosher salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Italian Bread</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 2.5 - 3.25 hr 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min  Ingredients  600g or 5 cups bread flour (or all-purpose if not available) 1 packet (appr. 2 1/4 tsp or 7g) active dry yeast olive oil for greasing  Directions  Follow directions on the packet to activate yeast in a bowl large enough for mixing the dough Add enough water for a total of 400g or 1 3/4 cups (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagna</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</guid>
      <description>A nice recipe for amazing fully home-made lasagna.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 6  Ingredients  Parmesan cheese Emental cheese (optional) Dry mozzarella cheese Fresh Bolognese sauce or about 1 litre worth of store-bought sauce Béchamel sauce or ricotta lasagna filling Lasagna pasta sheets  Directions  Prepare the bolognese or jared pasta sauce. When the sauce is almost done cooking prepare your béchamel or ricotta filling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom risotto</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20-30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  Olive oil 1 shallot 4 cloves of garlic 300g button or crimini mushrooms 400g risotto rice (Arborio, Carnaroli or Vialone Nano) 1/2 cup white wine (optional) Mushroom or chicken stock Butter Grated Pecorino or Parmesan cheese  Directions  Finely mince the shallot and garlic and slice the mushrooms into large pieces. Heat a pan with some olive oil on medium-high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta (store bought)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients  pasta basil (optional) butter (optional)  Directions  Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Alla Norma</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid>
      <description>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  3 aubergines (900g) 300g spaghetti 100ml olive oil 5 garlic cloves, minced 1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes) 2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon caster sugar Fresh basil  Directions  Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid>
      <description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients  a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced)  Directions  Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crush and sliced garlic until translucent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ragu Napoletano</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12  Ingredients Tomato Sauce  6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional)  Aromatics and Herbs  8 cloves garlic 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ragù</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil  Directions  Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Sauce (Ragu all&#39;Italiana)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</guid>
      <description>My great-grandma&amp;rsquo;s red sauce. All purpose: good for pastas, lasagnas, subs, etc.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 12 mins 🍳 Cook time: Simmer all day 🍽️ Servings: 7  Ingredients  1/3 lb salt pork 2 lb chuck roast 3 Cloves of garlic Crushed hot red pepper Sweet onion Large carrot 2 Bay leaves 2 tbsp. Olive oil (she used mazola oil) 12 oz. Can tomato paste 29 oz. Diced tomatoes 29 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</guid>
      <description>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 5-6  Ingredients  Ricotta cheese One large egg Parmesan cheese Oregano (Optional)  Directions  Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handful of finely grated parmesan. Add the oregano and the egg and mix. Add salt and pepper to taste.  Contribution  Josiah - website, donate  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti aglio e olio</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</guid>
      <description>Aglio e olio, pasta with garlic and olive oil, is one of the simplest yet greatest pasta dishes of all time. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, easy, and uses a lot of basic pantry ingredients which makes this a convenient weeknight meal.
 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  1 pound (500g) spaghetti (or similarly shaped pasta) 1/2 cup (110g) extra virgin olive oil 5-6 cloves of garlic 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes A bunch of fresh parsley  Directions  Heat a large skillet on medium-high heat, start cooking the pasta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti all&#39;amatriciana</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</guid>
      <description>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&amp;rsquo;s all I had that day.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g) Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&amp;rsquo;d like) Extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup (40g) Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g) White wine 1/4 cup (60g) Tomato passata 10oz (300g) Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g) (optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan  Directions  Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</guid>
      <description>Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &amp;ldquo;Gaeta&amp;rdquo; olives, and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.
 ⏲️Prep time: ~18 min 🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min 🍽️Servings: 4  Ingredients  Pot of water 320g italian spaghetti 2 garlic cloves 10g salted capers 25g anchovies in oil 800g peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo; 1 bunch of parsley 100g Gaeta olives 2 chopped chillies A pinch of salt  Directions  Wash capers from salt, then cut them Pit and crush Gaeta olives Wash and chop the bunch of parsley Start cooking the pasta until al dente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6  Ingredients For the sauce  ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional)  For the meatballs  1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tortellini</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional)  Directions  Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuscan Style Pork Roast</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</guid>
      <description>An herbaceous pancetta stuffed pork roast with a crispy exterior. Finished with a lemon vinaigrette. Adapted from Binging With Babish whose instructions are notoriously bad.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 people  Equipment  Food processor Fine mesh strainer Cast iron skillet Butchers twine  Ingredients  1 pork Roast 2-3 Tbsp fresh rosemary 8 cloves garlic, minced ⅓ cup high quality olive oil 1 lemon 4 oz pancetta or bacon 1 tsp fresh parsley  Directions  Preheat oven to 275°F (135°C) Butterfly the roast by cutting into three parts by cutting into the side starting a third of the way up the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
