<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thai on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/thai/</link><description>Recent content in thai on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/thai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Panang-Style Beef Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 315 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 lb Ground Beef 1 can (400mL) Coconut Milk 1 Red Chili Pepper 1/2 cup Red Curry Paste 4 tsp Peanut Butter 3/4 cup Jasmine Rice 2 Tbsp Cilantro 1 Sweet Bell Pepper 1/2 Onion (2 oz), chopped 1 Tbsp Garlic Puree 1 oz Peanuts, chopped 1/2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Mild Curry Paste Directions Start rice.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Satay with Peanut Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 lbs boneless chicken breast or thigh 1.5 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tbsp ground tumeric 2 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp coconut milk 3 tbsp peanut butter (creamy) 1 tbsp massaman curry paste water to thin peanut sauce Directions Cut the chicken into 1/2 inch thick strips. Mix chicken with oyster sauce, tumeric, 1 tbsp sugar and coconut milk.</description></item><item><title>Fish Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fish-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fish-curry/</guid><description>Best served with white rice
🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:5 Ingredients 3T neutral oil 1 onion 1 red onion 2 cloves of garlic 4cm ginger 1 red pepper 1t curry powder 250g green beans 4 tomatoes 200ml fish broth 200ml coconut milk 400g fish fillet (white fish) Directions Boil green beans for 10 minutes Cut onions, tomato, garlic and fish. Heat oil on a wok and sauté the onion and garlic Add beans, tomato, broth and spices and boil for 6 minutes Add coconut milk, fish and pepper (whole) and boil for an additional 6 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people Ingredients 2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander Directions Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description></item></channel></rss>