<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>japanese on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/japanese/</link><description>Recent content in japanese on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/japanese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grilled Mackerel with Miso Soup and Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 Norwegian Mackerel Fillets 1 tbsp Sake 2 tbsp Miso paste 1/2 Onion 1 Summer Squash 1 tbsp butter 1 cup Jasmine Rice (optional) Soy Sauce (optional) Directions Place the mackerel fillets in a small container at room temperature. Pour sake on both sides of the fillets and let rest in the container, covered, for 30 min.</description></item><item><title>Okonomiyaki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</guid><description>Okonomiyaki is a Japanese savory pancake. Instead of using air bubbles to lighten the pancake, thin strips of cabbage provide levity to the cake. This is a very popular street food in Japan, and can be topped with all sorts of different ingredients, as &amp;ldquo;Okonomiyaki&amp;rdquo; roughly translates to &amp;ldquo;Grilled how you like&amp;rdquo;.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 125g flour</description></item><item><title>Spicy Mayo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</guid><description>A simple sauce that is at almost every sushi bar in the United States.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min Ingredients chili sauce (e.g Sriracha) mayonnaise sesame oil Directions Add 2 parts mayonnaise to 1 part chili sauce in a bowl. Add 1 tbsp of sesame oil for every cup of mayonnaise you use. Mix all of the ingredients together, and taste test it for more chili sauce or mayonnaise.</description></item><item><title>Miso-soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</guid><description>Miso-soup is Japanese traditional home cooking.
Ingredients dashi stock miso paste tofu(optional) seaweed(optional) green onion(optional) Directions put about half of the water in the pot and bring the water to a boil. put the dashi stock in the pot. if you use tofu or seaweed, cut the ingredients into bite-sized pieces, place the ingredients in the pot and bring to a boil. Melt the miso in the water and bring the water to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Noodle Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</guid><description>This is a very easy and simple Japanese style ramen noodle soup. This is very cheap to make, and you can really customise this however you wish with the garnish. This is my own spin inspired by other recipes that I found.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 20 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 750ml Chicken stock 4 Pork chops OR 4 Chicken Breasts Set honey 3 Garlic cloves Soy sauce Worcestershire sauce Ginger, sliced Chinese 5 Spice 1 Red Chilli, sliced and deseeded (Optional, but recommended) 375g Ramen Noodles (Medium Egg Noodles work well too) 100g Spinach (Optional) 4 Tbsp Sweetcorn (Optional) Sesame seeds (Optional) 4 Boiled Eggs (Optional) 1 Sheet of Dried Nori (Optional) Spring Onion, chopped (Optional) Directions For the broth, add 700ml of chicken stock to a large boiling pot with the garlic, ginger, soy sauce, chinese five spice, chili, and 300ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Sticky Porkchops</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</guid><description>Simple chinese inspired sticky porkchops.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 hours 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Pork chops 2 heaped tbsp Set honey 3 Garlic cloves, crushed Soy sauce Ginger (thumb sized piece), sliced 1 tbsp Chinese Five Spice Directions Fill a shallow dish with soy sauce to about half the thickness of your porkchops. The level shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fully submerge them.</description></item><item><title>Miso Ginger Pork</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-ginger-pork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-ginger-pork/</guid><description>Ingredients ground pork sushi rice green onion fresh ginger miso paste pickled daikon zucchini or bok choy sesame oil (or olive oil) broth (optional) Directions cook sushi rice slice daikon, and pickle in a quick brine (rice vinegar, sugar, water) dice white parts of green onion, mince green ends for garnish mince fresh ginger chop zucchini or bok choy into half inch (1-1.5 cm) chunks heat up 2 tablespoons sesame oil break up and brown ground pork till almost cooked through salt and pepper the pork add 1/2 cup to 1 cup (250-500 mL) water or broth add white parts of green onion and ginger add miso paste to taste simmer stirring occasionally add zucchini or bok choy, cook al dente serve pork &amp;amp; veggies over bed of rice, garnish with green onion (optional) add some spice!</description></item></channel></rss>