<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spread on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/spread/</link><description>Recent content in Spread on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/spread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>&lt;p>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2-3 medium potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 long or 4 short cucumbers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 strands of spring onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10-12 radishes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bunch of dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Kefir or 1 kvass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 mineral water (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it brew for a few minutes and the dish is ready to eat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tzatziki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tzatziki.webp" alt="Tzatziki">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A traditional greek dip that goes well with crackers, celery and carrots or in a greek gyro. Great for parties and sharing with your family friends. Can be eaten immediately after preparation or after a few hours of being in the fridge for enhanced flavor.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 6 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Greek yogurt, 2 cups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cucumber, 3 inches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic, 1 clove/teaspoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil, 1 teaspoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lemon/lime or vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Finely grate the cucumber and chop the dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain the cucumber thoroughly with a clean kitchen towel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mash the garlic and the olive oil in a mortar and pestle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add all three to the Greek yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Squeeze in some lemon/lime or vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a generous pinch of salt and small pinch of pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally add some extra olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir and enjoy with your favorite snack&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Orange jam</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</guid><description>&lt;p>This jam is a traditional topping for the Polish &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/mazurek">mazurek&lt;/a>, but
can be used as a generic sweet spread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 medium sized oranges&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Zest all fruit.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel off the albedo (the white part under the skin).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blend the fruit (not too much, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to become an even mush, just
cut up into small pieces).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine the blended fruit, zest, and sugar in a pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to boil and boil for 30-40 minutes on low heat. The mixture will
thicken as water evaporates. Note that it will thicken even further once it
cools, so don&amp;rsquo;t boil for too long - it is expected to be still a little runny
at the end of boiling.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mayonnaise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Horseradish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worchestershire sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dijon mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pickle relish (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put ingredients into bowl or cup.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix together thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/hummus.webp" alt="Hummus">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons&amp;rsquo; worth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fresh parsley (optional for serving)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place garbanzo beans in a small saucepan or pot, add 1 teaspoon baking soda (this alters the pH to encourage the beans to break down and shed their skins), and cover with a few inches of water. Bring to a boil and cook for 20 minutes, until the skins begin to fall off and the beans look overcooked/mushy. You may need to reduce the heat after a few minutes to prevent boil-overs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the garbanzo beans are boiling, combine the garlic and lemon juice with 1/4 teaspoon salt in the workbowl of your food processor. Pulse until a fine, uniform consistency is achieved. You may need to scrape down the top and sides of the bowl to ensure the garlic is chopped finely enough. Leave the mixture for at least 10 minutes for the raw garlic taste to mellow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After 20 minutes of boiling, drain the garbanzo beans and their skins in a mesh strainer, then rinse for at least 30 seconds with cold water to remove any lingering taste from the baking soda.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tahini to the food processor. Blend until creamy. Scrape down the sides and bottom of the bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the food processor is running on &amp;ldquo;high,&amp;rdquo; slowly drizzle in two tablespoons of ice-cold water. Continue to run on high, scraping down the bowl as necessary (1-3 times), until the mixture has enough air worked into it that it lightens in color and thickens in texture substantially.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scrape down the bowl again, then add the garbanzo beans and cumin (and za&amp;rsquo;atar, if you have it). Pulse a few times, then set the food processor to high again. Drizzle in 1 tablespoon of olive oil, as slowly as you can manage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continue to process the hummus on high for at least one minute longer, up to three minutes longer if it hasn&amp;rsquo;t become smooth enough yet. You can make the hummus thinner at this point by slowly adding ice water a teaspoon at a time while processing on high. Taste the hummus at this point to determine if it needs more lemon juice or more salt for flavor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer the hummus into a serving bowl and smooth out the surface with the back of a spoon, creating swirls or indentations for olive oil as desired. Top with additional olive oil and optionally finely chopped fresh parsley, more za&amp;rsquo;atar, or a sprinkling of sumac (a spice mixture) or dukkah (a seed mixture).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve immediately or transfer to an airtight container and store in the refrigerator for up to one week.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350Â°F (175Â°C) for ten to twelve minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter. (This may take a few minutes)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/guacamole.webp" alt="Fresh Guacamole">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with
some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 Hass avocados&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 medium onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small tomato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cilantro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lime&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And of course, some totopos to eat with.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mash the avocados, add lime juice, mix and mash some more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mince the cilantro, tomato and onion and add them to the avocado mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt and black pepper to taste and mix thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy fresh with some totopos!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This recipe is best consumed fresh, since the avocado oxidizes pretty fast and
might lose its appetizing color and texture in just some hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick and simple bread spread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>10 dried plums&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 jar of dried tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp of smoked paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pinch of dried coriander (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want to make it more liquid you can add water from the plums.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>