<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spread on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/spread/</link><description>Recent content in spread on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/spread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.
Ingredients 2-3 medium potatoes 4 eggs 2 long or 4 short cucumbers 3 strands of spring onions 10-12 radishes bunch of dill 2 Kefir or 1 kvass 500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat 1 mineral water (optional) Directions Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled) Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat) Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.</description></item><item><title>Tzatziki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</guid><description>A traditional greek dip that goes well with crackers, celery and carrots or in a greek gyro. Great for parties and sharing with your family friends. Can be eaten immediately after preparation or after a few hours of being in the fridge for enhanced flavor.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Greek yogurt, 2 cups Cucumber, 3 inches Dill Garlic, 1 clove/teaspoon Olive oil, 1 teaspoon Lemon/lime or vinegar Salt and pepper Directions Finely grate the cucumber and chop the dill Strain the cucumber thoroughly with a clean kitchen towel Mash the garlic and the olive oil in a mortar and pestle Add all three to the Greek yogurt Squeeze in some lemon/lime or vinegar Add a generous pinch of salt and small pinch of pepper Optionally add some extra olive oil Stir and enjoy with your favorite snack</description></item><item><title>Orange jam</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</guid><description>This jam is a traditional topping for the Polish mazurek, but can be used as a generic sweet spread.
Ingredients 4 medium sized oranges 1 lemon 1 1/2 cup sugar Directions Zest all fruit. Peel off the albedo (the white part under the skin). Blend the fruit (not too much, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to become an even mush, just cut up into small pieces). Combine the blended fruit, zest, and sugar in a pot.</description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.
Ingredients Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended) Mayonnaise Horseradish Worchestershire sauce Paprika Dijon mustard Onion powder Pickle relish (optional) Directions Put ingredients into bowl or cup. Mix together thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>Ingredients One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas) 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina) 1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons' worth 1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry) 1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding) 1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it) 1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving Fresh parsley (optional for serving) Directions Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts Directions Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350°F (175°C) for ten to twelve minutes While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds. Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:
2 Hass avocados 1/4 medium onion 1 small tomato Cilantro 1 lime And of course, some totopos to eat with.
Directions Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item></channel></rss>