<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cookies on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/cookies/</link><description>Recent content in cookies on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/cookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid><description>
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 230 g melted butter (2 sticks) 330 g bread flour 5 g salt 5 g baking soda 100-200 g white sugar 100-200 g brown sugar 1 egg 15 g milk 5 g vanilla 225 g 50-70% dark chocolate chips or semi-sweet milk chocolate chips Directions Preheat oven to 375°F Mix the flour, baking soda, and salt in a bowl Using a mixer or whisk, beat the butter, sugar, eggs, vanilla and milk in a separate bowl for a few mins Combine and stir in the dry ingredients, then the chocolate chips Use an ice cream scooper or spoon to make uniform balls of cookie dough to the size you like and evenly space them out on a parchment paper lined baking sheet (you may need more than one sheet depending on the size of the cookies) Bake in the oven one baking sheet at a time for around 8-10 minutes, taking them out when they start to brown Cool for a few minutes then put them on a cooling rack</description></item><item><title>Greek Easter Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid><description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies Ingredients 1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more) Directions Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description></item><item><title>Matcha Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid><description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut Directions Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description></item></channel></rss>