<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soup on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/soup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soup on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aljotta</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</guid>
      <description>Aljotta (&amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;Yo!&amp;quot;) is a light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; white fish that don&amp;rsquo;t turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock. There are a some variants; restaurant versions could very well include lemon juice and shellfish which I don&amp;rsquo;t associate with aljotta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almeirim Stone Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</guid>
      <description>It is truly emblematic of Portuguese cuisine, as it uses all of the ingredients available in order to waste no food.
Ingredients  well-washed stone kidney beans or fresh pig&amp;rsquo;s ear (blanched and sliced thin) chouriço negro or firm type of blood sausage mixed meat chouriço or mediterranean smoked sausage pork belly, fatback or bacon potatoes, cubed onions, chopped garlic cloves bay leaf cilantro/coriander, chopped  Directions  In a saucepan, boil the kidney beans with the pig&amp;rsquo;s ear, sausages, pork belly, onions, garlic and bay leaf in some water and add a well-washed stone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo &amp;amp; Chickpea Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid>
      <description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min  Ingredients  Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying  Directions  Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erwtensoep (Dutch pea soup)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</guid>
      <description>Erwtensoep, also called snert, is the Dutch version of pea soup. Slices of rookworst (smoked sausage) are added before serving. The soup, which is traditionally eaten during the winter, is emblematic of Dutch cuisine. It is customarily served with Frisian rye bread (roggebrood) and bacon, cheese or butter. Pancakes are sometimes served with pea soup; this dish is called snert met struif, struif referring to the pancakes.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  7 1/2 cups / 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people  Ingredients  2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander  Directions  Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</guid>
      <description>Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients  3 cups red lentils 12 cups water 1 large red onion, diced 2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced 1 medium zucchini, diced 4 cups Swiss chard, chopped 1 bunch of cilantro, chopped ¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste 1 teaspoon cumin  Directions  In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Leek Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  3 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 1 quart chicken or veggie stock 11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes 1 bay leaf ¾ cup heavy cream white pepper (optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg (optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed  Directions  Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato and Grilled Bell Pepper soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</guid>
      <description>🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️Servings:12  Can be prepared the night before and kept frozen for a week or two.
Ingredients  10 tomatoes 2 red bell peppers 2 onions 1 clove of garlic 1L stock or broth ¾t Cayenne pepper 1t paprika powder 3t bruschetta herbs 1t oregano 1t giner syrup 2T olive oil 2T heavy cream  Directions  Halve, deseed and grill the bell peppers in an oven or on a grill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid>
      <description> ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  yogurt 1/3 cup rice 2 tablespoon flour 1 egg yolk butter  Directions  wash the rice put water in the pot and wait for water to boil add some salt and rice wait for 15 minutes mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl add water from the soup and mix by warming when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well serve warm  Contribution  digi - sourcehut  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian Borscht</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</guid>
      <description>Borscht is a beet soup that originates from Ukraine and is common in Eastern Europe and North Asia. Depending on the recipe, borscht may be purely vegetarian; it may be served either hot or cold; and it may range from a hearty one-pot meal to a clear broth or a smooth drink.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 25 mins 🍳 Cook time: 40 mins 🍽️ Servings: 10  Ingredients  3 red beetroots 4 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 8 cups chicken broth + 2 cups water 3 yukon potatoes 2 carrots 2 celery ribs 1 onion 4 Tbsp ketchup or 3 Tbsp tomato sauce 1 red bell pepper (optional) 1 can white cannelini beans with their juice (optional) 2 bay leaves (optional) 1 pressed garlic clove (optional) 1 cup sour cream (optional) fresh dill to taste (optional)  Directions  Peel, grate and/or slice all vegetables (keeping sliced potatoes in cold water to prevent browning until ready to use then drain).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
