<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>snack on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/snack/</link><description>Recent content in snack on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/snack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Banana and oatmeal cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Serving : 3 Ingredients 2 ripe bananas (250 g/9 oz peeled) 100g (3.5 oz) of oatmeal 1 table spoon of cinnamon powder (optional) 1 table spoon of honey (optional) Directions Pre-heat the oven to 180°C (350°F) Peel the bananas and squash them not too finely in a bowl. Incorporate the oatmeal. Incorporate cinnamon powder and/or honey (optional). On the oven tray, place parchment paper and form discs of the mix, each around 8 cm (3 in) Cook with rotating heat for around 20 minutes, until outside becomes golden and slightly crispy.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Corn</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</guid><description>Recipe can be expanded or contracted to your needs. I personally divide the recipe in half to fit my 2 quart saucepan (recipe calls for a 3 quart). I recommend using Orville Redenbacher&amp;rsquo;s popcorn kernels, as they are specifically formulated to pop consistently. Follow these directions precisely, and I will guarantee you will have no burnt or unpopped kernels.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Serving 14 Ingredients 2 tablespoons vegetable oil, or oil of your choice 1/4 cup of popcorn kernels 2 tablespoons of sugar (brown sugar works too) salt to taste Directions Add oil into your saucepan and 3 popcorn kernels.</description></item><item><title>Butter-based biscuit and cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-based-biscuit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-based-biscuit/</guid><description>This recipe is some basic recommandations for making butter based biscuits (aka shortbread, sablés, cookies &amp;hellip;). The complexity comes from the presence of butter mostly.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min ⏲️ Wait time: 1h 🍳 Cook time: 15 min Ingredients Butter Flour White sugar Eggs (optionnal) Directions Prepare the dough Mix the sugar and eggs until it gets white Add the &amp;ldquo;Pommade&amp;rdquo; butter and mix thoroughly until the preparation is airy.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Chips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</guid><description>Credits to creator of recipe, Ethan Chlebowski, (original recipe). I decided to post it on here to be more available.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 11 min 🍽️ Servings: 1~2, about 1 plate full Ingredients 1 Russet Potato, or other potato with high starch and low moisture. The amount of starch effects the crunchiness of the chip. Peanut Oil for frying (at least 1 to 2 inches in the pan) Salt or seasoning of your choice Directions Set a wok or pot over medium-low heat and add the peanut oil about 1 to 2 inches up the pot.</description></item><item><title>Tahini short bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</guid><description>This short bread recipe uses sesame paste called Tahini, a minimal amount of white sugar is necessary in order to get a crunchy/caramelized short-bread. For better results, a food processor is welcome for this recipe. IMPORTANT Butter is what makes this recipe complicated when cooking the dough, make sure it is not liquid or that the room is not to warm and make sure that the shortbreads are cold before putting in the oven.</description></item><item><title>Red Bean Buns (豆沙包)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dou-sha-bao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dou-sha-bao/</guid><description>Soft and fluffy sweet buns filled-up with creamy Azuki red bean paste.
⏲️ Prep time: 2h 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 350g (~12 oz) wheat flour 1 sachet (~ 4g / 0.14 oz) baker&amp;rsquo;s yeast 1 teaspoon baking powder 200g (7 oz) sugar 20cl (~ 0,05 gal) water 1 teaspoon sunflower oil 250g (~ 9 oz)red beans Azuki (soak 24h before recipe) salt 6 baking paper square 7x7cm (~ 3x3inches) Directions 24h after soaking, boil the beans during 5 minutes and rince to clean up impurities.</description></item><item><title>Tzatziki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</guid><description>
A traditional greek dip that goes well with crackers, celery and carrots or in a greek gyro. Great for parties and sharing with your family friends. Can be eaten immediately after preparation or after a few hours of being in the fridge for enhanced flavor.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Greek yogurt, 2 cups Cucumber, 3 inches Dill Garlic, 1 clove/teaspoon Olive oil, 1 teaspoon Lemon/lime or vinegar Salt and pepper Directions Finely grate the cucumber and chop the dill Strain the cucumber thoroughly with a clean kitchen towel Mash the garlic and the olive oil in a mortar and pestle Add all three to the Greek yogurt Squeeze in some lemon/lime or vinegar Add a generous pinch of salt and small pinch of pepper Optionally add some extra olive oil Stir and enjoy with your favorite snack</description></item><item><title>Aussie Snags (sausage sizzle)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</guid><description>An Australian BBQ classic tradition that is simple and very easy to make. Great for parties and outdoor events especially national events. Sometimes served at hardware chains.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: Depends Ingredients Sausages (thin) Onions (4g per sausage) Tomato sauce Mustard (optional) White sliced bread Butter Oil Wood chips (optional, fuel for smokey flavour) Directions Chop up the onions into rings Bring the sausages to the grill, turning once every 5 mins Add oil of your choice to the hotplate then add the onions Use your tongs to toss the onions until they are golden brown When the onions are golden brown turn off the hotplate When the sausages are cooked, butter the bread, then the onions, and add a sausage (optionally split) Finally tomato sauce on top</description></item><item><title>Soleier (pickled eggs)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</guid><description>Soleier are a german pub dish. They are typically enjoyed between two beers.
⏲️ Preparation time: 10min 🍳 Cook time: 10min 🍽️ Servings: 10 Ingredients peels of five onions 10 eggs 2 loorber leaves 3 cloves 4 allspice 1Tbsp peppercorns 1Tbsp caraway seeds 1Tbsp mustard seeds 1tsp of Szechuan pepper (optional) 1tsp lovage (optional) 1tsp nutmeg (optional) 100mL vinegar 3 cloves of garlic Directions Put 750mL of water and the peels of five onions in a pot and let them cook for five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Greek Easter Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid><description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies Ingredients 1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more) Directions Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>Ingredients One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas) 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina) 1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons&amp;rsquo; worth 1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry) 1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding) 1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it) 1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving Fresh parsley (optional for serving) Directions Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts Directions Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350°F (175°C) for ten to twelve minutes While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds. Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 3 bananas 100 g / ½ cups butter 150 g / ¾ cups sugar 2 eggs 1½ tsp. cooking powder 260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour 50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate 50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate some vanilla sugar (optional) Directions Peel the bananas and mush them together. Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sweet Potato Fries Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</guid><description>A simple, tasty, and healthy carb based snack.
Ingredients 1-2 Sweet Pototoes (try different types) Olive Oil Cinnamon Rosemary (optional) Directions Set oven heat to 425°F (220°C). Grab a pan and put a layer of parchment paper (or aluminum foil) on it. Chop the potato(es) on your cutting board with a sharp knife throwing them onto the pan. Drizzle the fries with olive oil. Toss the fries with clean hands to coat the fries in olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:
2 Hass avocados 1/4 medium onion 1 small tomato Cilantro 1 lime And of course, some totopos to eat with.
Directions Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl. Mash the avocados, add lime juice, mix and mash some more.</description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer Directions Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Beef Jerky</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</guid><description>Beef Jerky is ideal for road trips and camping, as it will not perish as readily as fresh meat. It is suitable not only as a snack but also as a meal. This recipe for jerky is not heavily brined and flavored as commercial jerky is.
Ingredients ¾ tsp. salt ¼ tsp. pepper 1 tbsp. brown sugar ¼ tsp. garlic 2 tbsp. Worcestershire sauce or Teriyaki sauce ¼ tsp. Liquid Smoke 1 Lb.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Matcha Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid><description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut Directions Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description></item></channel></rss>