<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>belgian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/belgian/</link><description>Recent content in belgian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/belgian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Belgian pear syrup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</guid><description>A delicious syrup that can be eaten on bread and used in a multitude of recipes.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 hours Ingredients 7 pears (Quality doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter; you can argue that overripe pears are better because they have more sugar content.) 3 apples a small handful of dates, raisins, dried apricots or prunes (optional &amp;ndash; you can experiment with these; they can bring out some nice flavors.</description></item><item><title>Stoemp</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</guid><description>Mashed potatoes in Belgian style
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g potatoes 300g carrots 100g bacon 50g butter 100ml heavy cream 1/2 teaspoon ground nutmeg Directions Cut bacon into bits. Sauté bacon until well colored. Peel and dice into small chunks potatoes, peel and slice carrots. Boil for 20-25 minutes potatoes and carrots in salted water. Drain vegetables and mash with a fork, so that the texture remains slightly chunky.</description></item><item><title>Stoofvlees</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</guid><description>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions. Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 to 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Large onions 1 tablespoon butter 1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces 2 33cl bottles of brown beer 2 bayleaves 2 twigs of thyme 1 clove (spice) 2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon) 2 teaspoons of vinegar 1 slice of bread mustard Directions Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&amp;rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</description></item></channel></rss>