<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quick on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/quick/</link><description>Recent content in quick on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/quick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</guid><description>Easy recipe to expand - black turtle beans and chickpeas also work well here.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1/3 cup Salad Oil (olive oil, canola, or sunflower) 1/2 cup Cider Vinegar 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Pepper 1/4 cup Sugar 1/2 tsp Celery Seed 1 can Cut Green Beans 1 can Cut Waxed Beans 1 can Red Kidney Beans 1 Carrot, thinly sliced 1 small Onion, chopped 1 Bell Pepper Directions Put dressing ingredients in a large salad bowl an whisk until blended.</description></item><item><title>Easy Chicken and Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 cup Onion, chopped 1/2 cup Celery, chopped 2 Tbsp Butter or margarine 2 cups Chicken, cooked and chopped 1 3/4 cups Hot water 2/3 cup Long Grain White Rice 1 can (10 oz) Mushrooms with liquid 1 cup Frozen Peas and Carrots 1 tsp Dried Thyme and Rosemary Directions In large fry pan, cook onion and celery in butter until soft.</description></item><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.
Ingredients 2-3 medium potatoes 4 eggs 2 long or 4 short cucumbers 3 strands of spring onions 10-12 radishes bunch of dill 2 Kefir or 1 kvass 500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat 1 mineral water (optional) Directions Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled) Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat) Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter sauce.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min Ingredients spaghetti or fettucine butter heavy cream garlic oregano white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended) lemon/lemon juice (optional) red pepper flakes (optional) seafood, choose from: mussels squid shrimp clams lobster Directions Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow these instructions. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook slightly once we add the sauce.</description></item><item><title>Korv Stroganoff</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</guid><description>This easy Swedish dish makes for a great weeknight dinner.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 kg Swedish falukorv 1 yellow onion 1 tbsp olive oil 4 tbsp tomato purée 2 1/2 dl cream 1 dl milk 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp Dijon mustard Directions Cut the sausage into sticks and dice the onion. Fry the sausage and onion in oil for about ten minutes.</description></item><item><title>Banana and oatmeal cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Serving : 3 Ingredients 2 ripe bananas (250 g/9 oz peeled) 100g (3.5 oz) of oatmeal 1 table spoon of cinnamon powder (optional) 1 table spoon of honey (optional) Directions Pre-heat the oven to 180°C (350°F) Peel the bananas and squash them not too finely in a bowl. Incorporate the oatmeal. Incorporate cinnamon powder and/or honey (optional). On the oven tray, place parchment paper and form discs of the mix, each around 8 cm (3 in) Cook with rotating heat for around 20 minutes, until outside becomes golden and slightly crispy.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Corn</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</guid><description>Recipe can be expanded or contracted to your needs. I personally divide the recipe in half to fit my 2 quart saucepan (recipe calls for a 3 quart). I recommend using Orville Redenbacher&amp;rsquo;s popcorn kernels, as they are specifically formulated to pop consistently. Follow these directions precisely, and I will guarantee you will have no burnt or unpopped kernels.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Serving 14 Ingredients 2 tablespoons vegetable oil, or oil of your choice 1/4 cup of popcorn kernels 2 tablespoons of sugar (brown sugar works too) salt to taste Directions Add oil into your saucepan and 3 popcorn kernels.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Chips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</guid><description>Credits to creator of recipe, Ethan Chlebowski, (original recipe). I decided to post it on here to be more available.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 11 min 🍽️ Servings: 1~2, about 1 plate full Ingredients 1 Russet Potato, or other potato with high starch and low moisture. The amount of starch effects the crunchiness of the chip. Peanut Oil for frying (at least 1 to 2 inches in the pan) Salt or seasoning of your choice Directions Set a wok or pot over medium-low heat and add the peanut oil about 1 to 2 inches up the pot.</description></item><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients For the bechamel 50g Butter 50g Flour 1 Liter of milk Salt Ground Pepper Nutmeg For the bites 12 Slices of bread 2 Tbsp of Mustard 12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs 80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette Directions Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan. As soon as it foams, sprinkle it with flour, salt, pepper, add a pinch of nutmeg, mix.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Pasta Olive oil Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers Crushed garlic cloves Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta) Chopped parsley Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended) Directions Start heating up water for the pasta. Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat. Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.</description></item><item><title>Steak Tartare</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</guid><description>Steak Tartare is a dish prepared using raw ground / minced beef and egg yolk. A popular dish in Europe, this recipe is a good stepping stone into the world of raw meats, organs and pates.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Ground Beef (Lean as possible) Eggs Onion or Shallots Capers Gherkin / Cornichons Parsley (Optional) Ketchup (Optional) Mustard (Optional) Worcestershire Sauce (Optional) Directions Dice your onions or shallots.</description></item><item><title>Lavacake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</guid><description>Easily made chocolate dessert with fluid chocolate content. The only requirement is a baking tin with cupcake pits.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 7 min 🍽️ Servings 4 Ingredients 1 Egg 25g Flour 25g Butter 75g Chocolate Directions Cover the baking tin with some butter. Heat the oven for 200°C. Mix all of the ingredients. Fill dough in the baking tins pits. Bake for 7 min. in the oven at 200°C.</description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 14 Ingredients 1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes 1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes 1 green onion 1 red onion 1 jalapeño pepper 1 handfull fresh cilantro 1 clove garlic 1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional) 1 chili pepper (optional) 1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional) Directions Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.</description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying Directions Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water. Allow to boil for 5 or so min.</description></item><item><title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid><description>Very easy, high protein.
Servings: 2 Ingredients 1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice 1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas 1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli) 2 chicken breasts 1 tbsp honey 1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce 1 tbsp minced garlic Directions Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in. While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube. Season with olive oil, black pepper, and paprika.</description></item><item><title>Tanzanian Tea w/ Milk</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</guid><description>This is a very traditional simple beverage from Tanzania, a country in East Africa. While I stayed there in Mwanza and Dar es Salaam, they would always have this option for breakfast (or in general).
⏲️ Prep time: 5-10 min 🍳 Cook time: 3-8 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Black Ceylon Tea (Preferably, you want a dark, herbal flavor from your tea. I have some from Dar es Salaam, but when I tried researching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find out what kind of tea it is.</description></item><item><title>Okonomiyaki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</guid><description>Okonomiyaki is a Japanese savory pancake. Instead of using air bubbles to lighten the pancake, thin strips of cabbage provide levity to the cake. This is a very popular street food in Japan, and can be topped with all sorts of different ingredients, as &amp;ldquo;Okonomiyaki&amp;rdquo; roughly translates to &amp;ldquo;Grilled how you like&amp;rdquo;.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 125g flour
1 egg</description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter). It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min Ingredients Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf. Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.) Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.</description></item><item><title>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</guid><description>If your Oatmeal isn&amp;rsquo;t Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal&amp;hellip; Is it even Oatmeal?
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Serving: 1 hearty serving Ingredients 1/2 cup Large Flake Oats (no partially cooked quick-oats allowed!) Almonds Pecans 1 Tbsp Roasted Flax Seed 1 Tbsp Hemp Hearts Cranberries (adjust amount to preference) 1/2 Banana (mashed) 1 cup Milk (3.25% if possible) Cinnamon (adjust amount to preference) 1 Egg ON Vanilla Ice Cream Protein Powder (optional) Directions Chop or mash nuts and fruit.</description></item><item><title>Shakshouka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</guid><description>Shakshouka is a dish of eggs poached in a sauce of tomatoes, olive oil, peppers, onion and garlic, and commonly spiced with cumin, paprika, cayenne pepper, and nutmeg. This recipe is a quick and simple version for a delicious breakfast.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 5 small tomatoes 5 eggs 1 peeled white onion some chives cumin powdered sweet pepper Directions Scald the tomatoes so they are easier to peel.</description></item><item><title>Egg Roll in a Bowl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</guid><description>Egg rolls, but, you know, in a bowl.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 pound ground turkey 1 bag coleslaw mix 1 small onion 2-3 cloves of garlic 1 tbsp fresh ginger 1/4 cup Hoisin sauce soy sauce sesame oil Directions Grate or mince ginger finely. Process with the garlic cloves by grinding with salt under the edge of a knife. Finely mince the onion.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</guid><description>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette) Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil) Garlic salt Directions Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F). Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil. Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil. Season with garlic salt, to taste.</description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 mins 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended) Flour (Wheat flour recommended) Directions Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan. Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan. Stir and turn on maximum heat. Keep stirring until it becomes thick. If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.</description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 White onion 1 Eggplant Olive oil Egg (optional) Directions Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring) Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long (Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top (Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg.</description></item><item><title>Assam Tea</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</guid><description>This is a simple Assam tea recipe.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 2 teaspoons of Assam Tea 150 ml of fresh water Sugar (Optional) Milk (Optional) Directions Add 150 ml of water to a small pan and bring it to boil. Then add 2 teaspoons of tea into it and reduce the heat to low. Strain the tea using a tea filter into a cup.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps) Ingredients 2 sausages 2 bacon rashers 1 egg 2 wraps milk ketchup (optional) Directions Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through. Next, fry the bacon. Next, possibly while the bacon is frying, crack an egg into a bowl, add a dash of milk and whisk it Then, put the egg mixture into the microwave for a minute, take it out and whisk it again, do this twice again or until the scrambled egg is ready.</description></item><item><title>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</guid><description>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&amp;rsquo;s quite similar to a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&amp;rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it provides as a sweet and cooling effect.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500 gm of Greek Yogurt One Red onion 50 gm of Cucumber Sprigs of Mint Dash of Honey Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option) Directions Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.</description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups Tomato purée Parmigiano (grated) Parsley Directions Start cooking the pasta. Mix the cream with the purée and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down to medium and add the grated parmigiano.</description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).
🍽️ Servings:1-4 Ingredients for 1 liter of Glühwein
300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice 1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :) 50 g Sugar 25 g Raisins 1 orange 1 cinamon bark 1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger) 1 spoon cloves 5 star anise if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre Directions cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration) throw everything in a pot warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil) enjoy</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties
Ingredients 1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio Onion, chopped or powder (optional) Garlic, chopped or powder (optional) Directions Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil. Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature. Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings. Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.</description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.
Ingredients Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended) Mayonnaise Horseradish Worchestershire sauce Paprika Dijon mustard Onion powder Pickle relish (optional) Directions Put ingredients into bowl or cup. Mix together thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Danish Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid><description>
Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients 375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 eggs Directions Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed. Served With Sugar Syrup Powdered sugar Marmalade (Jam)</description></item><item><title>Bolinhos de Coco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid><description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min Ingredients 300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional) Directions Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl. Scoop tablespoons of the batter into a cookie sheet or cupcake pan.</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiro</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</guid><description>A very traditional Brazilian dessert that is present in every Brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.
Ingredients One can of condensed milk. Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder. One spoon of butter (Actual butter and preferably unsalted. No margarine!) Sprinkles (Optional) Directions Add all ingredients into a pan. Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) until it stops sticking to the bottom of the pan.</description></item><item><title>Pickled Red Onions</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</guid><description>A good way to use up older red onions and goes great with just about anything.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings Varies Ingredients Red Onions Vinegar Water Directions Cut onion in half and slice root to stem and place in a jar Mix equal parts of water and vinegar in a pot and bring to a boil. Add salt to taste As soon as it begins to boil, turn off and pour the mix into the jar and allow to cool.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli with Ginger and Garlic Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</guid><description>Asian inspired broccoli dish with tasty sauce. Sauce can be used for all kinds of Asian inspired sauted vegetables.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1-2 Broccoli (fresh best, frozen works too) Minced garlic (1 tablespoon) Minced ginger (1 tablespoon) Sherry or regular white wine (you cook with what you drink with!) (1 tablespoon) Soy sauce (1-2 tablespoon) Directions Cut broccoli into little flourettes (hold the broccoli upside down and cut around the stem with a pairing knife) Fill your pan (or wok) around half inch (1.</description></item><item><title>Simple Tuna Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 (7 oz) can white tuna, drained 6 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 tablespoons sweet pickle relish A pinch of garlic powder (optional) 2 tablespoons white vinegar or lemon juice (optional) 1 cup shredded cheese (optional) 1 chopped hard-boiled egg (optional) Directions In a medium bowl, stir together tuna, mayonnaise, and relish. Add optional ingredients like vinegar, cheese or hard-boiled eggs if wanted.</description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people Ingredients 1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas Directions Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 6 patties
Ingredients 1 cup soft bread crumb 1/2 cup milk 1 1/2 pound ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1/2 teaspoon salt dash pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 2 tablespoons of fat or salad oil Directions Combine all ingredients except fat: mix well; shape into 6 patties. Heat fat in skillet. Brown patties on all sides; lower heat; cook to desired degree of doneness.</description></item><item><title>Hellfire Steak</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</guid><description>I first learned this recipe from a Bishop I had growing up. It produces quite a good steak despite the unconventional ingredients.
Ingredients Steak Kosher Salt Mustard Powder Tabasco Sauce Directions Rub a generous amount of salt all over the steak Coat the entire steak with mustard powder Pour Tabasco Sauce onto both sides of the steak, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to put more on than you think you might otherwise be comfortable with the salt will cancel out a lot of the spice while grilling.</description></item><item><title>Oaty Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted) Directions Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description></item><item><title>Simple sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid><description>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.
Ingredients Tomato sauce. Mayonaise Directions Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity.</description></item><item><title>Fried Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients Potatoes Oil or Crème Fraîche Onions Directions Peel and cut the potatoes to desired size. Cut the onions. Put a bit of Oil or Crème Fraîche in your pan. Put both the potatoes and the onions into the pan. Cook them until they&amp;rsquo;re golden-brown. Enjoy</description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer Directions Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets Ingredients 2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 3/4 cup milk, scalded 1 tablespoon butter, or margarine 4 egg yolks, beaten until thick 4 egg whites, beaten stiff Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet) Directions Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.</description></item><item><title>Quesadilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</guid><description>A quick and easy low-prep meal, able to be taken anywhere.
⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time 🍽️ Serves: 1 Ingredients 1-2 tortillas. Any brand works, but you can decide if you want the tortilla folded in half, or 2 tortillas together. ~4 small pinches of (Mozzarella, Oaxaca, or Montery Jack cheese). Most cheeses are fine, but the taste of oaxaca cheese is more authentic. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have pre-grated cheese, you can cut thin slices off of the block of cheese.</description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>Ingredients Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional) Directions Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs. Mix in and let eggs cook using heat from the pot and tortellini.</description></item><item><title>Tuna Sub</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</guid><description>Use the best tuna you can find. I like oil-packed but water is OK. Someone you know has a tuna salad recipe.
Ingredients 1 recipe of your favorite tuna salad Sandwich bun or bread (a good one) Thinly sliced cheese (your favorite) Sliced tomatoes Baby spinach leaves Pickles Mayo and mustard Other sandwich toppings (very little out of bounds here). Directions Lightly toast one side of the bun Add cheese to bottom of bun Spread a layer of tuna salad Place several spinach leaves on top bun Add sliced tomatoes Add pickle slices Season with salt and pepper to taste Combine halves and enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour) Directions Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional) Directions Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Flammkuchen</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid><description>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up. I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.
🍽️ Servings:2 Ingredients 400g Pizza dough (either bought or from Pizza Dough) 1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons) 150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables) 2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche Directions we start by flattening the dough.</description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people Ingredients 2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander Directions Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description></item><item><title>Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 200g wheat flour or 100g glutenfree flour 200 ml milk 2 eggs 2 tsp sugar 1 tsp baking soda a little bit of salt Directions Mix all ingredients in a bowl. Let the dough rest for ~15 mins. Heat a pan with a bit butter or oil. For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides.</description></item><item><title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid><description>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.
🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients porkchops: 4 shallots: 2 gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup mustard: 2tbsp butter olive oil Directions Cut the shallots into small dices. Cut the gherkins into long strips. Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.</description></item><item><title>Oats</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid><description>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do with oats.
We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.
Ingredients oats water pinch of salt Pick and choose additional ingredients:
chopped banana any berries cinnamon peanut butter Directions Bring water (with pinch of salt) to boil.</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea. Bring water to a rolling boil.</description></item></channel></rss>