<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/quick/</link><description>Recent content in Quick on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/quick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zurich-Style Meat Saute</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally called &amp;ldquo;Züri Gschnätzlets&amp;rdquo; (Zurich chopped) from the city of Zurich
in Switzerland, this is a tasty and practical recipe from simple ingredients.
You can use any kind of meat really, depending on your taste. Very
traditionally, finely sliced liver and kidney is also mixed in with the meat
and mushrooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>600g	Beef, finely sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250g	Mushrooms, finely sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1	Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml	White whine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fry the meat in butter at high heat until it starts loosing liquid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take the meat out of the pan and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute the onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mushrooms, saute, then add a tbsp of flour and mix well. The flour
will make the sauce thicker, so use carfully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the white wine and let it boil for a few minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add cream, boil until the sauce is very creamy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the meat, boil until the meat is warm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add parsley, and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Serve with &lt;a href="./roesti.md">Rösti&lt;/a> or other traditional Swiss dish.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</guid><description>&lt;p>Easy recipe to expand - black turtle beans and chickpeas also work well here.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/3 cup Salad Oil (olive oil, canola, or sunflower)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Cider Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Celery Seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can Cut Green Beans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can Cut Waxed Beans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can Red Kidney Beans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Carrot, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Bell Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put dressing ingredients in a large salad bowl an whisk until blended.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Empty cans of beans into a colander and rinse under cold water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop remaining vegetables and add to dressing. Add beans and gently stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refrigerate for at least an hour before serving, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Easy Chicken and Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Celery, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Butter or margarine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups Chicken, cooked and chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 3/4 cups Hot water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2/3 cup Long Grain White Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can (10 oz) Mushrooms with liquid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Frozen Peas and Carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Dried Thyme and Rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In large fry pan, cook onion and celery in butter until soft.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in remaining ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake in covered 8 cup baking dish in preheated (350F) oven for about 30 minutes or until rice is cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>&lt;p>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2-3 medium potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 long or 4 short cucumbers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 strands of spring onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10-12 radishes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>bunch of dill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Kefir or 1 kvass&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 mineral water (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it brew for a few minutes and the dish is ready to eat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter
sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>spaghetti or fettucine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lemon/lemon juice (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>red pepper flakes (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>seafood, choose from:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mussels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>squid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>shrimp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>clams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lobster&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">these
instructions&lt;/a>. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook
slightly once we add the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Defrost/Deshell your seafood of choice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop a half tablespoon of garlic into small pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large pan on medium heat, saute your chopped garlic in salt and butter for a
minute or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add and saute the seafood. Season with oregano, red pepper flakes and salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a half cup heavy cream and a third cup of white wine to the pan. Cook until you have the
consistency you want.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain your pasta (Which should be cooked by now) and pour contents of the pan into the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Korv Stroganoff</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/korv-stroganoff.webp" alt="Korv Stroganoff">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This easy Swedish dish makes for a great weeknight dinner.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 kg Swedish &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Falukorv">falukorv&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 yellow onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tbsp tomato purée&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 1/2 dl cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 dl milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Dijon mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the sausage into sticks and dice the onion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the sausage and onion in oil for about ten minutes. Add the tomato purée and cook for another minute.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in cream, milk, soy sauce and Dijon mustard. Let it simmer for at least five minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season to taste with plenty of pepper, and possibly salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with boiled rice. Optionally top with freshly ground pepper and/or garnish with chopped parsley.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Banana and oatmeal cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Serving : 3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 ripe bananas (250 g/9 oz peeled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g (3.5 oz) of oatmeal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 table spoon of cinnamon powder (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 table spoon of honey (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Pre-heat the oven to 180°C (350°F)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel the bananas and squash them not too finely in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incorporate the oatmeal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incorporate cinnamon powder and/or honey (optional).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the oven tray, place parchment paper and form discs of the mix, each around 8 cm (3 in)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook with rotating heat for around 20 minutes, until outside becomes golden and slightly crispy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eat warm or cold. Can be kept a couple of days in a sealed container.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Kettle Corn</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/kettlecorn.webp" alt="Kettle Corn" title="Kettle Corn made with brown sugar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recipe can be expanded or contracted to your needs. I personally divide the recipe in half to fit my 2 quart saucepan (recipe calls for a 3 quart). I recommend using Orville Redenbacher&amp;rsquo;s popcorn kernels, as they are specifically formulated to pop consistently. Follow these directions precisely, and I will guarantee you will have no burnt or unpopped kernels.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Serving 14&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons vegetable oil, or oil of your choice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup of popcorn kernels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons of sugar (brown sugar works too)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>salt to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add oil into your saucepan and 3 popcorn kernels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover with lid and set stove to medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once all 3 kernels pop, add in the rest of your kernels and shake to coat in oil. Pour sugar directly onto the kernels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shake the pot for 3 seconds, rest for 3 seconds, and repeat till the kernels start to pop steadily. Depending on your stove, you may need to lift the pot to shake.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once kernels start popping, shake pot every 1-2 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Important&lt;/strong>. Once you no longer hear pops for about 3 seconds, immediately transfer into a bowl to avoid burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Kettle Chips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</guid><description>&lt;p>Credits to creator of recipe, Ethan Chlebowski, &lt;a href="https://www.ethanchlebowski.com/cooking-techniques-recipes/kettle-cooked-chips">(original recipe)&lt;/a>.
I decided to post it on here to be more available.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 11 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1~2, about 1 plate full&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Russet Potato, or other potato with high starch and low moisture. The amount of starch effects the crunchiness of the chip.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peanut Oil for frying (at least 1 to 2 inches in the pan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt or seasoning of your choice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Set a wok or pot over medium-low heat and add the peanut oil about 1 to 2 inches up the pot. Set a thermometer to monitor the temperature to reach 315 F (157 C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wash the exterior of the potato. Using a mandolin set on 2 mm (~1/16th inch), a very sharp knife or a potato peeler cut the potatoes into thin chip slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potatoes to the hot oil and cook for 9 to 11 minutes while stirring fairly constantly. &lt;br>
Note: The oil should drop to roughly 250 F in the first few minutes before stabilizing and increasing back to 315 F. This may be slightly different depending on the size of the pot and the amount of oil you use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once golden browned and completely crisp with no bubbling, remove the chips with a slotted spoon and add to a paper towel over a wire rack to absorb excess oil. Seasoning immediately with salt and any seasoning of your choice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t throw away your oil! Let it cool. Place a paper towel in a metal strainer and strain it into a glass or plastic container for next time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="seasoning-suggestion">Seasoning suggestion&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ethan suggests making a special seasoning from jalapeños, onions, garlic, salt and (optional) some MSG. This optional step takes a LOT longer than the rest of the recipe.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dry out the vegetables after cutting and preparing them, sliced quite thin so that they dry out, in the oven at the lowest temperature that it will go to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave for about 6 hours to dry in the oven.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once dry and brittle, break the vegetables up into little pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powder them in a mortar and pestle until completely dry and fine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour powder into a separate bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a spoonfull of salt and (optional) a small amount of MSG to the mortar and pestle. Grind to the same consistency as the vegetables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the salt-msg mix to the vegetable powder along with about half a tablespoon of sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle over the chips and mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/croque-monsieur.webp" alt="croquemsr">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For the bechamel
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>50g Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Liter of milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ground Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the bites
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>12 Slices of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp of Mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As soon as it foams, sprinkle it with flour, salt, pepper, add a pinch of nutmeg, mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then pour in the milk, little by little (especially not all at once), stirring with a whisk each time, until the sauce thickens.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn on the oven on th. 6/180°, take the baking sheet out of the oven and line it with aluminum foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread 6 slices of bread in front of you, spread them with a little mustard, add a layer of béchamel, 1 slice of ham folded in 4, grated cheese, a layer of béchamel, put the other 6 slices of bread on the on top, add a thin layer of béchamel and distribute the rest of the grated cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the croque-monsieur on the baking sheet and put them in the oven for about 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can place them under the broiler for 3-4 minutes at the end.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pasta-arrabbiata.webp" alt="arrabiata">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crushed garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Start heating up water for the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add your crushed tomatoes, together with some salt and pepper, increase the heat to medium and let simmer for 10-15 minutes or until it looks nicely thickened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the water starts boiling, put a handful of salt into it and then your pasta of choice. Ideally leave the pasta slightly undercooked, because it will go in the hot sauce and finish cooking there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the sauce is almost ready, add most of your chopped parsley and stir it around. Save some to top the dish later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the pasta is ready (ideally at the same time as the sauce or slightly later), strain it and add it to the sauce, which should be off the heat. If the sauce looks a bit too thick, add some of the pasta water. Mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add some of the grated cheese of your choice and stir it in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with some more grated cheese and chopped parsley on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Steak Tartare</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</guid><description>&lt;p>Steak Tartare is a dish prepared using raw ground / minced beef and egg yolk. A popular dish in Europe, this recipe is a good stepping stone into the world of raw meats, organs and pates.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ground Beef (Lean as possible)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion or Shallots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gherkin / Cornichons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parsley (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ketchup (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mustard (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worcestershire Sauce (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dice your onions or shallots.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finely slice your cornichons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rinse, drain and chop your capers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop parsley. (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop ground beef into smaller pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the above to a mixing bowl and mix with hands.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add ketchup, mustard or Worcestershire sauce as needed and mix further. (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Separate an egg yolk from the whites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loosely roll some of the mixture into a ball in your hand and place onto a plate and press softly to form a bowl shape, add egg yolk to indentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve, you may now add salt and pepper as desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Lavacake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/lavacake.webp" alt="lavacake">
Easily made chocolate dessert with fluid chocolate content. The only requirement is a baking tin with cupcake pits.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 7 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25g Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25g Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>75g Chocolate&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cover the baking tin with some butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat the oven for 200°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix all of the ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill dough in the baking tins pits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 7 min. in the oven at 200°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve hot with berries and vanilla ice-creame.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 0 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 14&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 green onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 red onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 jalapeño pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 handfull fresh cilantro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 chili pepper (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refrigerate until consumption. (max 1 week)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recommend serving with corn bread.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chorizo Sausage(s)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika, 2 Tsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cumin, Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Juice from whole Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chickpeas, 400g ( drained )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter and sunflower oil, for frying&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow to boil for 5 or so min. Add Parsley and then salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p>Very easy, high protein.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 chicken breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp minced garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube. Season with olive oil, black pepper, and
paprika. Cut broccoli into pieces and place into steamer basket over pot 1/2 filled with water, do
not start it yet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put chicken cubes into a hot pan and cook for ~3 minutes. After 3 minutes add honey, soy sauce,
and garlic. Cook for another 5 minutes. Begin boiling broccoli water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add frozen peas to rice and stir, they will heat up quickly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add rice and peas to chicken and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tanzanian Tea w/ Milk</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tanzania-tea-with-milk-01.webp" alt="tea-n-milk">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a very traditional simple beverage from Tanzania, a country in East Africa. While I stayed there in Mwanza and Dar es Salaam, they
would always have this option for breakfast (or in general).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5-10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 3-8 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Black Ceylon Tea (Preferably, you want a dark, herbal flavor from your tea. I have some from Dar es Salaam,
but when I tried researching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find out what kind of tea it is. No, they didn&amp;rsquo;t list the ingredients on
the box lol)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk/Sweet Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweetener (Sugar, Syrup, Monk Fruit extract, etc.) (optional, but recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tanzania-tea-with-milk-02.webp" alt="tea">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Okonomiyaki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okonomiyaki is a Japanese savory pancake. Instead of using air bubbles to lighten the pancake, thin strips of cabbage provide levity to the cake. This is a very popular street food in Japan, and can be topped with all sorts of different ingredients, as &amp;ldquo;Okonomiyaki&amp;rdquo; roughly translates to &amp;ldquo;Grilled how you like&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>125g flour&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>1 egg&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/torrijas.webp" alt="Torrijas">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter).
It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 1 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated lemon rind (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mull the milk with cinnamon and a bit of sugar (not too much, the milk is already sweet). Add the lemon rind if you want.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool down the milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the milk is cooling, beat the eggs and heat up half a pan of olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the dry bread in slices. Soak it in the milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coat the bread soaking it in the beaten eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the soaked &amp;amp; coated bread with the heated oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally sprinkle some sugar onto the Torrijas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy when they are cooled down. Don&amp;rsquo;t eat too much, it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy resisting!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-00.webp" alt="hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-00">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your Oatmeal isn&amp;rsquo;t Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal&amp;hellip; Is it even Oatmeal?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Serving: 1 hearty serving&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Large Flake Oats (no partially cooked quick-oats allowed!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Almonds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pecans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Roasted Flax Seed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Hemp Hearts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cranberries (adjust amount to preference)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Banana (mashed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Milk (3.25% if possible)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cinnamon (adjust amount to preference)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ON Vanilla Ice Cream Protein Powder (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Chop or mash nuts and fruit.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine nuts, fruit, and other dry ingredients in a saucepan
&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-01.webp" alt="hearty-breakfast-oatmeal-01">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add milk and cook mixture over medium heat until oats are desired tenderness (5-10 mins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add egg and protein powder and cook for a few more minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Shakshouka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shakshouka is a dish of eggs poached in a sauce of tomatoes, olive oil, peppers, onion and garlic, and commonly spiced with cumin, paprika, cayenne pepper, and nutmeg.
This recipe is a quick and simple version for a delicious breakfast.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/shakshouka-02.webp" alt="Shakshouka">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>5 small tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 peeled white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some chives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>powdered sweet pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Scald the tomatoes so they are easier to peel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel the tomatoes and cut into cubes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop the onion and glaze it on the frying pan with oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SEASON&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir and wait for it to get denser&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knock the eggs in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season the eggs
&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/shakshouka-01.webp" alt="Shakshouka">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover the pan with a lid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook until eggs are laid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chives&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Egg Roll in a Bowl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</guid><description>&lt;p>Egg rolls, but, you know, in a bowl.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 pound ground turkey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bag coleslaw mix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp fresh ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Hoisin sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sesame oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Grate or mince ginger finely. Process with the garlic cloves by grinding with salt under the edge of a knife. Finely mince the onion. &lt;strong>Optional&lt;/strong> Marinade the ground turkey in 2 Tbsp of soy sauce and 1 tsp baking soda for 15 minutes to improve browning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Garlic Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</guid><description>&lt;p>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season with garlic salt, to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 10-15 minutes or until crunchy throughout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with cheese, charcuterie, pickles, dips, or to accommodate a soup.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 3 mins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flour (Wheat flour recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir and turn on maximum heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep stirring until it becomes thick.
If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the sauce with the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 White onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Eggplant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Egg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg. If it breaks just scramble it, the recipe doesn&amp;rsquo;t call for anything fancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can serve the dish with that oil (provided it is not burnt) or keep it for cooking other stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Assam Tea</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/assam-tea.webp" alt="Assam Tea">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a simple Assam tea recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 1 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 teaspoons of Assam Tea&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 ml of fresh water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sugar (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add 150 ml of water to a small pan and bring it to boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then add 2 teaspoons of tea into it and reduce the heat to low.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain the tea using a tea filter into a cup.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add sugar and milk to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 sausages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 bacon rashers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 wraps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ketchup (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Next, fry the bacon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Next, possibly while the bacon is frying, crack an egg into a bowl, add a dash of milk and whisk it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then, put the egg mixture into the microwave for a minute, take it out and whisk it again, do this twice again or until the scrambled egg is ready.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the sausage, bacon and scrambled egg to a wrap (I recommend two sausage halves, a bacon rasher and half the bowl of scrambled egg per wrap). Add ketchup if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&amp;rsquo;s quite similar to
a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&amp;rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it
provides as a sweet and cooling effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>500 gm of Greek Yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One Red onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50 gm of Cucumber&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprigs of Mint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dash of Honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.5-1cm or 3/8 inches sized cubes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slice the cucumber into tiny strips (Julienne). Hand crush the mint.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prep the serving bowl with yogurt and add the onions and cucumber.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mint, honey, 1 tsp of salt and the sugar/chilli powder (Depending on the sweet/spicy choice)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix well and serve. Garnish with additional mint as required.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/cinque-pi.webp" alt="Cinque Pi">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tomato paste 2 TS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parmigiano (grated)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Start cooking the &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the cream with the tomato paste and bring to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn the heat down to medium and add as much grated parmigiano as you like.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it cook on medium to low heat until the pasta is done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chopped parsley and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can either add the sauce to the pasta or serve separately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with some additional parmigiano and a leaf of parsley.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings:1-4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>for 1 liter of Glühwein&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50 g Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25 g Raisins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 orange&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cinamon bark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 star anise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>throw everything in a pot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid><description>&lt;p>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion, chopped or powder (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic, chopped or powder (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mayonnaise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Horseradish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worchestershire sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dijon mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pickle relish (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put ingredients into bowl or cup.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix together thoroughly.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Danish Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/danish-pancake.webp" alt="pancake">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Danish Pancake recipe&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>375g wheat flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 ½ tablespoon sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>9 dl milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat a pan with butter or margarine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn when one side starts turning brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They are done when both sides start turning brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Butter or Margarine when needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="served-with">Served With&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Syrup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powdered sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marmalade (Jam)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Bolinhos de Coco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures.
Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300 g coconut&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 egg yolks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 whole egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powdered sugar (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scoop tablespoons of the batter into a cookie sheet or cupcake pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for around 10 minutes or until slightly brown on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Top with powdered sugar if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let cool and enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Brigadeiro</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/brigadeiro.webp" alt="Brigadeiro">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A very traditional Brazilian dessert that is present in every Brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One can of condensed milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One spoon of butter (Actual butter and preferably unsalted. No margarine!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkles (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add all ingredients into a pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) until it stops sticking to the bottom of the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove it from the pan and eat it with a spoon or roll it into small balls.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you chose to roll it into balls, you may also roll them around in sprinkles while still hot.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="closing-remarks">Closing remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Depending on how much brigadeiro you want to make, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to add more or less of each ingredient, so be creative! Be careful with the chocolate powder, you definitely do not want to add too much of it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pickled Red Onions</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pickled-onions.webp" alt="Pickled Red Onions in a Jar">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good way to use up older red onions and goes great with just about anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings Varies&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Red Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut onion in half and slice root to stem and place in a jar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix equal parts of water and vinegar in a pot and bring to a boil. Add salt to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As soon as it begins to boil, turn off and pour the mix into the jar and allow to cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Seal and place in fridge for a few hours until vibrant pink.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can add other herbs or spices before sealing it to give different flavors as well. Use any of your standard pickling spices if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Broccoli with Ginger and Garlic Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Asian inspired broccoli dish with tasty sauce. Sauce can be used for all kinds of Asian inspired sauted vegetables.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1-2 Broccoli (fresh best, frozen works too)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minced garlic (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minced ginger (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sherry or regular white wine (you cook with what you drink with!) (1 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy sauce (1-2 tablespoon)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut broccoli into little flourettes (hold the broccoli upside down and cut around the stem with a pairing knife)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill your pan (or wok) around half inch (1.57cm) with water and bring to a rapid boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put broccoli in and steam with lid on for approx. 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain broccoli and wipe pan dry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One teaspoon of oil and saute garlic and ginger (use sesame seed oil for Asian touch, but neutral or olive oil works well too).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with sherry, put half a cup (approx 120 ml) of warm water or chicken stock. Reduce on medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in soy sauce, brown sugar and lemon juice to your taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thicken sauce with corn starch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put dry cooked broccoli back in and saute for very short time (you want it nice and crunchy).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Simple Tuna Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tuna-salad.webp" alt="Tuna Salad">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 (7 oz) can white tuna, drained&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 tablespoons mayonnaise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoons sweet pickle relish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A pinch of garlic powder (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons white vinegar or lemon juice (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup shredded cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 chopped hard-boiled egg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a medium bowl, stir together tuna, mayonnaise, and relish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add optional ingredients like vinegar, cheese or hard-boiled eggs if wanted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season with garlic powder, salt, and pepper if wanted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4 people&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup flour (2.5 dl)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup milk (2.5 dl)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 very ripe bananas&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add mashed bananas and mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add some butter to a medium warm frying pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make smaller or bigger pancakes, up to you. Wait until tiny air bubbles form on top (2 to 5 minutes), turn and continue frying until the bottom is browned. Repeat.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Either eat the pancakes as they get ready or put a plate in a preheated oven (low degree) to keep the ready pancakes warm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</guid><description>&lt;p>🍽️ Servings: 6 patties&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup soft bread crumb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 pound ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>dash pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon cayenne&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons of fat or salad oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine all ingredients except fat: mix well; shape into 6 patties.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat fat in skillet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brown patties on all sides; lower heat; cook to desired degree of
doneness.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Hellfire Steak</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first learned this recipe from a Bishop I had growing up. It produces quite a good steak despite the unconventional ingredients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Steak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kosher Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mustard Powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tabasco Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Rub a generous amount of salt all over the steak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coat the entire steak with mustard powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour Tabasco Sauce onto both sides of the steak, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to put more on than you think you might otherwise be comfortable with the salt will cancel out a lot of the spice while grilling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grill over low heat until steak is cooked to your preference.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Oaty Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3⁄4 cup milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3⁄4 rolled oats&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1⁄2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 tablespoon sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1⁄2 cup flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25g butter (melted)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to
combine ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or
sprayed griddle or fry pan. Turn spoon for round
pancakes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn pancakes as soon as bubbles form and
burst in the middle. Slide thin metal blade under
pancake and flip over. Second side is cooked when
centre springs back.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a dab of butter on cooked surface of several
pancakes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pile up so butter is between pancakes. Pour
syrup over before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve Oaty pancakes for breakfast or brunch, with juice
or coffee. Pour syrup over the pile of buttered pancakes
and serve bacon or sausages alongside if you like.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Simple sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tomato sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mayonaise&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity. More mayonnaise, more sweetness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Fried Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil or Crème Fraîche&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel and cut the potatoes to desired size.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a bit of Oil or Crème Fraîche in your pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put both the potatoes and the onions into the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook them until they&amp;rsquo;re golden-brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether
or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever
suits your lifestyle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Green onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loaf of French Bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tabasco&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the pan heats up, use your hands and tear off pieces of bread that are roughly the size of your hand.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure you have one piece of bread per egg you want to make. I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled with the egg:bread ratios, and this seems to work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the olive oil starts smelling a bit (or smoke comes off of it), crack in however many eggs you care to eat. Turn down the heat to medium.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Act fast! As the eggs start cooking, prepare a plate with two handfuls of chopped green onion and Tabasco.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After about four minutes (or when the tops of the eggs start to set), take out eggs and place on top of bed of onions &amp;amp; Tabasco.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn heat back to medium-high and add a touch more olive oil. Place pieces of bread in pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every so often, move the pieces of bread around to soak up the oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the bread is about to turn a good shade of golden-brown, add a generous sprinkle of Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s to the plated eggs (on top of them).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and move the pan off the burner. Take out bread pieces and place on the same plate as the eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with glass of ice-cold beer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Ideally, you won&amp;rsquo;t even need a fork! Simply use the bread to guide the eggs on top of each piece, break the yolk into the piece, and take a large
bite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/8 teaspoon pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup milk, scalded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon butter, or margarine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 egg yolks, beaten until thick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 egg whites, beaten stiff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow it to cool; combine with egg yolks, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold in egg whites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set oven for moderate 350°F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour egg mixture into hot buttered frying pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook over low heat 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer to oven; bake 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Omelet is done when an inserted knife comes out clean.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut across at right angles to handle of pan, being careful not to cut all the way through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold carefully from handle to opposite side and serve on hot platter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="for-cheese-omelet">For Cheese Omelet&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add 1/2 cup grated sharp Cheddar Cheese just before folding in egg whites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before putting omelet in oven, sprinkle top with an additional 1/2 cup of grated cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Quesadilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/quesadilla.webp" alt="brisket quesadilla" title="Brisket and Bean Quesadilla with using Montery Jack Cheese">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick and easy low-prep meal, able to be taken anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Serves: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1-2 tortillas. Any brand works, but you can decide if you want the tortilla folded in half, or 2 tortillas together.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~4 small pinches of (Mozzarella, Oaxaca, or Montery Jack cheese).
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Most cheeses are fine, but the taste of oaxaca cheese is more authentic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have pre-grated cheese, you can cut thin slices off of the block of cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A thin coating of oil on the pan. It will be more traditional, but also more unhealthy. (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any ingredients you want. ie, veggies, chicken, mushrooms (cooked), or beans&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat a pan to medium with an (optional) thin coating of oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lay a single tortilla down on the pan and arrange cheese on the edges.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Arrange on 1 edge if you are making a folded quesadilla. Do both edges if using 2 tortillas. The cheese will help make sure the ingredients don&amp;rsquo;t fall out when flipping.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the ingredients onto one half of the tortilla if using 1, or the entire surface if using 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold empty half of the tortilla in the pan onto itself if you are only using one tortilla.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you are using 2 simply place the second on top of the first.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Periodically flip the tortilla until both sides are golden brown.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This may be hard if using 2 tortillas, so try your best or transfer it to a plate, flip it with your hands, and transfer it back to the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tortellini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cooking cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring water to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt to water only after boiling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tortellini in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in and let eggs cook using heat from the pot and tortellini.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve on a plate. Add pepper, more salt if needed, and optionally, shredded cheese on top for extra creaminess.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tuna Sub</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Use the best tuna you can find. I like oil-packed but water is OK. Someone you know has a tuna salad recipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 recipe of your favorite tuna salad&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sandwich bun or bread (a good one)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thinly sliced cheese (your favorite)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sliced tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Baby spinach leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pickles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mayo and mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other sandwich toppings (very little out of bounds here).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Lightly toast one side of the bun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add cheese to bottom of bun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread a layer of tuna salad&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place several spinach leaves on top bun&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add sliced tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add pickle slices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season with salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine halves and enjoy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/cacio-e-pepe.webp" alt="pepe">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino Romano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package
according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it. See &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile place the peppercorns on a cutting board and mash them with a pestle.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place half of the peppercorns in a pan and toast them at medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the pasta, place it in the pan and save the boiling water for later use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the pasta with the pepper with 2 spoons of the water previously saved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare the Pecorino by putting half of it a bowl with a spoon of the pasta water you saved; continue mixing the cheese with the water until a cream is formed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the pasta is almost cooked, add the cream and mix (you can add more water if the pasta is too dry).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve on a plate with the Pecorino left before on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/carbonara.webp" alt="carbonara">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it.
I recommend using the best ingredients you can source.
Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This recipe assumes medium eggs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks. Add a generous amount of your preferred grated cheese (Pecorino or Parmigiano) around 35g (you can optionally add a dash of black pepper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill a pot with water and salt it less than typical &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">pasta&lt;/a> water. When it boils, cook the pasta one minute less than advised.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the preferred pork (Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta) in an iron or nonstick pan (if using a different kind of pan add a dash of extra virgin olive oil) on low to medium heat until the sides are crisp but the insides are chewy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While everything is being cooked and fried, beat the eggs manually using a fork until everything is entirely liquid. Remember to watch the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When your pasta is done (-1 minute), drain it and put it in the bowl with eggs. At this step you may consider the timing: if the pasta is too hot you will cook the eggs, and some people don&amp;rsquo;t like it this way, so just wait for a minute. Keep moving and stirring to fully incorporate the eggs. Add guanciale and as many fats remaining in the pan as you want. Keep moving and stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plate and optionally garnish with the preferred grated cheese and black pepper. Voila.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick and simple bread spread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>10 dried plums&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 jar of dried tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp of smoked paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pinch of dried coriander (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want to make it more liquid you can add water from the plums.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Flammkuchen</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up.
I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings:2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>400g Pizza dough (either bought or from &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pizza-dough">Pizza Dough&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>we start by flattening the dough. Even if you buy thin crust that is already sold as &amp;lsquo;super thin&amp;rsquo; you have to make it even thinner. Make it so thin that you can fill 2 baking sheets with it (yes, you will make two large flammkuchen - since they are thin you need one per person) :) I take two pieces of parchment paper, put the dough in between and flatten it using a bottle (e.g. wine). It has to be as thin as possible (1-2 mm).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>once the dough is flat, put it on your baking tray and preheat the oven at 450 to 500 Fahrenheit (230 to 260 Celsius)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>distribute the sour cream evenly (it should be a very thin layer, just barely covering the dough&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut the onion and bacon into small pieces and distribute onion, bacon/vegetables (also in small pieces) evenly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put in the oven for 10 minutes and take it out when it is getting a bit dark. The thin parts will get a bit brown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put salt and pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I usually take it down from the baking tray and let it cool down for 2-5 minutes before eating&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2 people&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can coconut milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 small or 5 big mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lime&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil. Add the noodle spices. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t like it too creamy, add extra water.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop the mushrooms and coriander (and other veggies if you wish). Cut the lime into four pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When boiling add mushroom, and crack the eggs directly into the pot (be sure not to stir after this, otherwise they will break). Wait 30 seconds to 1 minute.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the noodles and salad leaves (or whatever veggie you got).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After 3-5 minutes it&amp;rsquo;s done. Serve in deep bowls. Squeeze the lime juice and chopped coriander on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Pro tip: Squeeze some remaining lime juice into your drinking water.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pancake.webp" alt="Pancakes made at home">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>200g wheat flour or 100g glutenfree flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200 ml milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a little bit of salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix all ingredients in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the dough rest for ~15 mins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a pan with a bit butter or oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="served-with">Served with&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Syrup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cinnamon and sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid><description>&lt;p>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>porkchops: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>shallots: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mustard: 2tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the shallots into small dices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the gherkins into long strips.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the porkchops are cooked, set them aside in a warm environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweat the shallots in the same pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with white wine, let it reduce until there&amp;rsquo;s about two teaspoons left.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the stock.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the gherkins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in the mustard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the sauce reduce until it gets a coating consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in a knob a butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the chops back in, flip them to coat them in sauce, warm them up for 30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with a nice mashed potato or saute potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Oats</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become
great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions
on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do
with oats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>oats&lt;/li>
&lt;li>water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pinch of salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Pick and choose additional ingredients:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>chopped banana&lt;/li>
&lt;li>any berries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>peanut butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring water (with pinch of salt) to boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add oats. Use a 2:1 water-to-oats ratio (by volume) for rolled oats, 3:1 for
steel cut.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil on medium heat until most of the water has been absorbed/evaporated.
Rolled oats will be ready quicker than steel cut.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour over fruit in bowl (if having fruit).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle cinnamon (if having cinnamon).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a spoonful of peanut butter (if having peanut butter).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="serving-sizes">Serving sizes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll need less dry steel cut oats versus rolled oats for the same serving
size. My personal &amp;ldquo;standard serving&amp;rdquo; is 1/3 cup steel cut or 1/2 cup rolled
(note that, per the ratios above, both of these end up needing 1 cup water).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta.
TL;DR: you boil it.
Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta-sauce">pasta sauce&lt;/a> or used in another dish.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>basil (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring water to a rolling boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now add pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep it boiling, but decrease heat as it tries to overflow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until pasta is at the preferred softness (see below), then strain it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the pasta is sitting in your strainer, you may add basil leaves or other herbs and aromatics. I also recommend taking a knob or so of room temperature butter and add it in and stirring it, melting it into the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-long-should-pasta-be-cooked">How long should pasta be cooked?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The often recommended way to cook most pasta is &lt;em>al dente&lt;/em>, which often means &amp;ldquo;slightly undercooked,&amp;rdquo; or with a subtle firmness that makes it still substantial.
Cooking pasta more than that is no great crime,
but if you keep it in there for &lt;em>too&lt;/em> long, it&amp;rsquo;ll become mush.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>