<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eggs on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eggs on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eggs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid>
      <description>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the homepage.
Ingredients  eggs butter cheese(optional) milk (optional)  Directions Boiled eggs  Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged). Place eggs in water. Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency (about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium runny, 10+ for hard boiled).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frittata</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid>
      <description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6  Ingredients  4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional)  Directions  Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hangover Eggs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients  Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer  Directions  Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omelet</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets  Ingredients  2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 3/4 cup milk, scalded 1 tablespoon butter, or margarine 4 egg yolks, beaten until thick 4 egg whites, beaten stiff Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet)  Directions  Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soleier (pickled eggs)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</guid>
      <description>Soleier are a german pub dish. They are typically enjoyed between two beers.
 ⏲️ Preparation time: 10min 🍳 Cook time: 10min 🍽️ Servings: 10  Ingredients  peels of five onions 10 eggs 2 loorber leaves 3 cloves 4 allspice 1Tbsp peppercorns 1Tbsp caraway seeds 1Tbsp mustard seeds 1tsp of Szechuan pepper (optional) 1tsp lovage (optional) 1tsp nutmeg (optional) 100mL vinegar 3 cloves of garlic  Directions  Put 750mL of water and the peels of five onions in a pot and let them cook for five minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Tortilla</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 6  Ingredients  8 free-range eggs 1 kg of potatoes 1 white onion Extra virgin olive oil  Directions  Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes. Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir. Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
