<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Israeli on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/israeli/</link><description>Recent content in Israeli on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/israeli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Challah Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</guid><description>&lt;p>A kind of braided bread preparation.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 2-4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>NOTE: Prep time does not account for the 3-4 hours the dough must be left to rise and cool (see directions 5, 10, &amp;amp; 12).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>600ml ( 1 Pint ) warm water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon dry active baking yeast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>7 tablespoons honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5kg flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon poppy seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fill a large bowl with the water, and sprinkle with the yeast.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk together: honey, oil, 2 eggs, and salt. Add to bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add flour to bowl in small amounts, beating/whisking after each addition.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the mixtures becomes a viscous dough, begin kneading until smooth and elastic, and no longer sticky.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover bowl with a damp cloth and let rise for 1-2 hours, or until dough has doubled in size.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle flour onto a chopping board, place the dough onto it and divide in half.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knead each half, adding flour as needed to keep the dough non-sticky.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide each half into thirds and roll into a long snake about 4cm (1.5in) in girth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pinch the ends of the each three snakes together firmly and plait them together, making two items of braided dough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grease two baking trays or use baking paper, cover with dry cloth and let rise for one hour. Preheat oven to 190Â°C / Gas mark 5.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk an egg and brush onto each plait, sprinkle with seeds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake until bread has a hollow sound when tapped, cool on a rack for an hour before slicing.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>