<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>roast on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/roast/</link><description>Recent content in roast on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/roast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need a good-sized lidded pot that can go in the oven for this. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that then you can use a large roasting tray with sides and cover it with foil, sealing it as best you can. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent celebration or Sunday meal.
Ingredients Lamb shoulder, or something similar, like lamb shank, preferably on the bone. Get something that will fit in your pot, with room for vegetables around it.</description></item><item><title>Medieval Beef Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</guid><description>Medieval beef soup with turnips and turnip greens.
Ingredients One beef roast Around three to four large turnips with their greens attached Two cups of chicken stock 1/10 grams of Saffron 1/4 a stick of butter A slow cooker A bowl of warm water. Directions Cube the roast into bite sized pieces and place them in a large skillet with the butter. Heat the pan on medium-high heat and brown the meat with the melted butter until the outside is evenly cooked, sprinkle with pepper as it browns.</description></item><item><title>Roasted chicken breast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</guid><description>How to roast chicken breast with a &amp;ldquo;leave-in&amp;rdquo; probe thermometer. The thermometer ensures the chicken comes out juicy and delicious.
Ingredients Boneless skinless chicken breast(s) 1/4 stick of butter per chicken breast Seasoning (optional) Directions Fill a large bowl with enough water to submerge the chicken. Add salt to the water until it&amp;rsquo;s fully saturated. Put the chicken under the water and let it sit for 20-40 minutes at room temperature.</description></item><item><title>Tuscan Style Pork Roast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</guid><description>An herbaceous pancetta stuffed pork roast with a crispy exterior. Finished with a lemon vinaigrette. Adapted from Binging With Babish whose instructions are notoriously bad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 people Equipment Food processor Fine mesh strainer Cast iron skillet Butchers twine Ingredients 1 pork Roast 2-3 Tbsp fresh rosemary 8 cloves garlic, minced ⅓ cup high quality olive oil 1 lemon 4 oz pancetta or bacon 1 tsp fresh parsley Directions Preheat oven to 275°F (135°C) Butterfly the roast by cutting into three parts by cutting into the side starting a third of the way up the roast.</description></item></channel></rss>