<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pasta on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/pasta/</link><description>Recent content in pasta on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/pasta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One-Pot Chicken Tetrazzini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Butter 8 oz Mushrooms, sliced 1 small Red Pepper, chopped 1 small Onion, finely chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 4 cups Milk 2 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 8 oz Extra Broad Egg Noodles 5 oz Boursin Garlic and Fine Herbs 3 cup Deli Chicken, cooked and cut into bite-size pieces 1/2 cup Frozen Peas 1/2 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped Small Fresh Basil Leaves (optional) Parmesan, grated Directions Melt butter in a large saucepan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Pasta Primavera</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 12 oz Linguine 1/2 lb Asparagus, cut into 2&amp;quot; pieces 1/4 lb Green Beans, halved 1 cup Sugar Snap Peas, trimmed 1/2 cup Frozen Edamame or Peas 1 Tbsp Butter 1 small Onion, minced 2 cloves Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 2 1/2 cup Milk 1/3 lb Smoked Salmon, cut into wide strips 1/2 cup Fresh Mint, coarsely chopped 1/2 Lemon Directions In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook linguine 10 min or until al dente, adding asparagus, beans, and sugar snap peas during the last 3 minutes of cooking and edamame during the last minute.</description></item><item><title>Egyptian Lentils</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 1 cup Lentils 1 cup Elbow Macaroni 2 Fresh Chili or Bell Peppers 2 Tbsp Lime Juice 1 1/2 cup Regular Rice 3 Tbsp Oil 2 medium Tomatoes, chopped 1 large Onion, diced Directions Place lentils in a saucepan and cover by 1&amp;quot; or more of water. Turn heat to high and bring to a boil, then turn down heat to simmer, and cook covered for 35 minutes or until tender.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter sauce.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min Ingredients spaghetti or fettucine butter heavy cream garlic oregano white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended) lemon/lemon juice (optional) red pepper flakes (optional) seafood, choose from: mussels squid shrimp clams lobster Directions Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow these instructions. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook slightly once we add the sauce.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp Fettuccine Alfredo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</guid><description>Shrimp fettuccine alfredo is one of the best tasting and low effort dishes. The recipe i give below yields an alfredo sauce that is a bit on the thicker side. If you want a thinner sauce, adding a touch or two more milk will thin out the sauce. This is a great meal for 3-4 people or you can eat one serving and freeze the rest for 2-3 more dinners.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Pasta Olive oil Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers Crushed garlic cloves Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta) Chopped parsley Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended) Directions Start heating up water for the pasta. Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat. Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.</description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 Ingredients Pasta layer 600g penne rigate salted water Meat layer 1 large onion, finely diced 700g lean ground beef .5 TB ground allspice .5 TB ground cinnamon .25 TSP ground clove (optional) 340g tomato paste Béchamel layer 226g butter 226g flour 1L cold milk 237ml chicken stock freshly grated nutmeg (optional) grated cheese (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 190°C In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Sausage Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</guid><description>A delicious spicy pasta dish, super easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a student and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap for how much food you get. I found it in a newspaper a while back and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it with you guys because it&amp;rsquo;s my favourite meal. I also like to drink the excess red wine while cooking which adds to the enjoyment of cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 red onions, chopped Olive oil 6 spicy Italian sausages 1 sprig rosemary, needles finely chopped 1 red chilli, deseeded and diced A large glass of red wine (approx.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom Stroganov</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</guid><description>Prep time: 10 Minutes Cook time: 20 Minutes Servings: 2
Ingredients 8 oz uncooked pasta (spaghetti or any other long noodle will work. Stroganov can also be served over rice.) 12 oz mushrooms (I reccommend shitake, but white, portabello, or maitake will also work.) 2 cloves of garlic, minced 1 small yellow onion, minced 2 Tbsp butter 1 Tbsp general purpose flour 1 Cup vegetable broth 1 Tsp dijon mustard 1 Tsp Smoked paprika 4 Tbsp creme fraiche (can be made by mixing equal parts heavy and sour cream) 2 Tbsp parsely Directions Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and cook pasta al dente In a cup, combine flour, mustard, smoked paprika, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Ravioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</guid><description>
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Dough 4 eggs 400 g 00 flour Drizzle of olive oil Cheese Filling 1 lemon 50 g grated Pecorino Romano cheese 250 g ricotta 1 egg Seafood Fillings Chopped leftover lobster legs, lobster tail, or minced crab (optional) Directions The basic rule of thumb I use for pasta is 100g, 1 egg per person For this recipe you can go two ways, the old school &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; method or a kitchen aid mixer (skip to step 7) For the well method, pile the flour onto the counter and with your hand carve a hole or a well in the center Crack the eggs into the center of the well, and drizzle a bit of olive oil into the center With a fork, begin slowly breaking up, mixing, and incorporating the egg into the flour until there is no longer any loose egg that can escape the outer well border At this point use your hands to bring the sandy mixture together and knead the dough for about 5-10 minutes or until the dough is smooth For the stand mixer method just throw all the ingredients into the mixer with a dough hook and set it to level 4 for about 3-5 minutes and it will be done You might need to scrape the sides down and maybe hand knead the dough a bit longer after it&amp;rsquo;s done to make it into a nice smooth ball Cover the dough with plastic wrap and let it rest in the fridge a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to roll out (15-30 mins) While the dough is resting, make the filling by first mixing the ricotta and egg into a bowl Zest and juice a lemon peel into the bowl Optionally add seafood ingredients at this point Grate the Pecorino into the bowl, add salt and pepper to taste, and mix to distribute the ingredients evenly Take out the dough and cut it into 4 pieces, keeping the ones not currently being worked on covered so they don&amp;rsquo;t dry out Roll the dough out with a pasta machine down to the point where you can just barely see your hand through it (setting 2-3 out of 7) or roll it out with a rolling pin into a long sheet, maybe like 16 x 8 inches or so At this point you can either cut the sheet in half and make two sheets, a top and bottom, or one sheet, where you will fold the dough over and use the folded seam as one side of the ravioli Using a teaspoon, evenly space out the ricotta filling onto the sheets, leaving a few inches on each side for the seams As stated in step 16, either take the 2nd sheet and place it over top or fold over the dough and press down firmly, forcing out any air and making sure the two pieces of dough stick You may need to brush some water onto the dough if it is too heavily floured and not sticking Using a fancy pasta cutter, a knife, or even a pizza cutter, cut evenly between the seams of the raviolis to separate them If you used a pasta cutter, you are now done, store the raviolis on a floured wax paper sheet or freeze them for later If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a pasta cutter, use a fork to press down the dough around the edges of the cut raviolis to ensure they are firmly closed and no leaks or air bubbles are visible, or else they will explode when cooked To cook, throw them in salted boiling water and they will let you know when they&amp;rsquo;re done when they float to the top (1-2 minutes) Serve the seafood version with a simple fresh red sauce and basil, or spice it up a bit and go with a base of red sauce with some added heavy cream, and a pinch of red pepper flakes to make a pink sauce for the seafood version</description></item><item><title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g pasta 500g broccoli 4 eggs 200g scamorza cheese 400g béchamel sage (optional) parmesan cheese (optional) Directions Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside. Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes. While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan. Put a layer of béchamel. Put a layer of pasta.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</guid><description>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&amp;rsquo;s all I had that day.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g) Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&amp;rsquo;d like) Extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup (40g) Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g) White wine 1/4 cup (60g) Tomato passata 10oz (300g) Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g) (optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan Directions Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.</description></item><item><title>Bolognese Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid><description>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours Ingredients extra virgin olive oil 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 large onion 2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional) 200 grams pancetta (optional) 300 grams beef mince 350 grams pork mince 350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork) 140 grams concentrated tomato paste 690 grams diced tomatoes water 1 can peeled tomatoes 1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open) 1 glass of milk (optional) 1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional) Directions Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 mins 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended) Flour (Wheat flour recommended) Directions Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan. Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan. Stir and turn on maximum heat. Keep stirring until it becomes thick. If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Alla Norma</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid><description>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 aubergines (900g) 300g spaghetti 100ml olive oil 5 garlic cloves, minced 1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes) 2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon caster sugar Fresh basil Directions Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</description></item><item><title>Baba's Feta Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</guid><description>Greek Pasta Recipe with sauce made out of feta, stock, cream cheese and other ingredients. Uses mixed spice for special flavour, and is a great dinner or mid-day meal.
⏲️ Prep time: 15-30 min 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients Serves Around 3 People. You can scale up to 4 If you increase most quantities by +1/4.
Medium Sweet Onion (Finely Chopped) Virgin olive oil (not extra-virgin) White Sugar 3 Fresh Medium Garlic Cloves (Chopped Fine) 15-20 Kalamon/Kalamata Olives (Cut into thirds) Whole small courgette (Cut to small pieces) 6 Medium Mushrooms (Cut smallish and small stalk) 1/2 Broccli (Chopped small) 8-10 Finely sliced cherry tomatoes 1/2 Block of feta (Washed) 1 Chicken stock (Added to 3/4 Mug boiling water) Overfilled Teaspoon Mixed Spice 3/4 Bowls fusilli pasta Overfilled tablespoon Creme Cheese 1/3 Mug whole milk Directions Make sure to prepare &amp;amp; chop most ingredients before you start.</description></item><item><title>Baked Mostaccioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</guid><description>Pasta baked in dish with spicy sauce
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 bowls Ingredients 24 oz or 1 jar of Fradiavolo Sauce (Victoria) 1 box Mostaccioli Rigati or Penne Rigati (Ronzoni) ~8 oz shredded Mozzarella Cheese (Poly-O) I&amp;rsquo;ve found that pre-shredded cheese doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good as shredding it right before cooking. 2x 2 quart (8&amp;quot;) baking dishes or 1 large baking dish (see picture below) Directions Bring a pot to a boil and cook pasta for 6 minutes (very al dente).</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential) 50g Butter 100g Flour 200ml Milk 400g Cheddar Cheese 6 Rashers of bacon (optional) Directions Grate the cheese. Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares. Start cooking the pasta. Start melting the butter in another saucepan. Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides.</description></item><item><title>Lasagna</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</guid><description>A nice recipe for amazing fully home-made lasagna.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients Parmesan cheese Emental cheese (optional) Dry mozzarella cheese Fresh Bolognese sauce or about 1 litre worth of store-bought sauce Béchamel sauce or ricotta lasagna filling Lasagna pasta sheets Directions Prepare the bolognese or jared pasta sauce. When the sauce is almost done cooking prepare your béchamel or ricotta filling.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti aglio e olio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</guid><description>Aglio e olio, pasta with garlic and olive oil, is one of the simplest yet greatest pasta dishes of all time. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, easy, and uses a lot of basic pantry ingredients which makes this a convenient weeknight meal.
🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound (500g) spaghetti (or similarly shaped pasta) 1/2 cup (110g) extra virgin olive oil 5-6 cloves of garlic 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes A bunch of fresh parsley Directions Heat a large skillet on medium-high heat, start cooking the pasta.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</guid><description>author: postbellum Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &amp;ldquo;Gaeta&amp;rdquo; olives, and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.
⏲️Prep time: ~18 min 🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min 🍽️Servings: 4 Ingredients Pot of water 320g italian spaghetti 2 garlic cloves 10g salted capers 25g anchovies in oil 800g peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo; 1 bunch of parsley 100g Gaeta olives 2 chopped chillies A pinch of salt Directions Wash capers from salt, then cut them Pit and crush Gaeta olives Wash and chop the bunch of parsley Start cooking the pasta until al dente.</description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups Tomato purée Parmigiano (grated) Parsley Directions Start cooking the pasta. Mix the cream with the purée and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down to medium and add the grated parmigiano.</description></item><item><title>Dominican Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 box Spaghetti 1 Onion minced 1 Green Pepper minced 2 Garlic cloves minced 1 tbsp Chicken Bouillon Cube or Adobo 1 tbsp sazón 1 tbsp Tomato Paste 1 cup Tomato Sauce 1 tbsp Butter ¼ cup Evaporated Milk 2 tbsp Green Olives 1 tsp Sugar 1 cup Starchy Pasta Water Directions Boil spaghetti. In a separate pan, Sauté onions, peppers, and garlic until soft.</description></item><item><title>Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</guid><description>This is a based, easy and relatively quick to make meal. Great for making in large batches with a big pot and eating throughout the week.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6+ Ingredients 1/4 lb. Pork Sausage 1 lb. Med ground beef 1 3/4 Cups Elbow macaroni 1 Can of tomato sauce Diced half onion Diced half bell pepper Oregano leaves Paprika Sage Thyme Marjoram Rosemary leaves 2 Large grated garlic cloves Onion powder Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot sauce (optional) Mozzarella Cheese (optional) Better than Bulion 1 3/4 cups of Macaroni Elbows Directions Season the meat with the paprika, sage, thyme, marjoram, rosmary leaves, oregano leaves, and black pepper Saute the onion and the bell pepper until they become soft.</description></item><item><title>Quick Breakfast Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</guid><description>A quick breakfast spaghetti recipe that covers a healthy amount of carbs, fat, and spices. Eggs and/or bacon can be added to cover some protein, you should cook those while the boiler is cooking the spaghetti for time efficiency.
Ingredients Spaghetti (any kind you prefer) Ground spices (I like to use cumin, turmeric, paprika, and garlic) Tomato Paste/Sauce (preferably one with basil and without preservative) Extra Virgin Olive Oil Directions Boil some water fully and prepare a pot.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6 Ingredients For the sauce ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional) For the meatballs 1 lb.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid><description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese. Directions Preheat oven to 400F/200C.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Navy Style</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</guid><description>This is one of the three pasta dishes that I usually cook. It&amp;rsquo;s a Russian pasta recipe that is fast and easy to make and is quite tasty.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two hearty adult portions:
250g pasta. Usually I prefer to use fusilli or penne, but any short-cut pasta should do. 300-400g ground beef 3-4 tomatoes 1 carrot 1/2 onion 2-3 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika Directions Add olive oil to your frying pan, heat it to medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>Ingredients Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional) Directions Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs. Mix in and let eggs cook using heat from the pot and tortellini.</description></item><item><title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid><description>A swiss favorite, Älplermagronen combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet. It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.
🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients ~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes 3 onions (medium size) 400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy) 1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk 400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight) ~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese. Appenzeller works best.</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour) Directions Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional) Directions Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil Directions Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat. Add enough olive oil to gently fry the crumbles.</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea. Bring water to a rolling boil.</description></item></channel></rss>