<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pasta on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/pasta/</link><description>Recent content in Pasta on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/pasta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One-Pot Chicken Tetrazzini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 oz Mushrooms, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Red Pepper, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove Garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cups Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 oz Extra Broad Egg Noodles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 oz Boursin Garlic and Fine Herbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cup Deli Chicken, cooked and cut into bite-size pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Frozen Peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Small Fresh Basil Leaves (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parmesan, grated&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Melt butter in a large saucepan over medium-high heat. Add mushrooms, red pepper, onion and garlic; cook, stirring about 5 minutes until tender.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle with flour and stir. Gradually whisk in milk then Worcestershire, salt and pepper. Stirring occasionally, bring to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add noodles, reduce heat to a low boil. Stirring constantly and around edges of pan, cook until pasta is tender, about 7 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in chunks of Boursin, then chicken, peas, and parsley, stirring until chicken is hot and Boursin is melted. Serve sprinkled with basil and Parmesan.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Pasta Primavera</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>12 oz Linguine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 lb Asparagus, cut into 2&amp;quot; pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 lb Green Beans, halved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Sugar Snap Peas, trimmed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Frozen Edamame or Peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves Garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 1/2 cup Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 lb Smoked Salmon, cut into wide strips&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Fresh Mint, coarsely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook linguine 10 min or until al dente, adding asparagus, beans, and sugar snap peas during the last 3 minutes of cooking and edamame during the last minute. Drain very well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile in large saucepan, melt butter over medium heat. Add onion and garlic; cook, stirring 3 minutes. Stir in flour. Very gradually whisk in milk until smooth and stir often until mixture boils and has thickened (5 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add pasta mixture, stirring until hot. Stir in salmon and mint just until mixed. Squeeze juice from lemon into pasta and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Egyptian Lentils</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup Lentils&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Elbow Macaroni&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Fresh Chili or Bell Peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Lime Juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cup Regular Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 medium Tomatoes, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large Onion, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place lentils in a saucepan and cover by 1&amp;quot; or more of water. Turn heat to high and bring to a boil, then turn down heat to simmer, and cook covered for 35 minutes or until tender. Drain and transfer to a large bowl. Set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring 3 cups of water to a boil, add rice. Turn down to simmer for 20 minutes and fluff up rice with a fork and add to lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil 2 quarts of water, add elbow macaroni and cook until tender. Add to lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a small skillet add 1 Tbsp of oil and saute chopped peppers finely for two minutes. Add the tomato, 1/2 cup of water, bring to a boil and simmer for 5 minutes. Add the lime juice. Fold this sauce into the lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In another skillet heat 2 Tbsp oil, add onions and saute until brown. Garnish lentil mixture with the browned onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter
sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>spaghetti or fettucine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lemon/lemon juice (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>red pepper flakes (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>seafood, choose from:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>mussels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>squid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>shrimp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>clams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lobster&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">these
instructions&lt;/a>. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook
slightly once we add the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Defrost/Deshell your seafood of choice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop a half tablespoon of garlic into small pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large pan on medium heat, saute your chopped garlic in salt and butter for a
minute or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add and saute the seafood. Season with oregano, red pepper flakes and salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a half cup heavy cream and a third cup of white wine to the pan. Cook until you have the
consistency you want.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain your pasta (Which should be cooked by now) and pour contents of the pan into the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Shrimp Fettuccine Alfredo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shrimp fettuccine alfredo is one of the best tasting and low effort dishes.
The recipe i give below yields an alfredo sauce that is a bit on the thicker side.
If you want a thinner sauce, adding a touch or two more milk will thin out the sauce.
This is a great meal for 3-4 people or you can eat one serving and freeze the rest for 2-3 more dinners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pasta-arrabbiata.webp" alt="arrabiata">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crushed garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Start heating up water for the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add your crushed tomatoes, together with some salt and pepper, increase the heat to medium and let simmer for 10-15 minutes or until it looks nicely thickened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the water starts boiling, put a handful of salt into it and then your pasta of choice. Ideally leave the pasta slightly undercooked, because it will go in the hot sauce and finish cooking there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the sauce is almost ready, add most of your chopped parsley and stir it around. Save some to top the dish later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the pasta is ready (ideally at the same time as the sauce or slightly later), strain it and add it to the sauce, which should be off the heat. If the sauce looks a bit too thick, add some of the pasta water. Mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add some of the grated cheese of your choice and stir it in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with some more grated cheese and chopped parsley on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 50 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6-8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="pasta-layer">Pasta layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>600g penne rigate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>salted water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="meat-layer">Meat layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 large onion, finely diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>700g lean ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.5 TB ground allspice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.5 TB ground cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>.25 TSP ground clove (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>340g tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="béchamel-layer">Béchamel layer&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>226g butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>226g flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1L cold milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>237ml chicken stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>freshly grated nutmeg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grated cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 190°C&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions. Drain and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook onion in a bit of oil until soft. Add meat and cook until browned, breaking meat into small pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain any excess grease and add spices. Stir together and cook ~30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix tomato paste with enough water to create a viscous tomato sauce. Add sauce to meat and simmer 2-3 minutes before setting aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a saucepan melt the butter and add the flour. Cook 2-3 mins until no longer starchy, whisking frequently. Add milk gradually and whisk continuously. Add stock and cook until sauce is thickened. Add nutmeg and season to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add thin béchamel layer to bottom of casserole dish and assemble as follows: half pasta, all the meat sauce, 2nd half of pasta, rest of béchamel and cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake covered for 45 minutes, removing lid last 5-10 minutes to brown top. Let cool 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spicy Sausage Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spicy-sausage-pasta.webp" alt="Spicy Sausage Pasta">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A delicious spicy pasta dish, super easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a student and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap for how much food you get. I found it in a newspaper a while back and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it with you guys because it&amp;rsquo;s my favourite meal. I also like to drink the excess red wine while cooking which adds to the enjoyment of cooking.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 50 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 red onions, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 spicy Italian sausages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 sprig rosemary, needles finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 red chilli, deseeded and diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A large glass of red wine (approx. 250ml)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 x 400g tins chopped plum tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g pasta, preferably penne&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g parmesan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300ml double cream&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fry red onions with a splash of oil in a deep frying pan. Add the sausage meat (discarding the casings if need be). Add the rosemary and chilli&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase the heat and break up the sausage meat with a wooden spoon. Once meat has browned, pour in red wine and reduce by half. Add the chopped tomatoes and reduce the sauce, uncovered, for about 30 mins. Cook the pasta according to packet instructions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate the parmesan into a bowl. Drain the pasta and stir into the sauce with the parmesan, double cream and some seasoning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve :)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Mushroom Stroganov</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prep time: 10 Minutes
Cook time: 20 Minutes
Servings: 2&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 oz uncooked pasta (spaghetti or any other long noodle will work. Stroganov can also be served over rice.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 oz mushrooms (I reccommend shitake, but white, portabello, or maitake will also work.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves of garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small yellow onion, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp general purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cup vegetable broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tsp dijon mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tsp Smoked paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Tbsp creme fraiche (can be made by mixing equal parts heavy and sour cream)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp parsely&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and cook pasta al dente&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a cup, combine flour, mustard, smoked paprika, salt and pepper. Add broth and whisk until no lumps remain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While pasta is cooking, melt butter in a medium skillet and over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the butter is melted, add onions and cook until softened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add mushrooms and cook until all water evaporates and mushrooms are slightly browned, about 7 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garlic and cook for another 30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the flour and broth mixture into the mushrooms and cook until thickens, about 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in Creme Fraiche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the strained pasta to the mushroom sauce and stir to coat the pasta completely.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Ravioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/ravioli-01.webp" alt="Ravioli">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳Cook time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="dough">Dough&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400 g 00 flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drizzle of olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="cheese-filling">Cheese Filling&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50 g grated Pecorino Romano cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250 g ricotta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="seafood-fillings">Seafood Fillings&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chopped leftover lobster legs, lobster tail, or minced crab (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The basic rule of thumb I use for pasta is 100g, 1 egg per person&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For this recipe you can go two ways, the old school &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; method or a kitchen aid mixer (skip to step 7)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the well method, pile the flour onto the counter and with your hand carve a hole or a well in the center&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crack the eggs into the center of the well, and drizzle a bit of olive oil into the center&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With a fork, begin slowly breaking up, mixing, and incorporating the egg into the flour until there is no longer any loose egg that can escape the outer well border&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At this point use your hands to bring the sandy mixture together and knead the dough for about 5-10 minutes or until the dough is smooth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the stand mixer method just throw all the ingredients into the mixer with a dough hook and set it to level 4 for about 3-5 minutes and it will be done&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You might need to scrape the sides down and maybe hand knead the dough a bit longer after it&amp;rsquo;s done to make it into a nice smooth ball&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover the dough with plastic wrap and let it rest in the fridge a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to roll out (15-30 mins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the dough is resting, make the filling by first mixing the ricotta and egg into a bowl&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zest and juice a lemon peel into the bowl&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally add seafood ingredients at this point&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate the Pecorino into the bowl, add salt and pepper to taste, and mix to distribute the ingredients evenly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take out the dough and cut it into 4 pieces, keeping the ones not currently being worked on covered so they don&amp;rsquo;t dry out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll the dough out with a pasta machine down to the point where you can just barely see your hand through it (setting 2-3 out of 7) or roll it out with a rolling pin into a long sheet, maybe like 16 x 8 inches or so&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At this point you can either cut the sheet in half and make two sheets, a top and bottom, or one sheet, where you will fold the dough over and use the folded seam as one side of the ravioli
&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/ravioli-02.webp" alt="Lobster Ravioli">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using a teaspoon, evenly space out the ricotta filling onto the sheets, leaving a few inches on each side for the seams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As stated in step 16, either take the 2nd sheet and place it over top or fold over the dough and press down firmly, forcing out any air and making sure the two pieces of dough stick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You may need to brush some water onto the dough if it is too heavily floured and not sticking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using a fancy pasta cutter, a knife, or even a pizza cutter, cut evenly between the seams of the raviolis to separate them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you used a pasta cutter, you are now done, store the raviolis on a floured wax paper sheet or freeze them for later
&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/ravioli-03.webp" alt="Finished Ravioli">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a pasta cutter, use a fork to press down the dough around the edges of the cut raviolis to ensure they are firmly closed and no leaks or air bubbles are visible, or else they will explode when cooked&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To cook, throw them in salted boiling water and they will let you know when they&amp;rsquo;re done when they float to the top (1-2 minutes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve the seafood version with a simple fresh red sauce and basil, or spice it up a bit and go with a base of red sauce with some added heavy cream, and a pinch of red pepper flakes to make a pink sauce for the seafood version
&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/ravioli-04.webp" alt="Served Ravioli">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/baked-pasta-with-broccoli.webp" alt="baked-pasta-with-broccoli">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>500g pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g broccoli&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200g scamorza cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g béchamel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sage (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parmesan cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a layer of béchamel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a layer of pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a layer of broccoli, diced scamorza cheese, pepper, salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to step 4 and repeat until ingredients end.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add sage leafs on top (optional).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the pan inside the (preheated) oven at 180°C for 15~20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>End with 5~10 minutes of cooking with the grill function.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&amp;rsquo;s all I had that day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spaghetti-all-amatriciana.webp" alt="Jebusthebus">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&amp;rsquo;d like)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup (40g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>White wine 1/4 cup (60g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tomato passata 10oz (300g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mince the chili pepper(s) and keep it/them aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the guanciale in thin stripes and cook them in the oil with the minced pepper(s) for about 3 minutes on medium/high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Douse with the wine and turn up the heat. Cook until the alcohol has evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">cooking the pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lower the heat to medium and add the passata, some salt and plenty of pepper. Cook for about 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once finished, drain the pasta and add the sauce and the pecorino/parmesan, mix well and serve immediately. Optionally you can add some pecorino or parmesan on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Bolognese Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/bolognese-sauce-1.webp" alt="Bolognese sauce">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 45 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 celery sticks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200 grams pancetta (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300 grams beef mince&lt;/li>
&lt;li>350 grams pork mince&lt;/li>
&lt;li>350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>140 grams concentrated tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>690 grams diced tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 can peeled tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 glass of milk (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up a large saucepan or dutch oven on medium low heat and put enough olive oil in to cover the bottom of the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put in your diced veggies and pancetta and let it slowly sauté for about 10 minutes until everything is fragrant and soft.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are using garlic add it here and let it sweat for a minute&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add in your minced meat and break it up into small clumps about the size of a rice grain with a spoon, keep stiring until all your meat is lightly cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once all your meat is cooked and looks a bit grey add your wine, add enough to fully deglaze the pan (I usually add a little bit extra for the flavor)
stir it through until it has completely evaporated. (If you are using it you can also add the stock at this point)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once your pan is somewhat dry you can add the tomato paste to the beef, let it cook for a minute to remove the slight metallic taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add your canned and peeled tomatoes and use your spoon to break them up, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be too thorough since they will soften up while the sauce cooks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add the diced tomatoes, fill the jar your tomatoes came in with water give it a shake and add that to the pot, do the same with your can of peeled tomatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lower your heat to the lowest setting and slightly cover the pan with your lid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>let it simmer for as long as you can wait, preferably at least 4 hours, if it starts getting a bit too dry you can add a bit more water to make sure the sauce doesn&amp;rsquo;t burn.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once it&amp;rsquo;s done simmering for as long as you can muster and its nice and thick, the liquid should not come above your meat and should be pretty concentrated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can add your glass of milk, let it simmer for 10 more minutes and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 3 mins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flour (Wheat flour recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir and turn on maximum heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep stirring until it becomes thick.
If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the sauce with the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pasta Alla Norma</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid><description>&lt;p>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 aubergines (900g)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100ml olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon dried oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon caster sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fresh basil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use a peeler to shave off alternating strips on your aubergines, so they looked striped, like zebras.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then cut the aubergine widthways into 1cm thick slices. Place into a bowl with 75ml of olive oil, a good pinch of salt and black pepper. Coat the aubergines, then spread them onto two or three baking paper-lined trays. Roast for 30-35 minutes until dark brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whilst the aubergines are cooking, put two tablespoons of olive oil into a frying pan or pot on a medium-high heat. Add garlic and chilies and fry for 1 minute (don&amp;rsquo;t burn them!). Add tinned tomatoes, oregano, sugar and a pinch of salt and pepper to the pot. Reduce heat to medium low and cook until the sauce has thickened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Cook the pasta&lt;/a> according to packet instructions, once al dente, drain and retain some of the pasta water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once cooked, add the aubergine to the pasta sauce and mix well. Then add the spaghetti to the aubergine and sauce mixture, making sure everything is evenly coated. Add some of the pasta water if required to loosen the sauce, then top with fresh basil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check for seasoning, then serve immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Baba's Feta Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Greek Pasta Recipe with sauce made out of feta, stock, cream cheese and other ingredients.
Uses mixed spice for special flavour, and is a great dinner or mid-day meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15-30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Serves Around 3 People. You can scale up to 4 If you increase most quantities by +1/4.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Medium Sweet Onion (Finely Chopped)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Virgin olive oil (not extra-virgin)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>White Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Fresh Medium Garlic Cloves (Chopped Fine)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>15-20 Kalamon/Kalamata Olives (Cut into thirds)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whole small courgette (Cut to small pieces)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 Medium Mushrooms (Cut smallish and small stalk)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Broccli (Chopped small)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8-10 Finely sliced cherry tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Block of feta (Washed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Chicken stock (Added to 3/4 Mug boiling water)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overfilled Teaspoon Mixed Spice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 Bowls fusilli pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overfilled tablespoon Creme Cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 Mug whole milk&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Make sure to prepare &amp;amp; chop most ingredients before you start.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baked Mostaccioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/baked-mostaccioli-00.webp" alt="baked mostaccioli in bowl" title="Baked Mostaccioli in Bowl">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pasta baked in dish with spicy sauce&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 8 bowls&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>24 oz or 1 jar of Fradiavolo Sauce (&lt;a href="https://victoriapastasauces.com/product/fradiavolo-sauce/">Victoria&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 box Mostaccioli Rigati or Penne Rigati (&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=mostaccioli+rigati&amp;amp;tbm=shop">Ronzoni&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~8 oz shredded Mozzarella Cheese (&lt;a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/Polly-O-Mozzarella-Cheese-Chunk-with-Whole-Milk-16-oz-Pack/10448265">Poly-O&lt;/a>)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;ve found that pre-shredded cheese doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good as shredding it right before cooking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2x 2 quart (8&amp;quot;) baking dishes or 1 large baking dish (see picture below)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring a pot to a boil and &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">cook pasta&lt;/a> for 6 minutes (very al dente).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put pasta and sauce in baking dish(es) and mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover pasta and sauce generously with grated cheese until you can&amp;rsquo;t see the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake at 350°F / 175°C for 20 minutes
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Or 375°F / 190°C for 15 minutes on convection bake.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/baked-mostaccioli-01.webp" alt="baked mostaccioli on stove" title="Baked Mostaccioli right out of the Oven">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 1 hr&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g Cheddar Cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 Rashers of bacon (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Grate the cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">cooking the pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start melting the butter in another saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides. The quantity of flour required may vary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now start adding the milk slowly, while mixing, as to avoid lumps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat on low heat while stirring until the sauce becomes thick. If unsure, taste the sauce, and if you cannot taste the flour, it is ready for the next step.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 80% of the cheese and stir until melted in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the pasta and add to baking dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the sauce and mix in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If using bacon, fry it up and mix into the dish, making sure to include any fat that comes out of the bacon for extra flavour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the rest of the cheese to cover the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake at gas mark 6 for about 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Lasagna</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/lasagna.webp" alt="lasagna">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nice recipe for amazing fully home-made lasagna.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 45 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Parmesan cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emental cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dry mozzarella cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/bolognese-sauce">Fresh Bolognese sauce&lt;/a> or about 1 litre worth of store-bought sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/classic-bechamel-sauce">Béchamel sauce&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/ricotta-lasagna-filling">ricotta lasagna filling&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lasagna pasta sheets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare the bolognese or jared pasta sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the sauce is almost done cooking prepare your béchamel or ricotta filling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want you can add 3-4 handfuls of grated emental cheese to the béchamel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If necessary, boil the lasagna noodles following the instructions on the packaging, start preheating your oven to 175°C/350°F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread a thin layer of pasta sauce on the bottom of a large, deep baking tray.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover with lasagna sheets and spread a layer of béchamel sauce or ricotta, cover with lasagna sheets and spread a layer of pasta sauce if you want you can finely grate a little bit of parmesan on each layer of bolognese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rinse and repeat the previous step until the tray is nearly full or you are running low on béchamel sauce/ricotta filling, take care that the last layer should be bechamel or ricotta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate some parmesan on top of your final layer and cover with Dry mozzarella cheese, wrap the top in aluminum foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the tray in the centre of your pre-heated oven and let it cook for 30-35 minutes, after that remove the foil to let the top brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once it is done cooking take it out of the oven and cover again with aluminum foil, let it rest for 10 minutes before serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spaghetti aglio e olio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aglio e olio, pasta with garlic and olive oil, is one of the simplest yet greatest pasta dishes of all time. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, easy, and uses a lot of basic pantry ingredients which makes this a convenient weeknight meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 pound (500g) spaghetti (or similarly shaped pasta)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup (110g) extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5-6 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp red pepper flakes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A bunch of fresh parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat a large skillet on medium-high heat, start &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">cooking the pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finely slice or mince the garlic and finely chop the parsley.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the oil and garlic to the skillet and gently cook it until it&amp;rsquo;s lightly golden brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the red pepper flakes to the skillet and turn down the heat to let its flavor infuse the oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the pasta has finished cooking, drain it, and reserve at least around a cup of the cooking water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now add the drained pasta with some of the cooking water to the skillet and toss vigorously. The starch in the pasta water will help the sauce emulsify and get it to the right consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At the very last second add the parsley, to preserve its freshness. Adjust the seasoning to taste if necessary.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</guid><description>&lt;p>author: postbellum
Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &amp;ldquo;Gaeta&amp;rdquo; olives, and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️Prep time: ~18 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pot of water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>320g italian spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10g salted capers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25g anchovies in oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>800g peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bunch of parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g Gaeta olives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 chopped chillies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A pinch of salt&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Wash capers from salt, then cut them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pit and crush Gaeta olives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wash and chop the bunch of parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">cooking the pasta&lt;/a> until al dente.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the oil, the peeled garlic cloves and the chopped dry chilli peppers into a large pan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the anchovy fillets and capers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brown over medium heat for 5 minutes, stirring often, so the anchovies will melt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now add peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo;; mix it with a spoon and cook for another 10 minutes over medium heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the sauce is ready, remove the garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add crushed olives and chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain spaghetti directly in the pan and sauté it for half a minute&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The dish is ready&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/cinque-pi.webp" alt="Cinque Pi">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tomato paste 2 TS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parmigiano (grated)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Start cooking the &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the cream with the tomato paste and bring to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn the heat down to medium and add as much grated parmigiano as you like.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it cook on medium to low heat until the pasta is done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chopped parsley and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can either add the sauce to the pasta or serve separately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with some additional parmigiano and a leaf of parsley.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Dominican Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 box Spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Onion minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Green Pepper minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic cloves minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Chicken Bouillon Cube or Adobo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp sazón&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Tomato Paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Tomato Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup Evaporated Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp Green Olives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Starchy Pasta Water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">spaghetti&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a separate pan, Sauté onions, peppers, and garlic until soft.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add seasonings and black pepper to taste. Mix until well combined.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tomato paste, sauce, and the pasta water. Mix and let it come to a simmer. Simmer for 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add evaporated milk, butter, sugar, and olives.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Taste for seasoning and heat to desired temperature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add spaghetti and toss into the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni.webp" alt="Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a based, easy and relatively quick to make meal. Great for making in large batches with a big pot and eating throughout the week.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 1 hour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6+&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/4 lb. Pork Sausage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lb. Med ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 3/4 Cups Elbow macaroni&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Can of tomato sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Diced half onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Diced half bell pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oregano leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marjoram&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rosemary leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Large grated garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot sauce (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mozzarella Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better than Bulion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 3/4 cups of Macaroni Elbows&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Season the meat with the paprika, sage, thyme, marjoram, rosmary leaves, oregano leaves, and black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute the onion and the bell pepper until they become soft.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook stirring for about 7-8 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drop ground beef and pork into the cooked vegetables on low-medium heat, breaking the lumps into smaller pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for about 15 minutes at medium heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tomato sauce to the pot and stir&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the Better than Bouillon to the pot and stir&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a 1/2 cup of water to the large pot and cook and stir until the water has evaporated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust the stove to lowest heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the macaroni according to &lt;a href="pasta.html">this pasta recipe&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Important&lt;/em> Stir everything together, make sure the hamburger gets evenly distributed in the macaroni. Make sure to stir right to the bottom so the sauce can reach there too.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Quick Breakfast Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</guid><description>&lt;p>A quick breakfast spaghetti recipe that covers a healthy amount of carbs, fat, and spices. Eggs
and/or bacon can be added to cover some protein, you should cook those while the boiler is cooking
the spaghetti for time efficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spaghetti (any kind you prefer)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ground spices (I like to use cumin, turmeric, paprika, and garlic)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tomato Paste/Sauce (preferably one with basil and without preservative)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra Virgin Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil some water fully and prepare a pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the water is boiling, add all your spices in the pot with the spaghetti on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the boiled water on the spaghetti to make it soft so you can immerse it fully in the water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix thoroughly the water with the spices and salt and pepper if needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the pot on the stove, keep it boiling, and stir every minute or two for 8 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It should take no more than 8 minutes, but you can check if it is fully cooked by tasting one piece at a time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once it is fully cooked, strain the water from the pot and keep the spaghetti in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before placing it back on the stove, add and mix a generous amount of olive oil. Now&amp;rsquo;s the time to add bacon or turkey if you are also using that.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While stirring the spaghetti, add your tomato sauce or paste and keep mixing for a minute and avoid letting it stick to the boiler.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the spaghetti out in your favorite bowl and enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-sauce">For the sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>½ chopped sweet yellow onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cloves chopped garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup finely chopped carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup chopped fresh basil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp. tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup red wine (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-meatballs">For the meatballs&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lb. ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ lb. fresh bulk Italian style pork sausage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp. finely chopped basil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp. finely chopped Italian parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup finely chopped cremini brown mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 large eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¾ cup unseasoned breadcrumbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red wine (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-pasta">For the pasta&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 ½ lb. dry spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="prepare-the-sauce">Prepare the sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat olive oil in a 4 to 5 quart pot on medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add onions and cook for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garlic and cook for 30 seconds longer or until fragrant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the carrots and mushrooms, and cook for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tomato paste, stir to blend, and cook for a minute longer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the canned tomatoes, basil, and parsley.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mash and stir the tomatoes with a potato masher until the sauce starts to thicken, about 5 minutes over medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to low and simmer gently while preparing meatballs, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="form-the-meatballs">Form the meatballs&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol start="9">
&lt;li>In a large bowl, mix by hand the beef, Italian sausage, basil, parsley, mushrooms, eggs, breadcrumbs, cheese, and 2 tablespoons of salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Do not overmix or the meatballs will be tough.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>Use small melon baller (or teaspoon) to form 1-inch round meatballs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll and compress into tight balls.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="cook-the-meatballs">Cook the meatballs&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol start="12">
&lt;li>In a separate wide, shallow pan, heat olive oil on medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brown meatballs on all sides for about 2-3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Depending on the pan size, you may need to brown two batches of the meatballs. Cook them in a single layer; do not crowd the pan by stacking them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do not overcook the meatballs; they will continue to cook in the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="14">
&lt;li>Towards the end of browning the meatballs, add a little bit of red wine to deglaze the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="finish-and-simmer-the-sauce">Finish and simmer the sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol start="15">
&lt;li>Add the cheese and red wine to the sauce and stir it in. Add 1 teaspoon of salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add meatballs and gently stir. Simmer the sauce and meatballs for 30-45 minutes while cooking the spaghetti, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="cook-the-spaghetti">Cook the spaghetti&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol start="17">
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Cook the pasta&lt;/a> and optionally add 1/3 cup of pasta water to the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="serve">Serve&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol start="18">
&lt;li>Place a thin layer of sauce on a plate. Add pasta, sauce and meatballs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/chicken-pasta-casserole.webp" alt="Chicken Pasta Casserole">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4-6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16oz (450g) diced tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some oil and butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 400F/200C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice chicken and pan cook with oil until fully cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Cook the pasta&lt;/a> for a few minutes less than usual (about 7-8 minutes).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add chicken and pasta into a casserole dish. Mix together. Add diced tomato and shredded mozzarella cheese and keep mixing. Top with parmesan cheese and bread crumbs for an even coat. Add about a spoonful of butter evenly on the top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook in the oven for 22-25 minutes, until the top looks golden.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pasta Navy Style</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pasta-navy-style.webp" alt="Pasta Navy Style">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is one of the three pasta dishes that I usually cook. It&amp;rsquo;s a Russian pasta
recipe that is fast and easy to make and is quite tasty.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here are the ingredients for about two hearty adult portions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>250g pasta. Usually I prefer to use fusilli or penne, but any short-cut pasta
should do.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300-400g ground beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3-4 tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 carrot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add olive oil to your frying pan, heat it to medium-high heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop some onions and add them to the preheated pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After a couple of minutes add the ground beef to the pan, salt it and mix it
a bit with the onions in the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the meat is almost done, mince the garlic and add it together with the
cumin and paprika to the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Cook the pasta&lt;/a> in a pot until its done al dente while the beef is being
cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate the tomatoes over the pan using a grater with small-sized slots, in
such a way that the tomato paste and juice falls right away from the grater
to the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate the carrot using a grater with medium-sized slots and add it to the
pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt some more to taste, and add some black pepper to taste, mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook it over medium/medium-low heat for about 10-15 minutes or until the
water and juices from the tomatoes have almost completely evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once (or if) the pasta and beef is already cooked, add the pasta to the pan
and cook for another couple of minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve hot and enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Originally published at &lt;a href="https://www.yaroslavps.com/food/navy-style-pasta/">https://www.yaroslavps.com/food/navy-style-pasta/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tortellini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cooking cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring water to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt to water only after boiling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tortellini in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in and let eggs cook using heat from the pot and tortellini.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve on a plate. Add pepper, more salt if needed, and optionally, shredded cheese on top for extra creaminess.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/aelplermagronen.webp" alt="Älplermagronen">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A swiss favorite, &lt;em>Älplermagronen&lt;/em> combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet.
It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 onions (medium size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese. Appenzeller works best. Gruyère would be my go-to alternative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a jar of apple sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Feel free to vary these amounts, it&amp;rsquo;s not like this is anything strict.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/cacio-e-pepe.webp" alt="pepe">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spaghetti&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino Romano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package
according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it. See &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">Pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile place the peppercorns on a cutting board and mash them with a pestle.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place half of the peppercorns in a pan and toast them at medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the pasta, place it in the pan and save the boiling water for later use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the pasta with the pepper with 2 spoons of the water previously saved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare the Pecorino by putting half of it a bowl with a spoon of the pasta water you saved; continue mixing the cheese with the water until a cream is formed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the pasta is almost cooked, add the cream and mix (you can add more water if the pasta is too dry).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve on a plate with the Pecorino left before on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/carbonara.webp" alt="carbonara">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it.
I recommend using the best ingredients you can source.
Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This recipe assumes medium eggs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks. Add a generous amount of your preferred grated cheese (Pecorino or Parmigiano) around 35g (you can optionally add a dash of black pepper).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill a pot with water and salt it less than typical &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">pasta&lt;/a> water. When it boils, cook the pasta one minute less than advised.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the preferred pork (Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta) in an iron or nonstick pan (if using a different kind of pan add a dash of extra virgin olive oil) on low to medium heat until the sides are crisp but the insides are chewy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While everything is being cooked and fried, beat the eggs manually using a fork until everything is entirely liquid. Remember to watch the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When your pasta is done (-1 minute), drain it and put it in the bowl with eggs. At this step you may consider the timing: if the pasta is too hot you will cook the eggs, and some people don&amp;rsquo;t like it this way, so just wait for a minute. Keep moving and stirring to fully incorporate the eggs. Add guanciale and as many fats remaining in the pan as you want. Keep moving and stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Plate and optionally garnish with the preferred grated cheese and black pepper. Voila.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 pound tubular dried pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 pound sweet Italian sausage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 onion, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 carrot, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 celery stalk, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoon of tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup fresh parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 sprig of fresh thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 sprig of fresh rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grated Parmesan cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat.
Add enough olive oil to gently fry the crumbles.
Cook about five minutes until opaque, not browned.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add minced onion, carrot, and celery, and parsley to the pan.
Stir often and add more olive oil if pan is dry.
Cook 30 minutes on very low heat until vegetables are caramelized and sausage is browned.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add canned tomatoes and their juice.
Break up tomatoes in the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a simmer then add thyme and rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continue simmer uncovered for 20 minutes, until thickened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix tomato paste with 1 cup of hot water.
Reduce heat to very low and add mix to the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook about 10 minutes until the sauce is dark red and glistens with oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove herb sprigs and add pepper to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, boil large pot of salted water then cook and drain the &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta">pasta&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve ragù over plate of pasta and top with grated parmesan cheese;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta.
TL;DR: you boil it.
Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pasta-sauce">pasta sauce&lt;/a> or used in another dish.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>pasta&lt;/li>
&lt;li>basil (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring water to a rolling boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now add pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep it boiling, but decrease heat as it tries to overflow.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until pasta is at the preferred softness (see below), then strain it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the pasta is sitting in your strainer, you may add basil leaves or other herbs and aromatics. I also recommend taking a knob or so of room temperature butter and add it in and stirring it, melting it into the pasta.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-long-should-pasta-be-cooked">How long should pasta be cooked?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The often recommended way to cook most pasta is &lt;em>al dente&lt;/em>, which often means &amp;ldquo;slightly undercooked,&amp;rdquo; or with a subtle firmness that makes it still substantial.
Cooking pasta more than that is no great crime,
but if you keep it in there for &lt;em>too&lt;/em> long, it&amp;rsquo;ll become mush.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>