<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mexican on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/mexican/</link><description>Recent content in mexican on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/mexican/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mexican Meat Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 lb Lean Ground Beef 1 cup Black Beans (canned), rinsed and drained 1 cup Salsa, divided 1/2 cup Corn (frozen) 1/2 cup Bread Crumbs Cooking Spray Directions In bowl, place all ingredients except spray and using 3/4 cup of the salsa - mix well. Spray a loaf pan (approx. 5&amp;quot;x9&amp;quot;), and add above mix. Bake for 50 to 60 minutes - sit 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Frijol con puerco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 ~ 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 kg of black beans, rinsed and drained. 2 kg of pork loin or ribs cut into 5 cm pieces, it can be mixture of the two. 1 white onion without skin cut, in half. 4 branches of fresh epazote, or 15 branches of coriander tied with kitchen twine. 8 to 10 radishes, julienned or striped.</description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 14 Ingredients 1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes 1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes 1 green onion 1 red onion 1 jalapeño pepper 1 handfull fresh cilantro 1 clove garlic 1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional) 1 chili pepper (optional) 1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional) Directions Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.</description></item><item><title>Dianne's Southwestern Cornbread Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</guid><description>Dianne&amp;rsquo;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad is as colorful as it is delicious.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 🥶 Chill: 2 hrs Ingredients 1 (6-ounce) package Mexican cornbread mix 1 (1-ounce) envelope buttermilk Ranch salad dressing mix 1 small head romaine lettuce, shredded 2 large tomatoes, chopped 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (8-ounce) package shredded Mexican four-cheese blend 6 bacon slices, cooked and crumbled 5 green onions, chopped Directions Prepare cornbread according to package directions, cool, and crumble.</description></item><item><title>Corn Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 Minutes 🍳 Cook time: 1 Hour+ in fridge Ingredients 2 pounds frozen corn, defrosted 1/2 Red onion, finely chopped 4 Radishes, sliced thin and chopped Few pinches of Cilantro, finely chopped 1-2 Jalepenos, finely chopped (optional) Juice of 2-3 Limes Salt and pepper, to taste Directions Chop everything to pieces smaller than the corn kernels. Mix well and let sit covered in the fridge for at least an hour, even better overnight.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Pork Carnitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</guid><description>This recipe makes a lot and is super easy. A whole roast usually makes enough for a few meals (depending on how many people will be eating it). Leftovers can be refrigerated for 4-5 days.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hr 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-11 Ingredients 2 ½ lbs. boneless pork shoulder 6 cloves of garlic, cut into slivers 1 ½ teaspoons cumin ½ teaspoon sazon ¼ teaspoon dry oregano ¾ cup low sodium chicken broth 2-3 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce 2 bay leaves ¼ teaspoon dry adobo seasoning Directions Season pork with kosher salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Chicharrones</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicharrones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicharrones/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork Butt with fat Adobo Goya all purpose Cumin Goya Naranja juice Corn oil (preferred) Directions Cut pork butt to around bite sized pieces with fat attached for frying and flavor. Add Adobo Goya and spread evenly throughout the pork Add Black pepper 1 ml Add Cumin 1 ml Add Salt 5 ml Add Goya Naranja 15 ml Rub all of it to spread the spices along the meat Have a colander to put the Chicharonnes in after having fried it and have another pot on the bottom that has some paper inside for oil Put it in deep dish skillet around Medium (3-4) heat cover with lid for around 30-35 mins till you see it&amp;rsquo;s cooked, turning to make sure everything is cooking evenly After it dries up at around 30-35 mins put the temperature to High (6-7) without the lid Put some oil to make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stick too much Use spoon to spin/stir and fry until a golden brown Take out the Chicharonnes and put into the colander.</description></item><item><title>Chimichanga</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</guid><description>Essentially, just a fried burrito. Use whatever your favorite filling is.
⏲️ Prep time: 120min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Servings: 4 Ingredients taco-meat 1 Onion Diced Tomatoes 1 Bell Pepper Burrito sized tortilla Plain Greek Yogurt or Sour Cream Any other vegetables you want Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers, tomatoes, and onions and saute Add in meat. Season and cook until browned or fully cooked through Warm your tortilla and place small layer of yogurt, cheese, and filling on the bottom half of the tortilla Wrap by folding bottom over filling, folding sides in, and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Salsa Verde</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa-verde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa-verde/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound (450g) tomatillos, husks removed 1 clove garlic 2 jalapeño or serrano chilies 1/2 cup (26g) chopped onion 3 Tbsp (40ml) oil cilantro Directions Place tomatillos, garlic, and chilies in a medium saucepan and cover with water. Simmer until tomatillos turn pale green, about 10 minutes. Transfer tomatillos, garlic, and chilies into a blender or food processor. Add the onion and cilantro. Puree until smooth, then salt to taste, usually a teaspoon (6g) will suffice.</description></item><item><title>Fajita Seasoning</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</guid><description>Simple seasoning mix similar to Old El Paso. Can be used for any Mexican dishes or plain meats.
Ingredients 1/2 tsp Garlic Powder 1/2 tsp Onion Powder 1/2 tsp Paprika 1/2 tsp Smoked Paprika 1/2 tsp Ground Cumin 1/2 tsp Ground Coriander 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Salt 1 tsp Brown Sugar 1.5 tsp Chili Powder Directions Mix seasonings in a bowl. Adjust amounts depending on how much is needed.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Thinly minced and non-lean mince is preferred. Spices shall be left to the choice of the cook, if at all desired. Mince should be broken up well before cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1-2 hours Ingredients Chorizo pork sausage Pork mince Bacon strips Tomato sauce Chilis Kidney beans Olive oil Wine Butter (spices) Directions As pan heats: Slice chilies and chorizo as desired Olive oil in pan heat on high Pork mince in.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:
2 Hass avocados 1/4 medium onion 1 small tomato Cilantro 1 lime And of course, some totopos to eat with.
Directions Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl. Mash the avocados, add lime juice, mix and mash some more.</description></item><item><title>Quesadilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</guid><description>A quick and easy low-prep meal, able to be taken anywhere.
⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time 🍽️ Serves: 1 Ingredients 1-2 tortillas. Any brand works, but you can decide if you want the tortilla folded in half, or 2 tortillas together. ~4 small pinches of (Mozzarella, Oaxaca, or Montery Jack cheese). Most cheeses are fine, but the taste of oaxaca cheese is more authentic. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have pre-grated cheese, you can cut thin slices off of the block of cheese.</description></item><item><title>Refried Beans</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</guid><description>One of my favorite dishes that works either as an appetizer or side dish is refried beans. A classic from Mexican cuisine, that is best eaten with some totopos, or tortilla chips.
Ingredients As usual, the ingredients here are for about two adult portions:
400-500g can of pre-cooked beans 1/4 onion 3-4 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika 2-4 spoonfuls butter Cooking oil (can be olive oil) Directions Add the oil and the butter to the frying pan and heat to medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Taco Meat</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound (about 500 g) ground beef or turkey 1 medium onion, finely chopped (or 1 1/2 teaspoon onion powder) 1 medium tomato, chopped (or 1 small can of tomato sauce) 1 teaspoon chili powder (or 1/3 teaspoon each oregano, cumin, garlic powder) 1 teaspoon oregano (ground or leaf) 1/4 teaspoon cumin dash of pepper (1/8 teaspoon or less) Directions Brown beef and onion together. Drain grease. Add the rest of the ingredients to the browned meat.</description></item><item><title>Chili Con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients Canned Whole Peeled Tomatoes Red Peppers White Onions Chili Pepper Garlic Ground Beef Kidney Beans Dark Chocolate Chili Powder Tomato Paste Beef Stock (optional) Neutral Oil Cilantro Sugar seasoning cumin paprika chili flakes Directions Brown the beef by adding it to a pot with neutral oil. Start breaking it into small pieces. Allow water to leave the meat. Salt it to expel more water. Once water is gone, the sound will change and it will start to fry.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Chicken Tacos</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients chicken breasts two or three onions (preferably red) seasoning: adobo seasoning paprika cheese (either shredded Mexican blend or crumbling cheese) small tortillas lime cilantro, tomato, lettuce, other desired taco contents Directions Quarter two onions and spread on the bottom of a slow-cooker. Place chicken breasts on top of onions. Season slow-cooker contents liberally with adobo seasoning, paprika and any other desired seasonings, squeeze half of a lime too if desired.</description></item></channel></rss>