<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swiss on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/swiss/</link><description>Recent content in Swiss on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/swiss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zurich-Style Meat Saute</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally called &amp;ldquo;Züri Gschnätzlets&amp;rdquo; (Zurich chopped) from the city of Zurich
in Switzerland, this is a tasty and practical recipe from simple ingredients.
You can use any kind of meat really, depending on your taste. Very
traditionally, finely sliced liver and kidney is also mixed in with the meat
and mushrooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>600g	Beef, finely sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250g	Mushrooms, finely sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1	Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml	White whine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200ml Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fry the meat in butter at high heat until it starts loosing liquid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take the meat out of the pan and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute the onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mushrooms, saute, then add a tbsp of flour and mix well. The flour
will make the sauce thicker, so use carfully.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the white wine and let it boil for a few minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add cream, boil until the sauce is very creamy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the meat, boil until the meat is warm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add parsley, and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Serve with &lt;a href="./roesti.md">Rösti&lt;/a> or other traditional Swiss dish.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fondue</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</guid><description>&lt;p>A swiss classic for cold winter dinners.
Traditionally cooked in a &amp;ldquo;Caquelon&amp;rdquo; pot and served on a candle heated stove, to keep the cheese from going solid again.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 garlic clove&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 dl (1.5 cups) white wine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>800 g (1.7 lbs) swiss cheese (50/50 mix of Gruyère and Emmentaler recommended)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 shot of kirsch (cherry brandy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp lemon juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2 tbsp starch flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 loaf (~800g/~1.7 lbs) of white bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A pinch of nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Rub the Pot with garlic clove.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut bread into small squares.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put cheese, starch, wine and lemon juice in pot and melt while stiring constantly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Season with a bit of pepper and nutmeg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve right away.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stick bread squares on fondue fork one by one and stir them in the fondue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings:1-4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>for 1 liter of Glühwein&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50 g Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25 g Raisins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 orange&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cinamon bark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 star anise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>throw everything in a pot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Zopf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (plus one hour rising)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1kg white wheat flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½L milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>125g butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>14g dry yeast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1½T salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut or tear up butter and put in skillet with milk on low heat (This is so the ingredients are not too clod, temperature should not exceed 31 C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the flour in a large bow with the yeast, salt, milk and butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix and kneed for at least 15 minutes making sure to stretch the dough a lot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the dough rest in a warm spot for at least one hour (temperature should not be higher than 31 C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start heating an oven at 200 C (no need to preheat, it will be a good temperature once you are done braiding)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the dough in two or three sections (different according to region), then stretch and roll into long pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Braid the strips, place on a parchment lined baking sheet and brush down with a beaten egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 30 minutes testing with a wooden skewer in the widest part when done. IF the skewer comes out clean, you are done, if not add 5 minutes and repeat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the bread to cool before cutting.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Rösti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/roesti.webp" alt="Rösti">
Used two serving sizes for this Rösti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This swiss classic works great together with fried eggs and steamed peas or spinach.
Can be useful to get rid of leftover potatoes from the day before.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~800g (~1.5lb) potatoes (firm/waxy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g (~1lb) peas or spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions (medium size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Shred raw or cooked (but cool) potatoes with a grater. The shreds should be
quite large so don&amp;rsquo;t use your typical cheese shredder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice the first onion and mix together with potatoes. You can also add diced
bacon if you want to. Add your seasonings here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up some butter in a large pan. Add your mix to the pan on high heat.
Let the mixture get warm for a few minutes under constant stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to medium-high. Form the Rösti into a round cack. It should fill
out the whole pan. I recommend a thickness of around 1 - 1.5cm (~1/2&amp;quot;) for a
softer Rösti.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add some more butter flakes around the inside of the pan to get it under the
Rösti.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It can take quite a while for a nice crust to form. Check after roughly 5-10
minutes for browning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the Rösti is cooking dice the other onion and the carrots. Steam
everything in a pan with a bit of water. Use a lid to get the temperature
up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alternatively you can use fresh or creamed spinach.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied with the browning, flip the Rösti and set the heat to
medium-low. A plate can be useful here, put it on top of the Rösti in the
pan and flip. Then gently put the whole cake back in the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the Rösti crispness is to your liking, remove from pan and fry two
eggs. A runny yolk adds quite a bit to the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Top Rösti with eggs and serve with the peas or spinach.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/aelplermagronen.webp" alt="Älplermagronen">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A swiss favorite, &lt;em>Älplermagronen&lt;/em> combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet.
It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 onions (medium size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese. Appenzeller works best. Gruyère would be my go-to alternative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a jar of apple sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Feel free to vary these amounts, it&amp;rsquo;s not like this is anything strict.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>