<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rice on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/rice/</link><description>Recent content in Rice on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/rice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hakka-Style Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 lb Ground Beef&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Panko Breadcrumbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Soy Sauce, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tsp Chili Garlic Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 oz Ginger, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 medium Green Bell Peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Basmati Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 oz Green Peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Cilantro, loosely packed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Moroccan Spice Blend, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/4 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot. Cover and bring to a boil over a medium-high heat. Add rice and reduce heat to low. Cover and cook until rice is tender and liquid is absorbed (12-14 mins). Add peas halfway through cooking. When rice is done, remove pot from heat, and leave covered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While rice cooks, combine beef, panko, half the ginger, a quarter of the soy sauce and a third of the Moroccan spice blend. Roll mixture into 9 equal-sized meatballs. Arrange meatballs on a parchment-lined baking sheet. Bake on the middle rack in the oven until golden-brown and cooked through (8-10 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, core and cut the green peppers into 1/2&amp;quot; pieces and roughly chop cilantro. Stir together sweet chili sauce, remaining soy sauce, 1/4 cup water and chili garlic sauce in a small bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a large non-stick pan over medium-high heat. Add 1 Tbsp oil, then onion and peppers. Cook, stirring occasionally, until slightly softened (2-3 mins). Add remaining ginger and remaining Moroccan spice blend. Cook, stirring constantly, until fragrant (30 sec).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add meatballs and the stir-fry sauce to the pan with veggies. Cook, stirring gently, until sauce thickens slightly and coats meatballs (1 min). Season with salt and pepper, to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add half the cilantro to rice, then fluff with a fork. Divide rice between plates, then top with meatballs, veggies, and any sauce in the pan. Sprinkle remaining cilantro over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spicy Kung Pao-Style Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 Chicken Thighs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Basmati Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 small Sweet Peppers, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 ribs Celery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Ginger, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 whole Green Onions, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Chili Garlic Sauce, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Soy Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Peanuts, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat a medium pot over medium heat. Add 1/2 Tbsp oil, ginger and rice. Cook, stirring often, until fragrant (1 min). Add 1 1/4 cups water and bring to a boil over high heat. Reduce heat and cover until rice is tender and liquid is absorbed (12-14 mins). Remove the pot from heat, leave covered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While rice cooks, cut celery crosswise into 1/4&amp;quot; slices. Whisk together soy sauce, sweet chili sauce, 1/3 cup water, and half the chili garlic sauce in a medium bowl. Combine flour and 1/4 tsp each of salt and pepper in another medium bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a large non-stick pan over medium heat. Add peanuts to the dry pan. Toast, stirring often, until golden brown (4-5 mins). Transfer to a plate and heat the same pan over medium-high. Add 1/2 Tbsp oil, peppers, and celery. Cook, stirring often until fragrant (1 min). Transfer veggies to another plate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pat chicken dry and cut into 1&amp;quot; pieces. Add chicken to flour mixture, then toss to coat. Press flour mixture into chicken to coat completely. Heat the same non-stick pan over medium and add oil, then chicken. Cook, turning pieces occasionally, until golden brown and cooked through (6-8 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add veggies and sauce mixture to the pan with chicken. Cook, stirring occasionally, until sauce thickens slightly (2-3 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fluff rice with fork. Stir in half the green onions and season with salt. Divide rice between plates. Top with chicken, veggies, and sauce. Sprinkle peanuts and remaining green onions over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Beef and Broccoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 lb Beef, cut into strips&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Vegetable Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Ginger, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves Garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Carrots, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Snow Peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bean Sprouts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Broccoli Pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Beef Bouillon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Corn starch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Soy Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat oil, add beef and stir-fry until meat is browned and push to sides of pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add broccoli and carrots. Cover and steam vegetables until they are only slightly crunchy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove vegetables to a bowl. Add bouillon, salt and pepper to meat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine corn starch, 2 Tbsp water, and soy sauce. Add to meat to thicken sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add vegetables and heat. Serve over rice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Egyptian Lentils</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup Lentils&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Elbow Macaroni&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Fresh Chili or Bell Peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Lime Juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cup Regular Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 medium Tomatoes, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large Onion, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place lentils in a saucepan and cover by 1&amp;quot; or more of water. Turn heat to high and bring to a boil, then turn down heat to simmer, and cook covered for 35 minutes or until tender. Drain and transfer to a large bowl. Set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring 3 cups of water to a boil, add rice. Turn down to simmer for 20 minutes and fluff up rice with a fork and add to lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil 2 quarts of water, add elbow macaroni and cook until tender. Add to lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a small skillet add 1 Tbsp of oil and saute chopped peppers finely for two minutes. Add the tomato, 1/2 cup of water, bring to a boil and simmer for 5 minutes. Add the lime juice. Fold this sauce into the lentils.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In another skillet heat 2 Tbsp oil, add onions and saute until brown. Garnish lentil mixture with the browned onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Winter Risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Arborio Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Baby Spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic Cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 1/2 cup Vegetable Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Parmesan Cheese, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 lb Baby Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp White Wine Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Walnuts, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Leek, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Unsalted Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine vegetable broth in a medium pot. Cover and bring to a gentle boil over medium heat. While broth comes to a boil, peel and mince/grate the garlic. Roughly chop the spinach. Thinly slice mushrooms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a large non-stick pan over medium heat. When hot, add the butter, onions, leeks, and mushrooms. Season with salt. Cook, stirring occasionally, until softened (2-3 mins). Add rice, garlic, and vinegar. Cook, stirring constantly until fragrant (1-2 min).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 1 cup broth from the medium pot to the pan with rice. Stir until broth has been absorbed by rice. Continue adding broth 1 cup at a time, stirring regularly, until liquid is absorbed, the texture is creamy and the rice is tender (28-30 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While risotto cooks, add tomatoes and a tablespoon of oil to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Season with salt and pepper, then toss to coat. Roast on the middle rack of the oven until tomatoes start to burst (10-11 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the last cup of broth has been absorbed and rice is tender and creamy, add Parmesan and spinach to risotto. Stir until spinach wilts (3-4 mins). Stir in roasted tomatoes. Divide risotto between bowls. Sprinkle walnuts over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spinach-Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spinach-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spinach-rice-casserole/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 cups Brown Rice, cooked&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 lbs raw Spinach, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves Garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Eggs, beaten&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups Cheddar, grated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Parsley, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Tamari&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Salt (or more, to taste)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Sunflower Seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A few dashes each - Nutmeg; Cayenne; Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Saute onions and garlic with salt in butter. When onions are soft, add spinach. Cook 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine with all ingredients except sunflower seeds and paprika.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread into buttered casserole dish and sprinkle sunflower seeds and paprika on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake, covered, 35 minutes at 350F.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p>Very easy, high protein.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 chicken breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp minced garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube. Season with olive oil, black pepper, and
paprika. Cut broccoli into pieces and place into steamer basket over pot 1/2 filled with water, do
not start it yet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put chicken cubes into a hot pan and cook for ~3 minutes. After 3 minutes add honey, soy sauce,
and garlic. Cook for another 5 minutes. Begin boiling broccoli water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add frozen peas to rice and stir, they will heat up quickly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add rice and peas to chicken and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoon flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg yolk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>wash the rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put water in the pot and wait for water to boil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add some salt and rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>wait for 15 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add water from the soup and mix by warming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well&lt;/li>
&lt;li>serve warm&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Loaded Mexican Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</guid><description>&lt;p>A tex-mex style mexican rice with beans and meat. Adding the beans and meat take it from a side
dish to good good burrito filling. :x&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>5 serving&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Cup uncooked long grain white rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup frozen peas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup frozen corn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Caned adobo chilies chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Tbsp tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Can of black or pinto beans&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup ground meat (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Onion diced (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook rice per manufactures instructions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pore enough neutral oil in a large pan to cover the bottom entirely, and turn on to medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once pan is hot add rice, brake up the rice to ensue there are no clumps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add tomato paste and chilies to the pan, mix until rice is coated add water if needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain and add the beans, corn, and peas; if you are adding meat and or onion do so now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix well, ensue peas and corn thaw.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve hot as either a burrito or bowl with your choice of fillings/toppings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Mushroom risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20-30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 shallot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g button or crimini mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g risotto rice (Arborio, Carnaroli or Vialone Nano)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup white wine (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mushroom or chicken stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino or Parmesan cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Finely mince the shallot and garlic and slice the mushrooms into large pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a pan with some olive oil on medium-high heat. Ideally this should be a wide skillet with tall sides, but a pot will also do the job.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute the vegetables until fragrant, then add the mushrooms with a pinch of salt and cook them down until they&amp;rsquo;re nicely browned, about 10 minutes or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the rice in and let it toast for about a minute or so. This will develop some nice nutty flavors, but overdoing this will affect the creaminess of the finished dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with white wine and let the alcohol cook off. After that start ladling in the stock bit by bit stirring constantly for about 20-30 minutes (depending on the brand of rice used), until the rice is cooked but has a slight bite to it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and add a couple tablespoons of cold butter and grated cheese, and stir well to emulsify. Check for final seasoning and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pilaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Popular central asian and middle eastern dish.
High in nutrition, designed to be prepared and eaten communally.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>150ml cooking oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1kg long grain &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/rice">rice&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5kg meat (lamb or any other kind of meat)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>raisins, cardamom, paprika, coriander, cinnamon, cumin, turmeric (all optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put the cooking oil in a cauldron and heat it until the oil is boiling, add a head of onion until it is black, then throw it out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Throw coarsely chopped meat into the cauldron and let it boil until it&amp;rsquo;s golden brown, then add a pinch of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the chopped onions, then wait 2 minutes and add the sliced carrots, boil for another 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 500 ml of water diluted with tomato paste, boil for 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rinse the rice and put it into the cauldron but do not mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add another 500 ml of water diluted with tomato paste and wait until it is boiling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce the heat to minimum, then add two table spoons of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the cauldron and leave it on low heat for 1.5-2 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 hour before it is ready(or when you can&amp;rsquo;t see water above the rice), add the garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can now turn over the rice if it is undercooked and add some raisins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep boiling until all water is evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Arroz Chaufa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peruvian-chinese dish. Easy to cook just add and mix everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/arroz-chaufa-2.webp" alt="Arroz Chaufa">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bell Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chicken&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Welsh Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/arroz-chaufa-1.webp" alt="Ingredients">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the chicken into pieces and fry it. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook scrambled eggs. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the rice. If it is yesterday&amp;rsquo;s rice better, preferably without salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the welsh onion and bell pepper into small squares.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix everything over low heat, adding soy sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional: Add bacon, sesame oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If everything is salty, you can reduce it with just a teaspoon of sugar, especially if you cook the rice with salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>ShrimpÂ andÂ SausageÂ Gumbo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gumbo-shrimp-and-sausage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gumbo-shrimp-and-sausage/</guid><description>&lt;p>ThisÂ recipeÂ isÂ aÂ simplifiedÂ versionÂ ofÂ AB&amp;rsquo;sÂ SeafoodÂ GumboÂ &amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XuiKYWb7s5o">youtube&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸Â PrepÂ time:Â 15Â min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ CookÂ time:Â 130Â min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸Â Servings:Â 4-6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2-3Â lbsÂ Shrimp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2Â lbsÂ AndouilleÂ Sausage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2Â (32Â oz)Â ChickenÂ Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â cupÂ olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â cupÂ AllÂ PurposeÂ Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â cupÂ finelyÂ choppedÂ YellowÂ Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â cupÂ finelyÂ choppedÂ GreenÂ Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â cupÂ finelyÂ choppedÂ Celery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2Â tbspÂ mincedÂ Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â tbspÂ WorcestershireÂ Sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â tbspÂ CajunÂ orÂ CreoleÂ SeasoningÂ (CreoleÂ Kick)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â 12Â oz.Â bottleÂ ofÂ Beer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â tspÂ driedÂ Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Â tspÂ driedÂ Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3Â -Â 5Â BayÂ Leafs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2Â cupÂ GreenÂ Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1-2Â cupsÂ WhiteÂ Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional)Â 1Â JalapeÃ±oÂ Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional)Â InsteadÂ ofÂ chickenÂ broth,Â youÂ canÂ useÂ yourÂ ownÂ shrimpÂ stock&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>PrepÂ theÂ vegetables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get the roux started: Mix oil and flour over heat until it turns into a dark chocolate color. Low - medium heat for about 30 minutes or medium - high for 15 - 20 minutes if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling brave.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>EnsureÂ toÂ stirÂ frequentlyÂ whileÂ addingÂ theÂ followingÂ ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ onion.Â CookÂ forÂ 5Â minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ celeryÂ andÂ peppers.Â CookÂ forÂ 5Â minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ garlic.Â CookÂ forÂ 1Â minute.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ beer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ broth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ seasoningsÂ andÂ WorcestershireÂ Sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AddÂ sausageÂ andÂ bringÂ toÂ aÂ boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LowerÂ heat,Â cover,Â simmerÂ forÂ 90Â minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IncreaseÂ heatÂ toÂ medium.Â AddÂ shrimpÂ andÂ cookÂ forÂ 5-7Â minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TurnÂ offÂ theÂ heatÂ andÂ serveÂ overÂ whiteÂ rice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional)Â ForÂ leftovers,Â boilÂ gumboÂ withÂ dryÂ whiteÂ riceÂ andÂ turnÂ itÂ intoÂ aÂ jambalaya.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Stuffed Round Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/stuffed-round-squash-02.webp" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Round Squash, Zucchini, or Courguettes can be served as main dish (2 servings per person) or as accompaniment. The amount of squash should be adjusted according to their size. This recipe uses ones the size of a fist.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 50 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Carrot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Round squash&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cup of rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100gr of Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cook the rice. This usually takes 20 minutes. In the meantime, cut the onion into small cubes, grate the carrot, and cut the squash in halves. Scoop the squash halves, and cut the core in small cubes. Save them for later. &lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/stuffed-round-squash-00.webp" alt="">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain the rice and let it cool. On an oiled pan, mix the onion, carrot and squash core, and cook them for 10 minutes. You may now add seasoning. &lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/stuffed-round-squash-01.webp" alt="">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the squash halves facing down on a metal griddle in the oven. Add the rice to the vegetables, stir, and cook for 10 more minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip the squash, stuff them with cheese and the vegetables mixture, and put them again in the oven for 10 minutes at max heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rice is easy to make in any pot.
The simple use of different spices can change its use or what it accents.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/chicken-stock-bone-broth">chicken stock&lt;/a> (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>onion or garlic (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lime and cilantro (optional, for a Mexican taste)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add some amount of rice to a pot that has a cover.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add twice as much liquid to the same pot. Water is typical, but for extra flavor, use stock or broth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If desired, dice onion or garlic and mix into rice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover the pot, put it on the stove and turn the heat on the highest level.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As soon as you hear the water beginning to bubble and boil over, turn the heat down to low and allow it to simmer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for twenty minutes or so until the liquid has evaporated and the rice will be ready.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="for-mexican-rice">For Mexican rice&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For Mexican rice, you might want to avoid cooking in stock to avoid taste clashes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>