<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>salad on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/salad/</link><description>Recent content in salad on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/salad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</guid><description>Easy recipe to expand - black turtle beans and chickpeas also work well here.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1/3 cup Salad Oil (olive oil, canola, or sunflower) 1/2 cup Cider Vinegar 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Pepper 1/4 cup Sugar 1/2 tsp Celery Seed 1 can Cut Green Beans 1 can Cut Waxed Beans 1 can Red Kidney Beans 1 Carrot, thinly sliced 1 small Onion, chopped 1 Bell Pepper Directions Put dressing ingredients in a large salad bowl an whisk until blended.</description></item><item><title>Tabouleh</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 2 cups Cracked Wheat (bulghur) 2 cups Very Hot Water (or as directed) 1 Cucumber, chopped 2 small Tomatoes, chopped 1 bunch Green Onions, sliced 1/2 cup Mint (fresh), chopped 2 cup Parsley (fresh), chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 1/2 cup Lemon Juice (fresh) 3/4 cup Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Pepper 2 tsp Salt Directions Soak the cracked wheat in the hot water until the water is absorbed, about 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Perfect Potato Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 5 Potatoes, peeled and cut into bite-size chunks (about 2 lbs) 1 cup Plain Yogurt 1/2 cup Mayonnaise 1 Tbsp Prepared Horseradish 4 Radishes, thinly sliced 2 stalks Celery, diced 2 large Green Onions, thinly sliced 1/4 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped 1/4 cup Fresh Dill, chopped Directions Place potatoes in a pot and just cover with water.</description></item><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn 4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced 1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced 1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced 1 small Onion, sliced 1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped 3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 6 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar 1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp dill weed 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper 2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh Directions Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Coleslaw</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coleslaw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coleslaw/</guid><description>This is a coleslaw recipe that I got from a chili restaurant in my neighborhood that closed down a few years ago. This recipe makes more dressing than needed for the coleslaw, so you can save it or use it as a vegetable dip.
⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🥶 Fridge time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 8 - 10 Ingredients 3/4 cup mayonnaise 1/2 cup buttermilk 3 tbsp lemon juice 3 tbsp apple cider vinegar 4 tbsp distilled vinegar 1/3 cup olive oil 1/4 cup granulated sugar 1 1/2 tsp kosher salt 1 tsp ground black pepper 1 tsp celery seeds 1/2 tsp onion powder 1/4 tsp granulated garlic 1/4 tsp mustard powder One large head of green cabbage One large carrot Directions Finely shred, rinse, and drain the carrot Finely shred the cabbage (use a food processor if possible) Whisk together the mayonnaise, buttermilk, lemon juice, cider vinegar, distilled vinegar, olive oil, and sugar Add the salt, pepper, celery seeds, onion powder, and granulated garlic, and combine well Combine the shredded cabbage and carrot in a separate bowl Slowly add the dressing until it lightly coats the vegetables, and toss well.</description></item><item><title>Dianne's Southwestern Cornbread Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</guid><description>Dianne&amp;rsquo;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad is as colorful as it is delicious.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 🥶 Chill: 2 hrs Ingredients 1 (6-ounce) package Mexican cornbread mix 1 (1-ounce) envelope buttermilk Ranch salad dressing mix 1 small head romaine lettuce, shredded 2 large tomatoes, chopped 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (8-ounce) package shredded Mexican four-cheese blend 6 bacon slices, cooked and crumbled 5 green onions, chopped Directions Prepare cornbread according to package directions, cool, and crumble.</description></item><item><title>Crab salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</guid><description>
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Сrab meat (300 grams) Egg (3) Rice (50 grams) Corn (1 can) Cucumber (1) Carrot (1) Onion (1) Mayonnaise (100 grams) Directions Boil rice, eggs and carrot Chop crab meat and all other ingredients Combine and mix all ingredients Add mayonnaise Chill before serving</description></item><item><title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula Directions Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste. Simmer for 3 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Lemon juice salad dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</guid><description>A dressing that goes well on lettuce or any other mixed greens.
Ingredients Lemon juice from half a lemon Tablespoon of olive oil Clove of garlic Directions Combine lemon juice and oil in small bowl. Add salt and pepper to taste. Add the garlic, pressed or finely minced. Mix well before adding to salad.</description></item><item><title>Caesar Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid><description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing Directions Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons. Grate Parmesan over salad.</description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description></item></channel></rss>