<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>soup on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/soup/</link><description>Recent content in soup on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grilled Mackerel with Miso Soup and Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 Norwegian Mackerel Fillets 1 tbsp Sake 2 tbsp Miso paste 1/2 Onion 1 Summer Squash 1 tbsp butter 1 cup Jasmine Rice (optional) Soy Sauce (optional) Directions Place the mackerel fillets in a small container at room temperature. Pour sake on both sides of the fillets and let rest in the container, covered, for 30 min.</description></item><item><title>Ham and Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ham-and-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ham-and-lentil-soup/</guid><description>For more flavour, boil down a soup bone and use the broth when filling the crock pot.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 2 cup Lentils 1/2 lb Ham, diced 1 Onion, chopped 1 Bay leaf 2 ribs Celery, chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced Directions Combine all ingredients with 2 quarts water in the Crock Pot. Cook on low, covered, 8 to 10 hours.</description></item><item><title>Newfoundland Cod Chowder</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 4 Slices Bacon 2 Onions, sliced 1 tsp Savoury 6 Potatoes, peeled and cubed 3 Carrots, sliced 1 1/2 lbs Cod Fillets 1 can Evaporated Milk 2 Tbsp Fresh Parsley or Chives, chopped Directions In a large, heavy saucepan, cook bacon over medium-high heat for about 10 minutes or until crisp. Chop coarsely and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Turkish Red Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</guid><description>Serve with a squeeze of lemon and alongside turmeric flatbread.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 cup Red Lentils 5 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Paprika 1/2 Tbsp Red Paper Flakes 1 large Onion, finely diced 1 large Carrot, diced 4 tsp Tomato Paste 2 tsp Cumin 1/2 tsp Dried Mint 1/2 tsp Thyme or Oregano 4 cup Vegetable Broth 4 cup Water Directions Reserve half the paprika and red pepper flakes, set aside.</description></item><item><title>Autumn Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</guid><description>You can cook the veggies on the stove instead of baking them, just pay more attention to avoid burning. You can also use pumpkin instead of squash.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 Medium Squash 3 Potatoes 4 Carrots 1 Small Onion 1 Chicken Bullion Cube 1 cup Water 2 cups Milk Salt Pepper Directions Peel and chop squash, potatoes, carrots, and onion, add to oven-safe pot.</description></item><item><title>Gypsy Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</guid><description>The vegetables used in this soup are flexible. Any orange vegetable can be combined with green. Such as peas or green beans to replace peppers, or carrots and/or squash to replace the sweet potato.
⏲️ Prep time: 40 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 2 cup Chopped Onion 2 cloves Chopped Garlic 2 cup Sweet Potatoes, chopped and peeled 1/2 cup Chopped Celery 1 cup Chopped Fresh Tomatoes 3/4 cup Chopped Sweet Peppers 1-1/2 cup Cooked Chickpeas 3 cup Stock or Water 2 tsp Paprika 1 tsp Turmeric 1 tsp Basil 1 tsp Salt dash Cinnamon dash Cayenne 1 Bay Leaf 1 Tbsp Tamari Soy Sauce Directions In a soup kettle or large saucepan, saute onions garlic, celery, and sweet potatoes in olive oil for about five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 12 min 🍳 Cook time: 75 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 3 1/2 lbs Tomatoes 1 1/2 lbs Eggplant 1 lb Zucchini 3 Bell Peppers 2 lbs Onions 6 cloves Garlic Herbes de Provence (Basil, Thyme, Parsley) Olive Oil Salt Pepper 140g Tomato Paste (optional if tomatoes aren&amp;rsquo;t yummy) Directions Peel and drain the tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t mind the seeds): cut out the stem cores; drop the whole tomatoes into boiling water for 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.
Ingredients 2-3 medium potatoes 4 eggs 2 long or 4 short cucumbers 3 strands of spring onions 10-12 radishes bunch of dill 2 Kefir or 1 kvass 500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat 1 mineral water (optional) Directions Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled) Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat) Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.</description></item><item><title>Fennel White Bean and Kale Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup with lots of veggie and protein.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 bowls Ingredients ½ cup olive oil 2 small fennel bulbs, small-diced 2 small yellow onions, small-diced 4 teaspoons minced fresh rosemary or thyme 10 cloves of garlic, minced or pressed ½-1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes. 10-12 oz kale, (escarole, swiss chard, or spinach can also be used). 4 cans cannellini beans, rinsed 4 cups chicken broth.</description></item><item><title>Potato Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</guid><description>Serves many people or one person for many days.
Ingredients Potatoes (yellow or brown), I don&amp;rsquo;t count but 10+ Butter, a stick or two Whole Milk Garlic Cheese (optional) Onion Greens (optional) Sour Cream (optional) Directions Bake the potatoes at 450° for about an hour. Take them out and leave them to cool for a good 10 minutes. Begin heating up a big pot to about medium temperature, and put the butter in to melt.</description></item><item><title>Medieval Beef Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</guid><description>Medieval beef soup with turnips and turnip greens.
Ingredients One beef roast Around three to four large turnips with their greens attached Two cups of chicken stock 1/10 grams of Saffron 1/4 a stick of butter A slow cooker A bowl of warm water. Directions Cube the roast into bite sized pieces and place them in a large skillet with the butter. Heat the pan on medium-high heat and brown the meat with the melted butter until the outside is evenly cooked, sprinkle with pepper as it browns.</description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying Directions Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water. Allow to boil for 5 or so min.</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian Borscht</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</guid><description>Borscht is a beet soup that originates from Ukraine and is common in Eastern Europe and North Asia. Depending on the recipe, borscht may be purely vegetarian; it may be served either hot or cold; and it may range from a hearty one-pot meal to a clear broth or a smooth drink.
⏲️ Prep time: 25 mins 🍳 Cook time: 40 mins 🍽️ Servings: 10 Ingredients 3 red beetroots 4 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 8 cups chicken broth + 2 cups water 3 yukon potatoes 2 carrots 2 celery ribs 1 onion 4 Tbsp ketchup or 3 Tbsp tomato sauce 1 red bell pepper (optional) 1 can white cannelini beans with their juice (optional) 2 bay leaves (optional) 1 pressed garlic clove (optional) 1 cup sour cream (optional) fresh dill to taste (optional) Directions Peel, grate and/or slice all vegetables (keeping sliced potatoes in cold water to prevent browning until ready to use then drain).</description></item><item><title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</guid><description>author: skipper-davies Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 3 cups red lentils 12 cups water 1 large red onion, diced 2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced 1 medium zucchini, diced 4 cups Swiss chard, chopped 1 bunch of cilantro, chopped ¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste 1 teaspoon cumin Directions In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.</description></item><item><title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients yogurt 1/3 cup rice 2 tablespoon flour 1 egg yolk butter Directions wash the rice put water in the pot and wait for water to boil add some salt and rice wait for 15 minutes mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl add water from the soup and mix by warming when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well serve warm</description></item><item><title>Erwtensoep (Dutch pea soup)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</guid><description>Erwtensoep, also called snert, is the Dutch version of pea soup. Slices of rookworst (smoked sausage) are added before serving. The soup, which is traditionally eaten during the winter, is emblematic of Dutch cuisine. It is customarily served with Frisian rye bread (roggebrood) and bacon, cheese or butter. Pancakes are sometimes served with pea soup; this dish is called snert met struif, struif referring to the pancakes.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 7 1/2 cups / 1.</description></item><item><title>French Onion Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 6-7 Onions, cut into quarter moons 1 stick of butter 1/2 cup Olive oil Salt, to taste 1 Baguette Loaf, sliced 1 Can of Chicken Broth 3 Garlic cloves, finely chopped 1/4 cup brown sugar Balsamic vinegar, to taste Worcestershire Sauce, to taste Soy Sauce, to taste 64oz Beef Broth 2-3 Bay Leaves Melty cheese, preferably guereye or swiss Directions Sweat the onions in a covered Dutch oven over med-low heat, salt them, with 1 whole stick of butter and some olive oil for about 2 hours stirring occasionally but increasing in frequency as the heat gets raised over time.</description></item><item><title>Lobster bisque</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid><description>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 🍳Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 litres Ingredients 1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams 2 onions 2 carrots 1 shallot 2 garlic cloves cognac 3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree 4 tomatoes 3 tbsp flour 1 glass dry white wine 2 litres fish stock 1 bayleaf 2 twigs of thyme fresh parsley heavy cream olive oil 2 tbsp butter Directions Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.</description></item><item><title>Miso-soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</guid><description>Miso-soup is Japanese traditional home cooking.
Ingredients dashi stock miso paste tofu(optional) seaweed(optional) green onion(optional) Directions put about half of the water in the pot and bring the water to a boil. put the dashi stock in the pot. if you use tofu or seaweed, cut the ingredients into bite-sized pieces, place the ingredients in the pot and bring to a boil. Melt the miso in the water and bring the water to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Potato Leek Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 1 quart chicken or veggie stock 11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes 1 bay leaf ¾ cup heavy cream white pepper (optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg (optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed Directions Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.</description></item><item><title>Aljotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</guid><description>Aljotta (&amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;Yo!&amp;rdquo;) is a traditional Maltese light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; white fish that don&amp;rsquo;t turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup that is adaptable to customizing to your desired vegetables or other additions
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: Ingredients 2 chicken breasts 1 Onion 2 carrots 2 celery stalks 32 oz / 950ml Chicken Stock or Broth Pasta (Optional) Directions Cook chicken breasts, shred, and set aside in a bowl. Cut up carrots and celery, place in pot and saute. Add in chicken and stock or broth and mix together well.</description></item><item><title>Tomato and Grilled Bell Pepper soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</guid><description>🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️Servings:12 Can be prepared the night before and kept frozen for a week or two.
Ingredients 10 tomatoes 2 red bell peppers 2 onions 1 clove of garlic 1L stock or broth ¾t Cayenne pepper 1t paprika powder 3t bruschetta herbs 1t oregano 1t giner syrup 2T olive oil 2T heavy cream Directions Halve, deseed and grill the bell peppers in an oven or on a grill.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Noodle Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</guid><description>This is a very easy and simple Japanese style ramen noodle soup. This is very cheap to make, and you can really customise this however you wish with the garnish. This is my own spin inspired by other recipes that I found.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 20 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 750ml Chicken stock 4 Pork chops OR 4 Chicken Breasts Set honey 3 Garlic cloves Soy sauce Worcestershire sauce Ginger, sliced Chinese 5 Spice 1 Red Chilli, sliced and deseeded (Optional, but recommended) 375g Ramen Noodles (Medium Egg Noodles work well too) 100g Spinach (Optional) 4 Tbsp Sweetcorn (Optional) Sesame seeds (Optional) 4 Boiled Eggs (Optional) 1 Sheet of Dried Nori (Optional) Spring Onion, chopped (Optional) Directions For the broth, add 700ml of chicken stock to a large boiling pot with the garlic, ginger, soy sauce, chinese five spice, chili, and 300ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Sticky Porkchops</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</guid><description>Simple chinese inspired sticky porkchops.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 hours 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Pork chops 2 heaped tbsp Set honey 3 Garlic cloves, crushed Soy sauce Ginger (thumb sized piece), sliced 1 tbsp Chinese Five Spice Directions Fill a shallow dish with soy sauce to about half the thickness of your porkchops. The level shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fully submerge them. Mix in the honey until fully combined with the soy sauce, then mix in the garlic, ginger and chinese five spice.</description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people Ingredients 2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander Directions Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description></item><item><title>Almeirim Stone Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</guid><description>It is truly emblematic of Portuguese cuisine, as it uses all of the ingredients available in order to waste no food.
Ingredients well-washed stone kidney beans or fresh pig&amp;rsquo;s ear (blanched and sliced thin) chouriço negro or firm type of blood sausage mixed meat chouriço or mediterranean smoked sausage pork belly, fatback or bacon potatoes, cubed onions, chopped garlic cloves bay leaf cilantro/coriander, chopped Directions In a saucepan, boil the kidney beans with the pig&amp;rsquo;s ear, sausages, pork belly, onions, garlic and bay leaf in some water and add a well-washed stone.</description></item></channel></rss>