<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Syrup on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/syrup/</link><description>Recent content in Syrup on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/syrup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Belgian pear syrup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</guid><description>&lt;p>A delicious syrup that can be eaten on bread and used in a multitude of recipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 6 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>7 pears (Quality doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter; you can argue that overripe pears are better because they have more sugar content.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 apples&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a small handful of dates, raisins, dried apricots or prunes (optional &amp;ndash; you can experiment with these; they can bring out some nice flavors.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 grams sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 glass of water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>find sieve or cheese cloth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>glass jar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Wash the outside of the fruit with water and cut it in 8 medium sized pieces. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to core or deseed the fruit; everything can go in the pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the fruit in a large pan with a thick bottom so you get even heat. I suggest you place the pears on the bottom, since they don&amp;rsquo;t burn as fast. Add the glass of water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are using them, add the dried fruits at this point.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the heat as low as possible and let it all slowly stew for 3 hours, stirring every now and then.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At this point, you can boil your glass jars to sterilize them. Place the sterilized jars on a clean, dry towel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the fruit is done cooking for 3 hours, grab your sieve or cheese cloth, and place it over a bowl, run your fruit through it until you have extracted all the clear liquid. You can discard the pulp.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quickly rinse the pot with water until clean and add the fruit liquid back. Place back on the stove.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the sugar. Add a bit less sugar if you also used dried fruits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for another 2 hours. After that, stir every so often, Be careful with the stirring; if you stir too often, it might caramelize too quickly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After two to two and a half hours, your syrup should be nearly done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At this point, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you on how thick you want your syrup to be. A good way to test the viscosity is to drop a little bit on a cold plate or on your countertop to see how it is at room temperature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you are happy with the viscosity, pour the syrup into your sterilized jars and immediately seal them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>