<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>beans on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/beans/</link><description>Recent content in beans on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/beans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fennel White Bean and Kale Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup with lots of veggie and protein.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 bowls Ingredients ½ cup olive oil 2 small fennel bulbs, small-diced 2 small yellow onions, small-diced 4 teaspoons minced fresh rosemary or thyme 10 cloves of garlic, minced or pressed ½-1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes. 10-12 oz kale, (escarole, swiss chard, or spinach can also be used). 4 cans cannellini beans, rinsed 4 cups chicken broth.</description></item><item><title>Frijol con puerco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 ~ 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 kg of black beans, rinsed and drained. 2 kg of pork loin or ribs cut into 5 cm pieces, it can be mixture of the two. 1 white onion without skin cut, in half. 4 branches of fresh epazote, or 15 branches of coriander tied with kitchen twine. 8 to 10 radishes, julienned or striped.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula Directions Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste. Simmer for 3 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Cooked Chickpeas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</guid><description>Easy recipe for cooked chickpeas. Can be add to salads, rice, or almost anything else.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 can chickpeas / garbanzo beans, drained 1 tbsp olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper Directions Heat oil in pan. Add chickpeas and seasonings. Cook over medium-high heat for 10-15 minutes. Salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Thinly minced and non-lean mince is preferred. Spices shall be left to the choice of the cook, if at all desired. Mince should be broken up well before cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1-2 hours Ingredients Chorizo pork sausage Pork mince Bacon strips Tomato sauce Chilis Kidney beans Olive oil Wine Butter (spices) Directions As pan heats: Slice chilies and chorizo as desired Olive oil in pan heat on high Pork mince in.</description></item><item><title>Refried Beans</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</guid><description>One of my favorite dishes that works either as an appetizer or side dish is refried beans. A classic from Mexican cuisine, that is best eaten with some totopos, or tortilla chips.
Ingredients As usual, the ingredients here are for about two adult portions:
400-500g can of pre-cooked beans 1/4 onion 3-4 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika 2-4 spoonfuls butter Cooking oil (can be olive oil) Directions Add the oil and the butter to the frying pan and heat to medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Chili Con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients Canned Whole Peeled Tomatoes Red Peppers White Onions Chili Pepper Garlic Ground Beef Kidney Beans Dark Chocolate Chili Powder Tomato Paste Beef Stock (optional) Neutral Oil Cilantro Sugar seasoning cumin paprika chili flakes Directions Brown the beef by adding it to a pot with neutral oil. Start breaking it into small pieces. Allow water to leave the meat. Salt it to expel more water. Once water is gone, the sound will change and it will start to fry.</description></item><item><title>Drunken beans (Pintos Borrachos)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</guid><description>Pinto beans cooking with beer, what beer you use can change the dish.
Ingredients 1 small yellow onion 3 gloves of garlic 2 tomatoes. chopped 4 cups of water 1 1/2 cups of pinto beans (can be dried or canned) 1 tbsp oregano 3/4 tsp cumin 2 tbsp chilli powder(depends how hot you like it) 12oz of Beer/dark ale Directions Sauté onions. Add garlic, sauté bit longer. Add tomatoes, water, beans, oregano, cumin, chilli powder, beer and salt, gradually bring to boil.</description></item></channel></rss>