<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beans on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/beans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beans on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/beans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula  Directions  Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chilli con Carne</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</guid>
      <description>Thinly minced and non-lean mince is preferred. Spices shall be left to the choice of the cook, if at all desired. Mince should be broken up well before cooking.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1-2 hours  Ingredients  Chorizo pork sausage Pork mince Bacon strips Tomato sauce Chilis Kidney beans Olive oil Wine Butter (spices)  Directions  As pan heats: Slice chilies and chorizo as desired Olive oil in pan heat on high Pork mince in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooked Chickpeas</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</guid>
      <description>Easy recipe for cooked chickpeas. Can be add to salads, rice, or almost anything else.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 3  Ingredients  1 can chickpeas / garbanzo beans, drained 1 tbsp olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper  Directions  Heat oil in pan. Add chickpeas and seasonings. Cook over medium-high heat for 10-15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drunken beans (Pintos Borrachos)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</guid>
      <description>Pinto beans cooking with beer, what beer you use can change the dish.
Ingredients  1 small yellow onion 3 gloves of garlic 2 tomatoes. chopped 4 cups of water 1 1/2 cups of pinto beans (can be dried or canned) 1 tbsp oregano 3/4 tsp cumin 2 tbsp chilli powder(depends how hot you like it) 12oz of Beer/dark ale  Directions  Sauté onions. Add garlic, sauté bit longer. Add tomatoes, water, beans, oregano, cumin, chilli powder, beer and salt, gradually bring to boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refried Beans</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite dishes that works either as an appetizer or side dish is refried beans. A classic from Mexican cuisine, that is best eaten with some totopos, or tortilla chips.
Ingredients As usual, the ingredients here are for about two adult portions:
 400-500g can of pre-cooked beans 1/4 onion 3-4 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika 2-4 spoonfuls butter Cooking oil (can be olive oil)  Directions  Add the oil and the butter to the frying pan and heat to medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
