<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mushrooms on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/mushrooms/</link><description>Recent content in Mushrooms on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/mushrooms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Winter Risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Arborio Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Baby Spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic Cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 1/2 cup Vegetable Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Parmesan Cheese, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 lb Baby Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp White Wine Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Walnuts, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Leek, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp Unsalted Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine vegetable broth in a medium pot. Cover and bring to a gentle boil over medium heat. While broth comes to a boil, peel and mince/grate the garlic. Roughly chop the spinach. Thinly slice mushrooms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a large non-stick pan over medium heat. When hot, add the butter, onions, leeks, and mushrooms. Season with salt. Cook, stirring occasionally, until softened (2-3 mins). Add rice, garlic, and vinegar. Cook, stirring constantly until fragrant (1-2 min).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 1 cup broth from the medium pot to the pan with rice. Stir until broth has been absorbed by rice. Continue adding broth 1 cup at a time, stirring regularly, until liquid is absorbed, the texture is creamy and the rice is tender (28-30 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While risotto cooks, add tomatoes and a tablespoon of oil to a parchment-lined baking sheet. Season with salt and pepper, then toss to coat. Roast on the middle rack of the oven until tomatoes start to burst (10-11 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the last cup of broth has been absorbed and rice is tender and creamy, add Parmesan and spinach to risotto. Stir until spinach wilts (3-4 mins). Stir in roasted tomatoes. Divide risotto between bowls. Sprinkle walnuts over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Mushroom Stroganov</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prep time: 10 Minutes
Cook time: 20 Minutes
Servings: 2&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 oz uncooked pasta (spaghetti or any other long noodle will work. Stroganov can also be served over rice.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 oz mushrooms (I reccommend shitake, but white, portabello, or maitake will also work.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves of garlic, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small yellow onion, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp general purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Cup vegetable broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tsp dijon mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tsp Smoked paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Tbsp creme fraiche (can be made by mixing equal parts heavy and sour cream)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp parsely&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and cook pasta al dente&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a cup, combine flour, mustard, smoked paprika, salt and pepper. Add broth and whisk until no lumps remain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While pasta is cooking, melt butter in a medium skillet and over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the butter is melted, add onions and cook until softened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add mushrooms and cook until all water evaporates and mushrooms are slightly browned, about 7 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garlic and cook for another 30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the flour and broth mixture into the mushrooms and cook until thickens, about 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in Creme Fraiche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the strained pasta to the mushroom sauce and stir to coat the pasta completely.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Mushroom risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20-30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 shallot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g button or crimini mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g risotto rice (Arborio, Carnaroli or Vialone Nano)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup white wine (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mushroom or chicken stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated Pecorino or Parmesan cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Finely mince the shallot and garlic and slice the mushrooms into large pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat a pan with some olive oil on medium-high heat. Ideally this should be a wide skillet with tall sides, but a pot will also do the job.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute the vegetables until fragrant, then add the mushrooms with a pinch of salt and cook them down until they&amp;rsquo;re nicely browned, about 10 minutes or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the rice in and let it toast for about a minute or so. This will develop some nice nutty flavors, but overdoing this will affect the creaminess of the finished dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with white wine and let the alcohol cook off. After that start ladling in the stock bit by bit stirring constantly for about 20-30 minutes (depending on the brand of rice used), until the rice is cooked but has a slight bite to it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and add a couple tablespoons of cold butter and grated cheese, and stir well to emulsify. Check for final seasoning and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>