<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Potato on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/potato/</link><description>Recent content in Potato on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/potato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colcannon Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 70 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 Potatoes, peeled and quartered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>7 Tbsp Butter, cut into small chunks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Sour Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cup Cabbage, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Leeks, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cubes Chicken Bouillon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Cheddar Cheese, shredded&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place the potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water. Bring to a boil, then reduce heat to medium-low, cover and simmer until tender, about 20 minutes. Drain and allow to steam dry for a minute or two. Season the potatoes with salt, and mash with 6 Tbsp of the butter, the sour cream, egg, and milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 350F. Grease a 2-quart casserole dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat the remaining butter in a skillet over medium heat. Stir in the cabbage, leeks, and onion until the cabbage is tender and the onion is translucent (10 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crush the bouillon cubes into the cabbage mixture, and stir to blend and dissolve the cubes. Stir the cabbage mixture into the potato mixture until thoroughly mixed, and spoon into the prepared casserole dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake in the preheated oven for 40 minutes, top with cheddar cheese, and return to oven until the cheese melts (10 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Perfect Potato Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>5 Potatoes, peeled and cut into bite-size chunks (about 2 lbs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Plain Yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Mayonnaise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Prepared Horseradish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Radishes, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 stalks Celery, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 large Green Onions, thinly sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup Fresh Dill, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place potatoes in a pot and just cover with water. Partially lid and bring to a boil. Reduce heat and simmer partially covered just until potatoes are tender (5 mins). Don&amp;rsquo;t overcook. Drain well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile in a large bowl, stir yogurt with mayonnaise, horseradish, salt, and pepper. Stir in radishes, celery, green onions, parsley, and dill until mixed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add warm potatoes and stir to combine. Refrigerate at least 1 hour before serving. Taste and adjust seasonings if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Kettle Chips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</guid><description>&lt;p>Credits to creator of recipe, Ethan Chlebowski, &lt;a href="https://www.ethanchlebowski.com/cooking-techniques-recipes/kettle-cooked-chips">(original recipe)&lt;/a>.
I decided to post it on here to be more available.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 11 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1~2, about 1 plate full&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Russet Potato, or other potato with high starch and low moisture. The amount of starch effects the crunchiness of the chip.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peanut Oil for frying (at least 1 to 2 inches in the pan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt or seasoning of your choice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Set a wok or pot over medium-low heat and add the peanut oil about 1 to 2 inches up the pot. Set a thermometer to monitor the temperature to reach 315 F (157 C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wash the exterior of the potato. Using a mandolin set on 2 mm (~1/16th inch), a very sharp knife or a potato peeler cut the potatoes into thin chip slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potatoes to the hot oil and cook for 9 to 11 minutes while stirring fairly constantly. &lt;br>
Note: The oil should drop to roughly 250 F in the first few minutes before stabilizing and increasing back to 315 F. This may be slightly different depending on the size of the pot and the amount of oil you use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once golden browned and completely crisp with no bubbling, remove the chips with a slotted spoon and add to a paper towel over a wire rack to absorb excess oil. Seasoning immediately with salt and any seasoning of your choice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t throw away your oil! Let it cool. Place a paper towel in a metal strainer and strain it into a glass or plastic container for next time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="seasoning-suggestion">Seasoning suggestion&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ethan suggests making a special seasoning from jalapeños, onions, garlic, salt and (optional) some MSG. This optional step takes a LOT longer than the rest of the recipe.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dry out the vegetables after cutting and preparing them, sliced quite thin so that they dry out, in the oven at the lowest temperature that it will go to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leave for about 6 hours to dry in the oven.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once dry and brittle, break the vegetables up into little pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Powder them in a mortar and pestle until completely dry and fine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour powder into a separate bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a spoonfull of salt and (optional) a small amount of MSG to the mortar and pestle. Grind to the same consistency as the vegetables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the salt-msg mix to the vegetable powder along with about half a tablespoon of sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sprinkle over the chips and mix well.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Potato Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Serves many people or one person for many days.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Potatoes (yellow or brown), I don&amp;rsquo;t count but 10+&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter, a stick or two&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whole Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheese (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onion Greens (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sour Cream (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bake the potatoes at 450° for about an hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take them out and leave them to cool for a good 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Begin heating up a big pot to about medium temperature, and put the butter in to melt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes in half and scoop them directly into the pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you are finished with that, begin mashing them until they are a nice mashed-potato-like consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add milk little by little, stirring as you go, until you reach the desired consistency. I usually use half a gallon or so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shred cheese into the soup. Then add garlic, salt, pepper, cayenne, onion greens, and anything else you can think of.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the soup reach a boil, stirring constantly. Remove from heat and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I usually eat it with sour cream mixed in to cool it down and get that extra dairy in.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Ukrainian Vareniki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-vareniki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-vareniki/</guid><description>&lt;p>(Vareniki/Dumplings) Vareniki are popular all over the world, but abroad they have different names.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep: 30 mins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 mins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 45&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>18 ounces potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cups all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup sour cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¼ cup butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions, finely diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 ½ cups finely chopped button mushrooms&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water; bring to a boil. Reduce heat to medium-low and simmer until tender, about 25 minutes. Drain potatoes and mash; season with salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine flour and 1 teaspoon salt in a large bowl while potatoes are cooking. Stir sour cream and baking soda together in a second bowl. Add water to flour mixture and blend in, followed by sour cream mixture. Knead into a smooth dough, cover with plastic wrap, and refrigerate for 10 to 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Melt butter in a skillet over medium heat and cook onions until browned, 5 to 10 minutes. Add mushrooms and cook until browned, about 5 minutes. Add to mashed potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide dough into 4 portions and roll each portion into a 1 1/2-inch thick rope. Cut ropes into small 1/2-inch pieces. Press each dough piece into a small flat circle and place 1 teaspoon of potato filling in the center. Fold dough over into a half-moon shape and seal edges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring a large pot of salted water to a gentle boil. Add the vareniki in batches and cook until they float to the surface, about 3 minutes. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes more. Remove with a slotted spoon and place in a colander to drain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Potato sourdough bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/sourdough-potato-bread.webp" alt="Potato sourdough bread">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 45 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>150g boiled potatoes in there skin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>350g wheat flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g whole rye flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>11g salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150g water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250g sourdough&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil the potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel of the skin of the potatoes (let them cool down a bit)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir all ingredients and knead them well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the dough rest for 5 hours in warm (25-30°C) conditions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven to 250°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for up to 10 minute with steam.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Release the steam and turn the heat down to 220°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for another 35 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Pâté Chinois (Quebec Style Shepherd’s Pie)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pate-chinois.webp" alt="pate chinois" title="Homemade pate chinois with to much ketchup">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the most traditional dish that every household eats in Quebec. As a kid, you would eat Pâté Chinois at least once a week, either at home or at the school&amp;rsquo;s cafeteria,. It is very similar to a Shepherd’s Pie, as it is divided in 3 layers of ingredients: meat, legumes and mashed potatoes. The literal translation of the name is something like &lt;em>chinese pie&lt;/em>. You can search for the origin of the name on the internet, I&amp;rsquo;m not an history teacher.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cheesy Potato Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</guid><description>&lt;p>Potatoes baked in a dish smothered with cheese, what&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You will need a deep dish that is oven safe&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 45 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>30g+ Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250g Cheddar Cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>275ml Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16g Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>600g Potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As much bacon as you want to garnish&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preparation:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat to 180C&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter deep baking dish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peal and thinly slice potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grate Cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sauce:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Melt Butter in Pot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slowly add flour and stir constantly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After 2 min or bubbly remove from heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add milk slowly, stirring constantly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 3/4 of the cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and Pepper to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assembly:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add a thin layer of potatoes to the dish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a layer of cheese sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add bacon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat steps 1-3 of assembly until there are no more potatoes/sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the remaining 1/4 cheese to the top&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put in oven for 45 min. If it starts to brown too much cover with tinfoil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spanish-tortilla.webp" alt="Spanish Tortilla">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 free-range eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 kg of potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potato slices already salted and let them cook for approximately 20 minutes over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the potatoes are frying, beat the eggs in a bowl. Peel and cut the onion as finely as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add olive oil in another frying pan and slowly fry the onion until it gets a slightly golden color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the onion and add it to the bowl with the beaten egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the potatoes from the pan with a slotted spoon, draining the oil away as much as possible, and add them to the bowl with the onion and egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the mixture rest for at least 5 minutes so all the flavors come together. Give it a very gentle stir from time to time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the oil from the pan you used to fry the potatoes. Use the pan to cook the mixture over medium-high fire for about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip it over with the help of a big plate and cook the other side for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Things like the slicing of the potato, the amount of salt and how curdled is the inner part of the tortilla depend on your own taste. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to experiment!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Stoemp</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mashed potatoes in Belgian style&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>500g potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g bacon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100ml heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut bacon into bits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sauté bacon until well colored.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Peel and dice into small chunks potatoes, peel and slice carrots.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil for 20-25 minutes potatoes and carrots in salted water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain vegetables and mash with a fork, so that the texture remains slightly chunky.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix with bacon bits, butter, cream, nutmeg, salt, pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Potato Leek Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/potato-leek-soup.webp" alt="potato leek soup">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 large leeks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 quart chicken or veggie stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bay leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¾ cup heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Melt the butter in a pot on medium-low heat, add chopped leeks and potatoes. Stir until leeks are sweat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add stock, bay leaf, pepper and optional ingredients now. Raise heat to medium-high, simmer until potatoes are tender.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After removing the pot from the heat, remove the bay leaf and immersion blend pot until you reach a desired consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in heavy cream and salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Basic Sweet Potato Fries Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/sweet-potato-fries.webp" alt="cooked sweet pototo fries in pan">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A simple, tasty, and healthy carb based snack.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1-2 Sweet Pototoes (try different types)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rosemary (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Set oven heat to 425°F (220°C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grab a pan and put a layer of parchment paper (or aluminum foil) on it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop the potato(es) on your cutting board with a sharp knife throwing them onto the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drizzle the fries with olive oil. Toss the fries with clean hands to coat the fries in olive oil. Now wash your hands with soap to remove excess olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Top generously with cinnamon and salt. Pepper and/or rosemary may be added for additional flavor if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put in preheated oven. Setting timer for 20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At 20 minutes, flip the fries. Rubber tongs make it easy to grab and turn a lot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return to oven setting timer for another 10-20 minutes depending on quality of the oven and desired crispiness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy. Maybe them put in a glass bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A fast method to cut the the sweet pototoes is first into fourths, slice the fourths, chops the sliced layers while stacked into fries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want to experiment with a variety of fats, consider combining the olive oil with grass-fed butter and coconut oil. I believe the issue with coconut oil is it likes being cooked at lower temperatures or else the health quality of the oil will degrade.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Creamy Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/creamy-mashed-potatoes.webp" alt="Creamy Mashed Potatoes">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mashed potatoes is a really great recipe that is often relegated to the position
of side dish. This recipe is a spin of the classical mashed potatoes recipe
that&amp;rsquo;s got itself more going on. You can serve this dish for a relatively light
meal, or you can also serve it as a side dish if you want to have a really
hearty meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The quantities here are for about four adult portions. If you are planning on
eating this as a side dish, it might be more like 6-8 portions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fried Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil or Crème Fraîche&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel and cut the potatoes to desired size.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a bit of Oil or Crème Fraîche in your pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put both the potatoes and the onions into the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook them until they&amp;rsquo;re golden-brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Parmesan potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/parmesan-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/parmesan-potatoes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/parmesan-potatoes.webp" alt="Parmesan potatoes">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can have this as a side dish, or for breakfast. Well, you can have it
whenever and wherever you want if you are cooking it! We are grown ups here
after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you can already probably imagine, this dish doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of
ingredients. The quantities are for one average hungry student. If you want to
have it as a side dish this should be enough for two persons.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rösti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/roesti.webp" alt="Rösti">
Used two serving sizes for this Rösti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This swiss classic works great together with fried eggs and steamed peas or spinach.
Can be useful to get rid of leftover potatoes from the day before.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~800g (~1.5lb) potatoes (firm/waxy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g (~1lb) peas or spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions (medium size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>Shred raw or cooked (but cool) potatoes with a grater. The shreds should be
quite large so don&amp;rsquo;t use your typical cheese shredder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice the first onion and mix together with potatoes. You can also add diced
bacon if you want to. Add your seasonings here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat up some butter in a large pan. Add your mix to the pan on high heat.
Let the mixture get warm for a few minutes under constant stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to medium-high. Form the Rösti into a round cack. It should fill
out the whole pan. I recommend a thickness of around 1 - 1.5cm (~1/2&amp;quot;) for a
softer Rösti.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add some more butter flakes around the inside of the pan to get it under the
Rösti.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It can take quite a while for a nice crust to form. Check after roughly 5-10
minutes for browning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the Rösti is cooking dice the other onion and the carrots. Steam
everything in a pan with a bit of water. Use a lid to get the temperature
up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alternatively you can use fresh or creamed spinach.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied with the browning, flip the Rösti and set the heat to
medium-low. A plate can be useful here, put it on top of the Rösti in the
pan and flip. Then gently put the whole cake back in the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the Rösti crispness is to your liking, remove from pan and fry two
eggs. A runny yolk adds quite a bit to the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Top Rösti with eggs and serve with the peas or spinach.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/aelplermagronen.webp" alt="Älplermagronen">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A swiss favorite, &lt;em>Älplermagronen&lt;/em> combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet.
It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 onions (medium size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese. Appenzeller works best. Gruyère would be my go-to alternative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a jar of apple sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Feel free to vary these amounts, it&amp;rsquo;s not like this is anything strict.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tender chunks of meat in a rich brown gravy poured over sour cream mashed potatoes, made in a pressure cooker. This recipe is a modification of the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/91gAm1hBaT4">Texas Cafe Classics Sirloin Tips Recipe&lt;/a> by Mark Rippetoe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Any lean, tough cut of meat (ex. round steak)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unprocessed animal fat of some kind (ex. beef suet, mutton fat)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sour cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shredded cheese of your choice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Small amount of flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beef bouillon (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red wine (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Beef Tips in Gravy&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Potato and Eggplant (Aubergine) Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</guid><description>&lt;p>A simple and tasty curry that is easy to customise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 large eggplant (aubergine)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 medium potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions (finely sliced)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves (crushed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/garam-masala">garam masala&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp ground coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400 ml can chopped tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400 ml can coconut milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>rice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="optional-extras">Optional extras&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>red peppers (capsicums)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>paneer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat the oven to approximately 200 °C (392 °F).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the eggplant into 1 cm (⅓&amp;quot;) slices and place on a tray. Cover with a layer of oil and bake for 20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the sliced onions with oil until soft on medium (about 5-6 minutes).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the garlic, garam masala, turmeric and ground coriander and allow to release aroma for a minute or two.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tip in the canned tomatoes and coconut milk. Add the eggplant, and chunks of potato.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is possible to add additional vegetables at this step. I have on occasion added carrots and red peppers (capsicums).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="7">
&lt;li>Cover and simmer for ~15-20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boil 2 serves of rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the lid and cook for a further 5 minutes, or until reduced.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A nice optional addition at this point is paneer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="10">
&lt;li>Serve with the rice&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Gnocchi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gnocchi is a pasta based on potato, making it a less bloating alternative to other kinds of pasta.
They are substantial and can be roasted in butter and other ingredients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tomato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>parmesan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sage or oregano or thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil potatoes (with their skins) until mashable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slice potatoes in two and scoop them out of their skin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mash with a potato-masher while adding kosher salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slowly begin to add flour while mashing and kneading until there are no lumps of potato and the potato/flour mixture takes on a dough-like consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Begin to boil more water with lots of kosher salt added.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flour a work surface, pinch off some of the dough and roll it on the surface into a long chubby snake.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slice the dough snake into small pieces. Press the pieces with your finger to make an indentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the pieces to the boiling water. They will rise to the top when they are ready.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a pan, melt butter and add sprigs of sage (oregano or thyme will work as well, albeit are less traditional). Smashed tomato juices are also a nice addition.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the cooked gnocchi to the pan and roast them in butter for a minute or two until slightly browned. As pan begins to dry, add some pasta water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve gnocchi on a plate, grate on Parmigiano-Reggiano cheese liberally. Add garnish if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tiroler Gröstl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tiroler-groestl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tiroler-groestl/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 kg / 2 lbs potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 red onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500 g / 1 lbs porkchops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>400 g / 14 ounce bacon (smoked)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ample amount of chopped parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marjoram and cumin to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Clean potatoes and boil with skin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop onion, squeeze and mince the garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice pork and bacon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slice cooked potatoes in thick wedges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry potato wedges in butter, add more butter while stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add pork and bacon and bake until crispy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add and stir the rest of the ingredients, except eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the eggs separately and serve on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>