<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>drink on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/drink/</link><description>Recent content in drink on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/drink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kombucha</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kombucha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kombucha/</guid><description>The simple yet comprehensive guide to making tasty kombucha. This is intended to give you an initial overview of the process. I strongly encourage you to experiment with brewing times, teas, flavors, etc. The scoby is extremely tolerant, so the worst that can happen is that your resulting kombucha won&amp;rsquo;t be that great.
Ingredients 5l (1 gallon) jar 3-5 tbsp black (or green) tea 2 cups sugar kombucha scoby optional additional teas optional juices, fruits, spices patience ;) Directions Primary brew:</description></item><item><title>Strawberry Compote</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</guid><description>Strawberry Compote (клубничный компот) is a chilled sweet drink that is popular in many post-soviet countries. It is similar to strawberry jam or conserves in taste (less sweet/concentrated flavor), but resembles fruit punch in looks and consistency. It is very easy to adjust this recipe and scale it up/down.
FYI, I suggest using organic strawberries for this (may be on the expensive side), it makes a world of difference in flavor.</description></item><item><title>Italian Mulled Wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-mulled-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-mulled-wine/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Crushed Ingredients 1 star anise 1 bay leaf 1 pinch rosemary 1 pinch peppercorn 1 pinch thyme 1 pinch red pepper 1 pinch fennel seeds 1 pinch cloves 1 pinch nutmeg Non-Crushed Ingredients 1 bottle Italian red wine 1 orange 1 lemon 1 tbsp honey 1 tsp vanilla 1 stick cinnamon 4 figs (optional) 100 ml limoncello (optional) 50 ml sweet vermouth (optional) 50 ml bourbon, brandy, or cognac (optional) Directions Pour the wine into a stock pot and turn the gas on medium high Crush all the &amp;ldquo;Crushed Ingredients&amp;rdquo; in a mortar and pestle Peel and juice the orange and lemon (toss the peels and juice into the wine but not the white pith) When the wine is up to a simmer, immediately bring the gas down to low and pour in all the rest of the ingredients Cook on low for at least 15 minutes to infuse the flavors Keep the flame on low so the wine stays warm and continues to infuse, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t bubble / burn off the alcohol Feel free to double the recipe or scale any of these ingredients up or down to suite your taste</description></item><item><title>Tanzanian Tea w/ Milk</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</guid><description>This is a very traditional simple beverage from Tanzania, a country in East Africa. While I stayed there in Mwanza and Dar es Salaam, they would always have this option for breakfast (or in general).
⏲️ Prep time: 5-10 min 🍳 Cook time: 3-8 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Black Ceylon Tea (Preferably, you want a dark, herbal flavor from your tea. I have some from Dar es Salaam, but when I tried researching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find out what kind of tea it is.</description></item><item><title>Assam Tea</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</guid><description>This is a simple Assam tea recipe.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 2 teaspoons of Assam Tea 150 ml of fresh water Sugar (Optional) Milk (Optional) Directions Add 150 ml of water to a small pan and bring it to boil. Then add 2 teaspoons of tea into it and reduce the heat to low. Strain the tea using a tea filter into a cup.</description></item><item><title>Kvass</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</guid><description>Kvass is a Slavic fermented beverage which is both simple to make and rich in flavour.
⏲️ Prep time: ~30 min ⌛ Fermentation time: ~1 week Ingredients 100 g of raisins 100 g of sugar 3 slices of black bread (e.g. pumpernickel bread, rye bread) 1-2 lemons 1 pkg (7 g) of active dry yeast Optional: A handful of coffee beans Non-citrus fruits (e.g. plums, apples, kiwi) Directions Bring 1 L of water in a pot to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Bloody Mary Mix</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 (46 fluid ounce) bottle tomato-vegetable juice cocktail 1 fruit, without seeds lemons, juiced 1 teaspoon brown sugar 1 tablespoon steak sauce 1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce 1 teaspoon prepared horseradish 1 teaspoon hot pepper sauce 1/2 teaspoon celery salt Directions In a large pitcher, combine juice cocktail, lemon juice and brown sugar.</description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).
🍽️ Servings:1-4 Ingredients for 1 liter of Glühwein
300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice 1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :) 50 g Sugar 25 g Raisins 1 orange 1 cinamon bark 1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger) 1 spoon cloves 5 star anise if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre Directions cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration) throw everything in a pot warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil) enjoy</description></item><item><title>Irish Coffee</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish cream liqueur 1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish whiskey 1 cup hot brewed coffee 1 tablespoon whipped cream 1 dash ground nutmeg Directions In a coffee mug, combine Irish cream and Irish whiskey. Fill mug with coffee. Top with a dab of whipped cream and a dash of nutmeg.</description></item><item><title>Orange Glorious</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate 1 cup milk 1 cup water 1/2 cup white sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 12 cubes ice Directions In a blender, combine orange juice concentrate, milk, water, sugar and vanilla. Add ice cubes and blend until smooth. Pour into glasses and serve.</description></item><item><title>Coconut Oil Coffee</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</guid><description> 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 cup hot coffee 1 tbsp coconut oil 1 tbsp unsalted butter Directions Blend coffee, coconut oil, and butter together in a blender until oil and butter are melted and coffee is frothy.</description></item><item><title>Party Mimosa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (12 ounce) can apricot-mango nectar 1 (12 ounce) can pineapple juice 1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate, thawed and undiluted 1 (750 milliliter) bottle cold champagne 3/4 cup cold water Directions Stir together apricot nectar, pineapple juice, water, and orange juice concentrate in a large pitcher until combined. Pour in bottle of sparkling wine just before serving.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Morning Milkshake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</guid><description>A sweet and refreshing milkshake that barely requires any effort to make. You&amp;rsquo;re not required to make it and drink it on Sunday, it was just almost a tradition in my family to make it on the weekends, and it somehow does taste better on a Saturday or Sunday morning.
Ingredients These are for about 4 glasses or 1 liter:
1 banana (or 2 if they are small) ~120 grams of berries.</description></item></channel></rss>