<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cheesefare on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/cheesefare/</link><description>Recent content in cheesefare on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/cheesefare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Colcannon Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 70 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Potatoes, peeled and quartered 7 Tbsp Butter, cut into small chunks 1/2 cup Sour Cream 1 Egg 1 Tbsp Milk 3 cup Cabbage, shredded 2 Leeks, chopped 1 small Onion, chopped 2 cubes Chicken Bouillon 1/2 cup Cheddar Cheese, shredded Directions Place the potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water.</description></item><item><title>Tahini short bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</guid><description>This short bread recipe uses sesame paste called Tahini, a minimal amount of white sugar is necessary in order to get a crunchy/caramelized short-bread. For better results, a food processor is welcome for this recipe. IMPORTANT Butter is what makes this recipe complicated when cooking the dough, make sure it is not liquid or that the room is not to warm and make sure that the shortbreads are cold before putting in the oven.</description></item><item><title>Puff Pastry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/puff-pastry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/puff-pastry/</guid><description>A basic puff pastry recipe that can replace any recipe that calls for puff pastry.
⏲️ Prep time: ~1.5 hrs 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 24 Ingredients 5 cups bread flour 2 1/2 teaspoons salt 2 cups water 2 cups unsalted butter, softened Directions Before starting on the dough, place the butter between two pieces of plastic wrap. Pound into a flat disc using a rolling pin or other heavy object.</description></item><item><title>Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</guid><description>The success of this recipe depends entirely on the quality of the milk. The fresher the milk the better. Your regular UHT milk won&amp;rsquo;t work, because the necessary bacteria have been killed.
You do not necessary need cow milk, basically every animal milk will work, but the cheese will have vastly different (not necessarily worse) characteristics.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of milk 25g of table salt (optional with aging) 2g of rennet Some coarse salt Oil and vinegar (for aging) Directions Preparation Pour the milk and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 35°C.</description></item><item><title>Cream Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</guid><description>Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 250ml of fresh, non-UHT milk 250ml of yogurt 1lt of fresh cream 5g of table salt 6g of of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Mix the yogurt, the milk, the cream, the salt, and the sugar into a bowl. Heat the bowl to 80°C while stirring. Once the temperature has been reached, add the citric acid and mix well.</description></item><item><title>Greek Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h pour the newly obtained yogurt into the cheesecloth.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</guid><description>The ricotta is an Italian cheese made by cooking the whey (liquid byproduct of the cheese production), by cooking it at an high temperature (80-90°C), hence the name &amp;ldquo;ricotta&amp;rdquo;, which means &amp;ldquo;cooked again&amp;rdquo;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s typically made from the whey, you can make it directly from the milk as well.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of whey 500ml of milk (or if not using whey, 2l of milk) 10g of table salt 6g of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Preparation Pour the milk (and/or whey) and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 80°C.</description></item><item><title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g pasta 500g broccoli 4 eggs 200g scamorza cheese 400g béchamel sage (optional) parmesan cheese (optional) Directions Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside. Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes. While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan. Put a layer of béchamel.</description></item><item><title>Quarkbällchen – Fried curd balls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</guid><description>“Quark” is a type of fresh dairy product. It&amp;rsquo;s usually translated as curd cheese or cottage cheese.
Ingredients 420ml quark (plain yoghurt can be used as a replacement) 2 eggs 6 or 7 tbsp of sugar 2 packets of vanilla sugar 400g flour (500g if using yoghurt) 2 packets of baking powder 1L sunflower oil for frying (Optional) icing sugar (Optional) Alcohol by eye so that they do not soak up so much oil Directions Mix ingredients (quark, eggs, sugar, flour, baking powder) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Danish Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid><description>Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients 375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 eggs Directions Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed.</description></item><item><title>Potato Leek Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 1 quart chicken or veggie stock 11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes 1 bay leaf ¾ cup heavy cream white pepper (optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg (optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed Directions Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.</description></item><item><title>Dominican Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 box Spaghetti 1 Onion minced 1 Green Pepper minced 2 Garlic cloves minced 1 tbsp Chicken Bouillon Cube or Adobo 1 tbsp sazón 1 tbsp Tomato Paste 1 cup Tomato Sauce 1 tbsp Butter ¼ cup Evaporated Milk 2 tbsp Green Olives 1 tsp Sugar 1 cup Starchy Pasta Water Directions Boil spaghetti.</description></item><item><title>Bolinhos de Coco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid><description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min Ingredients 300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional) Directions Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiro</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</guid><description>A very traditional Brazilian dessert that is present in every Brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.
Ingredients One can of condensed milk. Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder. One spoon of butter (Actual butter and preferably unsalted. No margarine!) Sprinkles (Optional) Directions Add all ingredients into a pan. Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) until it stops sticking to the bottom of the pan.</description></item><item><title>Frittata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid><description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6 Ingredients 4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Tomato and Grilled Bell Pepper soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</guid><description>🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️Servings:12 Can be prepared the night before and kept frozen for a week or two.
Ingredients 10 tomatoes 2 red bell peppers 2 onions 1 clove of garlic 1L stock or broth ¾t Cayenne pepper 1t paprika powder 3t bruschetta herbs 1t oregano 1t giner syrup 2T olive oil 2T heavy cream Directions Halve, deseed and grill the bell peppers in an oven or on a grill.</description></item><item><title>Zopf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (plus one hour rising) 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 1kg white wheat flour ½L milk 125g butter 14g dry yeast 1½T salt 1 egg Directions Cut or tear up butter and put in skillet with milk on low heat (This is so the ingredients are not too clod, temperature should not exceed 31 C). Put the flour in a large bow with the yeast, salt, milk and butter.</description></item><item><title>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</guid><description>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionally garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).
~15/20 galettes.
Ingredients 500g buckwheat flour 1 egg 70cl water Directions Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Let it rest one hour at room temperature. Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan. When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.</description></item><item><title>French Crêpes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid><description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients 300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil Directions Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people Ingredients 1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas Directions Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description></item><item><title>Oaty Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted) Directions Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description></item><item><title>Simple sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid><description>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.
Ingredients Tomato sauce. Mayonaise Directions Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6 Ingredients For the sauce ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional) For the meatballs 1 lb.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed Round Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</guid><description>Round Squash, Zucchini, or Courguettes can be served as main dish (2 servings per person) or as accompaniment. The amount of squash should be adjusted according to their size. This recipe uses ones the size of a fist.
⏲️ Prep time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Onions 1 Carrot 4 Round squash 1 Cup of rice 100gr of Cheese (optional) Directions Cook the rice.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</guid><description>Mashed potatoes is a really great recipe that is often relegated to the position of side dish. This recipe is a spin of the classical mashed potatoes recipe that&amp;rsquo;s got itself more going on. You can serve this dish for a relatively light meal, or you can also serve it as a side dish if you want to have a really hearty meal.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about four adult portions.</description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer Directions Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets Ingredients 2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 3/4 cup milk, scalded 1 tablespoon butter, or margarine 4 egg yolks, beaten until thick 4 egg whites, beaten stiff Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet) Directions Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.</description></item><item><title>Quesadilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</guid><description>A quick and easy low-prep meal, able to be taken anywhere.
⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time 🍽️ Serves: 1 Ingredients 1-2 tortillas. Any brand works, but you can decide if you want the tortilla folded in half, or 2 tortillas together. ~4 small pinches of (Mozzarella, Oaxaca, or Montery Jack cheese). Most cheeses are fine, but the taste of oaxaca cheese is more authentic.</description></item><item><title>Rösti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</guid><description>Used two serving sizes for this Rösti
This swiss classic works great together with fried eggs and steamed peas or spinach. Can be useful to get rid of leftover potatoes from the day before.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients ~800g (~1.5lb) potatoes (firm/waxy) 2 carrots 500g (~1lb) peas or spinach 4 eggs 2 onions (medium size) butter Directions Shred raw or cooked (but cool) potatoes with a grater.</description></item><item><title>Scandinavian Coffee Cake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 cake Ingredients 1/2 cup milk 1/2 cup shortening 1/2 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 package active dry yeast 1/4 cup warm (not hot) water 3 cup sifted enriched Flour 2 eggs, beaten melted butter, or margarine 2/3 cup firmly packed brown sugar 2 teaspoon cinnamon chopped walnuts Directions Scald milk. Add shortening, sugar, and salt.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Morning Milkshake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</guid><description>A sweet and refreshing milkshake that barely requires any effort to make. You&amp;rsquo;re not required to make it and drink it on Sunday, it was just almost a tradition in my family to make it on the weekends, and it somehow does taste better on a Saturday or Sunday morning.
Ingredients These are for about 4 glasses or 1 liter:
1 banana (or 2 if they are small) ~120 grams of berries.</description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>Ingredients Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional) Directions Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs.</description></item><item><title>Tuna Sub</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</guid><description>Use the best tuna you can find. I like oil-packed but water is OK. Someone you know has a tuna salad recipe.
Ingredients 1 recipe of your favorite tuna salad Sandwich bun or bread (a good one) Thinly sliced cheese (your favorite) Sliced tomatoes Baby spinach leaves Pickles Mayo and mustard Other sandwich toppings (very little out of bounds here). Directions Lightly toast one side of the bun Add cheese to bottom of bun Spread a layer of tuna salad Place several spinach leaves on top bun Add sliced tomatoes Add pickle slices Season with salt and pepper to taste Combine halves and enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h store in the fridge</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour) Directions Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description></item><item><title>Caesar Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid><description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing Directions Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons.</description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional) Directions Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people Ingredients 2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander Directions Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description></item><item><title>Matcha Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid><description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut Directions Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description></item><item><title>Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 200g wheat flour or 100g glutenfree flour 200 ml milk 2 eggs 2 tsp sugar 1 tsp baking soda a little bit of salt Directions Mix all ingredients in a bowl. Let the dough rest for ~15 mins. Heat a pan with a bit butter or oil. For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides.</description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil Directions Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat.</description></item><item><title>Broiled Trevally</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/broiled-trevally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/broiled-trevally/</guid><description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a giant trevally, and if you have seen one, that fish looks ugly. So here&amp;rsquo;s a recipe to make it look&amp;mdash;and taste!&amp;mdash;more appealing.
Ingredients giant trevally eggplants squash (or zucchini) carrots onion garlic ginger tomatoes bay leaf olive oil thyme basil butter Directions Dice carrots, eggplant, squash, tomatoes and onions. Place these on a pan. Put basil, thyme, bay leaf, salt, and pepper on each of the fish&amp;rsquo;s side.</description></item><item><title>Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid><description>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the homepage.
Ingredients eggs butter cheese(optional) milk (optional) Directions Boiled eggs Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged). Place eggs in water. Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency (about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium runny, 10+ for hard boiled).</description></item></channel></rss>