<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pancake on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/pancake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pancake on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/pancake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Banana Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people  Ingredients  1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas  Directions  Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danish Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients  375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 Eggs  Directions  Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or Margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaty Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted)  Directions  Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid>
      <description>Here is a simple Pancake recipe
Ingredients  200g wheat flour 200 ml milk 2 Eggs 2 teaspoon sugar 1 teaspoon baking soda a little bit of salt  Directions  combine all ingredients all in a bowl and stir preheat a pan and add some oil Pour or scoop the batter onto the pan Brown on both sides  Contribution BeFe</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
