<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>portuguese on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/portuguese/</link><description>Recent content in portuguese on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/portuguese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bolo do Caco (Caco Bread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</guid><description>A traditional Madeiran-Portuguese Bread
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 💤 Rest time: 3 days 🍽️ Servings: 10 breads Ingredients Imperial
1¾ lb sweet potato 8 cups all-purpose flour ⅔ cup water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry - yeast 3 teaspoons salt Metric
750 g sweet potato 1 kg all-purpose flour 150 ml water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry yeast 3 teaspoons salt Directions Peel the sweet potatoes.</description></item><item><title>Francesinha</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</guid><description>Francesinha is a traditional dish from the city of Porto. The francesinha in its special sandwich variation consists of linguiça, ham, cold meat and beef steak, covered with melted cheese.
Ingredients Based Ingredients bread linguiça (type of Portuguese sausage) ham Portuguese cheese beef meat Sauce Ingredients blonde beer fried tomato sauce port wine beef broth salted butter onion minced garlic cornstarch olive oil piripiri (Portuguese chili) Directions Directions for the sauce In a big saucepan, heat the olive oil and add the garlic and the onions.</description></item><item><title>Bolinhos de Coco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid><description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min Ingredients 300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional) Directions Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl. Scoop tablespoons of the batter into a cookie sheet or cupcake pan.</description></item><item><title>Almeirim Stone Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</guid><description>It is truly emblematic of Portuguese cuisine, as it uses all of the ingredients available in order to waste no food.
Ingredients well-washed stone kidney beans or fresh pig&amp;rsquo;s ear (blanched and sliced thin) chouriço negro or firm type of blood sausage mixed meat chouriço or mediterranean smoked sausage pork belly, fatback or bacon potatoes, cubed onions, chopped garlic cloves bay leaf cilantro/coriander, chopped Directions In a saucepan, boil the kidney beans with the pig&amp;rsquo;s ear, sausages, pork belly, onions, garlic and bay leaf in some water and add a well-washed stone.</description></item><item><title>Bitoque - Portuguese Steak with Beer Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</guid><description>Bitoque (pronounced bee-tok) is a traditional quintessential Portuguese dish, its name comes from being cooked in wood burning ovens in the oil mills. Good in combination with red wine, beer sauce that I am going to also provide the ingredients and directions on how to do, rice, french fries and a salad.
Ingredients sirloin steaks garlic olive oil q.b. (quanto basta – ‘enough’) medium fat milk beer mustard flour eggs Directions Season the steaks with sliced garlic and salt.</description></item></channel></rss>