<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russian on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/russian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russian on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/russian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merchant&#39;s Buckwheat</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/merchants-buckwheat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/merchants-buckwheat/</guid>
      <description>Buckwheat is not very popular outside Russia, the former USSR, and some Asian countries; but it is a nice grain full of nutrients which can be used to prepare delicious and nutritious dishes.
Ingredients The ingredients below are for 2 hearty portions.
 400g pork meat 1/2 metric cup (~125ml) buckwheat 1 1/5 metric cup (~300ml) water 1 medium-sized carrot 1 small onion 6-8 tablespoons tomato paste Wheat flour Curcuma Chili powder (optional) 3-4 garlic cloves Parsley 3-4 bay leaves  Directions  Chop the onion and cut the pork into small pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Stroganov</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</guid>
      <description>Prep time: 10 Minutes Cook time: 20 Minutes Servings: 2
Ingredients  8 oz uncooked pasta (spaghetti or any other long noodle will work. Stroganov can also be served over rice.) 12 oz mushrooms (I reccommend shitake, but white, portabello, or maitake will also work.) 2 cloves of garlic, minced 1 small yellow onion, minced 2 Tbsp butter 1 Tbsp general purpose flour 1 Cup vegetable broth 1 Tsp dijon mustard 1 Tsp Smoked paprika 4 Tbsp creme fraiche (can be made by mixing equal parts heavy and sour cream) 2 Tbsp parsely  Directions  Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and cook pasta al dente In a cup, combine flour, mustard, smoked paprika, salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Navy Style</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the three pasta dishes that I usually cook. It&amp;rsquo;s a Russian pasta recipe that is fast and easy to make and is quite tasty.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two hearty adult portions:
 250g pasta. Usually I prefer to use fusilli or penne, but any short-cut pasta should do. 300-400g ground beef 3-4 tomatoes 1 carrot 1/2 onion 2-3 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika  Directions  Add olive oil to your frying pan, heat it to medium-high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pozharskiye Cutlets</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</guid>
      <description>Famous Russian cutlet recipe, favoured by Nicholas I. Despite what seems to be a massive amount of butter required, they&amp;rsquo;re rather light, yet creamy.
Ingredients  Chicken mince Butter (originally, 1 part butter per 2 parts chicken; 1/4 works perfectly fine) Eggs (~1 egg per 500g chicken, plus 3-5 for the breading) A couple white bread loaves (store-bought breadcrumbs also suffice, but require more eggs) Spices/salt (optional, recommended) Non-lard based, non-chunky sauce (optional) Onions (optional)  Directions  Prepare 2 medium-sized and 1 extra large bowl, a few plates and a regular frying pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid>
      <description>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.
Ingredients  Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended) Mayonnaise Horseradish Worchestershire sauce Paprika Dijon mustard Onion powder Pickle relish (optional)  Directions  Put ingredients into bowl or cup. Mix together thoroughly.  Contribution  Anon  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
