<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pizza on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/pizza/</link><description>Recent content in pizza on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/pizza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</guid><description>One serving should be enough to cover a pizza. The sauce can be stored in the refrigerator for ~16 days if put into a conserving jar.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 2 onions 3 garlic cloves olive oil 700g tomato sauce 6 spoon tomato concentrate 0.5 spoon sugar 1 spoon salt 1 spoon pepper 1 spoon thyme/rosemary (finely chopped) 1 spoon oregano (finely chopped) 2 spoon basil (finely chopped) Directions Finely chop onions and garlic into a pot.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</guid><description>This is a recipe combining two others and adding stuff on top. This is more of an example of possible ingredients, you can replace any of them with others.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 serving Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough 1 serving Easy Pizza Sauce ~80g mozzarella cheese ~40g Edam cheese ~40g Tilsitter cheese salami (optional) ham (optional) salsiccia (optional) aubergine (optional) zucchini (optional) mushrooms (optional) olives (optional) arugula salad (add after pizza is done) (optional) fresh basil leaves (add after pizza is done) (optional) Directions Cover a baking tray fully with a thin layer of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</guid><description>One serving(~200g dough) should be enough to make a pizza. The dough can be stored in the refrigerator for ~2 days. For it to last longer, it should be stored in the freezer.
⏲️ Prep time: 70 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g flour (Wholemeal Wheat Flour) 280ml lukewarm water 8g dry yeast 3.5 spoon olive oil 1.5 teaspoon salt Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough.</description></item><item><title>No-knead pizza dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</guid><description>Perfect for pan pizza in an 11 inch iron skillet.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 7-24 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 pizza Ingredients 200g flour 2g instant yeast (dry) 5g salt 5g olive oil 140g luke warm water Directions Mix dry ingredients in a bowl. Mix in olive oil and water. No need for hands or kneading! Cover bowl air tight, and let it sit in room temperature for at least 7 hours, and up to 24 hours.</description></item><item><title>Pan pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</guid><description>Pan pizza gives a thick and crispy crust 🍕. For this recipe, start early with the dough, preferably the night before. It takes a lot of time, but little effort and gives a fantastic result.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hours Ingredients no-knead pizza dough pizza sauce cheese olive oil pepperoni (optional) mushrooms (optional) pineapple (optional) &amp;hellip;really whatever you like (optional) Directions Preheat oven to max temp.</description></item><item><title>Pizza sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0.5-2 hours Ingredients 400g canned tomatoes, preferebly skinned and whole 150g tomato puré 1 medium sized onion olive oil garlic oregano chili pepper (optional) Directions Dice onion and fry in olive oil on medium heat. Add chopped garlic and chili pepper (optional) for some minutes. Mix in tomato puré, salt, pepper, and oregano. Cook until puré gets oily. Add canned tomatoes, and crush with spatula.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</guid><description>Here is a simple pizza dough recipe. Basically you use a 2/1 ratio of flour/liquid. If you use other flour like rye, you may need more liquid.
Ingredients 400g flour (basic wheat flour) 200ml lukewarm water 1 pkg (7g) dry yeast 1 spoon olive oil 1 teaspoon salt a teensy bit of sugar (to feed the yeast) Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough. Let it rest for about 30 minutes somewhere lukewarm Add some flour to a table and roll the dough out there.</description></item></channel></rss>