<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweet on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/sweet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sweet on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/sweet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description> ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients Filling  900 g (4-5) golden delicious apples 15 g (1 tbsp) lemon juice 50 g white sugar 65 g brown sugar 5 g (1 tsp) cinnamon 1-2 g nutmeg 15 g cornstarch 15 g ice water 226 g (2 sticks) cold butter, cut into slices  Crust  350 g flour 5 g salt 30 g white sugar 225 g butter 50-100 ml ice water  Egg Wash  1 egg (optional) 15 g water (optional)  Directions  Peel and cut the apples into 1-2 inch strips Put the apples in a bowl and mix in the lemon juice, sugar, cinnamon, nutmeg, and cornstarch and let it sit for 15 mins to release water Transfer the filling mixture to a sauce pan and reduce the liquid over medium to low heat for around 15 mins, stirring regularly, then turn off the gas While the filling is sitting / reducing, start the crust by putting the flour, salt, sugar, and pieces of butter in a food processor Run the food processor until it resembles a coarse sand (5-10 seconds) then start dripping in the ice water until the mixture starts to chunk together You&amp;rsquo;ll know when it&amp;rsquo;s done if you can pinch the dough with your hand and it sticks together Preheat oven to 350°F then start making the pie crust Cut the dough in half and roll both halves out with a rolling pin until they are big enough to cover your pie pan (around 9 inch diameter) Put the bottom half dough into the pie pan and cut off the excess dough with a knife Dump the sauce pan full of the filling into the pie pan and even it out Cover the pie filling with the top dough and fold over and tuck in the excess crust Use a fork or your fingers to pinch down the top crust to the bottom crust so you don&amp;rsquo;t have air gaps Optionally you can now brush on the egg wash to make the crust get a shiny golden brown color when it cooks Cut a few slits in the top crust with a knife to give it a nice design and allow for air to release Bake 45 minutes at 350°F or until the crust is brown to your liking and the apples are bubbling inside  Contribution  mfed3 - xmr: 48eEMdYtCQaV5wY7wvmxK6jCxKkia9dgpNTMNT1do7RLWXCwWDgSKjN3kiZ6yHbAuAXWgDGN6imnGT9NPeHWD7zX9hSyHu2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.
Ingredients  2 cups all purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda Spices:  1 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/4 teaspoon ginger   1/4 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas) 2 eggs 1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine) 1/2 cup butter or vegetable oil 1/4 cup crushed walnuts  Directions  Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C) Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, oil, sugar) in one bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min  Ingredients  3 bananas 100 g / ½ cups butter 150 g / ¾ cups sugar 2 eggs 1½ tsp. cooking powder 260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour 50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate 50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate some vanilla sugar (optional)  Directions  Peel the bananas and mush them together. Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people  Ingredients  1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas  Directions  Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bloody Mary Mix</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients  1 (46 fluid ounce) bottle tomato-vegetable juice cocktail 1 fruit, without seeds lemons, juiced 1 teaspoon brown sugar 1 tablespoon steak sauce 1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce 1 teaspoon prepared horseradish 1 teaspoon hot pepper sauce 1/2 teaspoon celery salt  Directions  In a large pitcher, combine juice cocktail, lemon juice and brown sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolinhos de Coco</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid>
      <description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min  Ingredients  300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional)  Directions  Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies </title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description> ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  230 g melted butter (2 sticks) 330 g bread flour 5 g salt 5 g baking soda 100-200 g white sugar 100-200 g brown sugar 1 egg 15 g milk 5 g vanilla 225 g 50-70% dark chocolate chips or semi-sweet milk chocolate chips  Directions  Preheat oven to 375°F Mix the flour, baking soda, and salt in a bowl Using a mixer or whisk, beat the butter, sugar, eggs, and vanilla in a separate bowl for a few mins Combine and stir in the dry ingredients, then the chocolate chips Use an ice cream scooper or spoon to make uniform balls of cookie dough to the size you like and evenly space them out on a parchment paper lined baking sheet (you may need more than one sheet depending on the size of the cookies) Bake in the oven one baking sheet at a time for around 8-10 minutes, taking them out when they start to brown Cool for a few minutes then put them on a cooling rack  Contribution  mfed3 - xmr: 48eEMdYtCQaV5wY7wvmxK6jCxKkia9dgpNTMNT1do7RLWXCwWDgSKjN3kiZ6yHbAuAXWgDGN6imnGT9NPeHWD7zX9hSyHu2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Oil Coffee</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</guid>
      <description>🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  1 cup hot coffee 1 tbsp coconut oil 1 tbsp unsalted butter  Directions  Blend coffee, coconut oil, and butter together in a blender until oil and butter are melted and coffee is frothy.  Contribution Front3ndNinja - Website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danish Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients  375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 Eggs  Directions  Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or Margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glutenfree Pfannkuchen (pancakes)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/glutenfree-pfannkuchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/glutenfree-pfannkuchen/</guid>
      <description>A very easy recipe for glutenfree Pfannkuchen (german pancakes).
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  100g glutenfree flour 200ml milk 50g sugar 2 eggs a pinch of salt  Directions  Mix all ingredients in a bowl Let the dough rest for ~15 mins Heat a pan with a bit butter For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides  Served with  Syrup Cinnamon and sugar  Contribution  Lxgr - github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irish Coffee</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish cream liqueur 1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish whiskey 1 cup hot brewed coffee 1 tablespoon whipped cream 1 dash ground nutmeg  Directions  In a coffee mug, combine Irish cream and Irish whiskey. Fill mug with coffee. Top with a dab of whipped cream and a dash of nutmeg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matcha Cookies</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
 115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut  Directions  Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients  2 eggs 40g sugar (3 tbsp) 20g honey (1 tbsp) 60ml milk (4 tbsp) (you can use water instead) 120g oat flour (1 cup) 1 tsp baking powder (or baking soda + some acid to activate it) Raspberry jam (optional)  Directions  Mix eggs, sugar, honey and milk. In another bowl mix oat flour and baking powder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oats</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid>
      <description>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do with oats.
We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.
Ingredients  oats water pinch of salt  Pick and choose additional ingredients:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaty Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted)  Directions  Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Glorious</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate 1 cup milk 1 cup water 1/2 cup white sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 12 cubes ice  Directions  In a blender, combine orange juice concentrate, milk, water, sugar and vanilla. Add ice cubes and blend until smooth. Pour into glasses and serve.  Contribution Front3ndNinja - Website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange jam</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</guid>
      <description>This jam is a traditional topping for the Polish mazurek, but can be used as a generic sweet spread.
Ingredients  4 medium sized oranges 1 lemon 1 1/2 cup sugar  Directions  Zest all fruit. Peel off the albedo (the white part under the skin). Blend the fruit (not too much, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to become an even mush, just cut up into small pieces). Combine the blended fruit, zest, and sugar in a pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid>
      <description>Here is a simple Pancake recipe
Ingredients  200g wheat flour 200 ml milk 2 Eggs 2 teaspoon sugar 1 teaspoon baking soda a little bit of salt  Directions  combine all ingredients all in a bowl and stir preheat a pan and add some oil Pour or scoop the batter onto the pan Brown on both sides  Contribution BeFe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Party Mimosa</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 (12 ounce) can apricot-mango nectar 1 (12 ounce) can pineapple juice 1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate, thawed and undiluted 1 (750 milliliter) bottle cold champagne 3/4 cup cold water  Directions  Stir together apricot nectar, pineapple juice, water, and orange juice concentrate in a large pitcher until combined. Pour in bottle of sparkling wine just before serving.  Contribution Front3ndNinja - Website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarkbällchen – Fried curd balls</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</guid>
      <description>“Quark” is a type of fresh dairy product. It&amp;rsquo;s usually translated as curd cheese or cottage cheese.
Ingredients  420ml quark (plain yoghurt can be used as a replacement) 2 eggs 6 or 7 tbsp of sugar 2 packets of vanilla sugar 400g flour (500g if using yoghurt) 2 packets of baking powder 1L sunflower oil for frying (Optional) icing sugar (Optional) Alcohol by eye so that they do not soak up so much oil  Directions  Mix ingredients (quark, eggs, sugar, flour, baking powder) in one bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scandinavian Coffee Cake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 cake  Ingredients  1/2 cup milk 1/2 cup shortening 1/2 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 package active dry yeast 1/4 cup warm (not hot) water 3 cup sifted enriched Flour 2 eggs, beaten melted butter, or margarine 2/3 cup firmly packed brown sugar 2 teaspoon cinnamon chopped walnuts  Directions  Scald milk. Add shortening, sugar, and salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Morning Milkshake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</guid>
      <description>A sweet and refreshing milkshake that barely requires any effort to make. You&amp;rsquo;re not required to make it and drink it on Sunday, it was just almost a tradition in my family to make it on the weekends, and it somehow does taste better on a Saturday or Sunday morning.
Ingredients These are for about 4 glasses or 1 liter:
 1 banana (or 2 if they are small) ~120 grams of berries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
