<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>turkish on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/turkish/</link><description>Recent content in turkish on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/turkish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Chicken Breasts 1 cup Bulghur Wheat 1 oz Mixed Olives, drained 4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped 2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend 2 Roma Tomatoes 1 Lemon 1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated 2 Tbsp White Vinegar 1 tsp Sugar Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot.</description></item><item><title>Turkish Red Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</guid><description>Serve with a squeeze of lemon and alongside turmeric flatbread.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 cup Red Lentils 5 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Paprika 1/2 Tbsp Red Paper Flakes 1 large Onion, finely diced 1 large Carrot, diced 4 tsp Tomato Paste 2 tsp Cumin 1/2 tsp Dried Mint 1/2 tsp Thyme or Oregano 4 cup Vegetable Broth 4 cup Water Directions Reserve half the paprika and red pepper flakes, set aside.</description></item><item><title>Turkish-Style Spiced Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Chicken Breasts 1 Tbsp Turkish Spice Blend 1 oz Almonds, sliced 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 12 oz Sweet Potato 2 oz Onion, chopped 100 mL Greek Yogurt 2 Tbsp Parsley 1 Lemon 1/2 tsp Garlic Salt 1 1/2 cup Chicken Broth 1 tsp Sugar Directions Cut sweet potatoes into 1/2 inch pieces.</description></item><item><title>Turmeric Flatbread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</guid><description>A great companion to Turkish Red Lentil Soup.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 cup Wheat Flour (white or whole) 1/2 Tbsp Ground Turmeric 1/2 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Baking Powder 2 Tbsp Olive Oil Directions Combine flour, turmeric, salt and baking powder. Stir in 1/3 cup water and the olive oil. Knead until smooth (1-2 min).</description></item><item><title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients yogurt 1/3 cup rice 2 tablespoon flour 1 egg yolk butter Directions wash the rice put water in the pot and wait for water to boil add some salt and rice wait for 15 minutes mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl add water from the soup and mix by warming when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well serve warm</description></item></channel></rss>