<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Turkish on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/turkish/</link><description>Recent content in Turkish on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/turkish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4 Chicken Breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Bulghur Wheat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 oz Mixed Olives, drained&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Roma Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp White Vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot. Cover and bring to a boil over high heat. While water comes to a boil, cut tomato into 1/4&amp;quot; pieces. Zest and juice the lemon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garlic and bulghur to the boiling water. Stir to combine, remove pot from heat, cover, and let stand until bulghur is tender and liquid is absorbed (15 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While bulghur rehydrates, pat chicken dry and season with Za&amp;rsquo;atar spice blend, salt, and pepper. Heat a large non-stick pan over medium-high heat. Add 1/2 tsp oil, then the chicken. Sear until golden-brown. Transfer chicken to a sheet and bake on the middle rack in the oven until chicken is cooked through (10-12 mins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, whisk together vinegar, lemon juice, lemon zest, 1 tsp oil, and 1/2 tsp salt in a small bowl. Set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When bulghur is done, fluff with a fork. Add olives, spinach, tomatoes, and half the dressing to the pot. Season with salt and pepper, then stir to combine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thinly slice chicken. Divide bulghur salad between plates, then top with chicken. Sprinkle with feta and drizzle remaining dressing over top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Turkish Red Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Serve with a squeeze of lemon and alongside turmeric flatbread.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup Red Lentils&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Tbsp Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Tbsp Red Paper Flakes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large Onion, finely diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large Carrot, diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tsp Tomato Paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Dried Mint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Thyme or Oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cup Vegetable Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 cup Water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Reserve half the paprika and red pepper flakes, set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pick through lentils for any foreign debris, rinse two or three times, drain and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large pot over medium-high heat, saute 2 Tbsp of the olive oil and and onion with a pinch of salt for 3 minutes. Add the carrots and saute for another 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tomato paste and stir it around for 1 minute. Add cumin, mint, thyme, and the paprika/pepper flakes not reserved - and saute for 10 seconds to bloom the spices. Immediately add the lentils, water, broth, and salt. Bring the soup to a boil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once boiling, reduce heat to a medium, cover the pot halfway, and cook for 15-20 minutes or until the lentils have fallen apart and the carrots are fully softened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, heat the remaining olive oil in a small sauce pan over medium heat, and swirl in the reserved paprika and red pepper flakes. The moment you see the paprika start to bubble, remove the pan from the heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blend the soup to reach the desired consistency. Taste for seasoning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide soup into bowls and drizzle the paprika oil on top of each serving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Turkish-Style Spiced Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 Chicken Breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp Turkish Spice Blend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 oz Almonds, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup Basmati Rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 oz Sweet Potato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 oz Onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100 mL Greek Yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Garlic Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cup Chicken Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut sweet potatoes into 1/2 inch pieces. Combine and toss sweet potatoes, half the onions, half the garlic salt, and a tablespoon of oil. Lay to a baking sheet and roast on the middle rack of the oven, stirring halfway through until golden brown (12-22 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While sweet potatoes roast, heat a medium pot over medium-high heat. When hot, add a tablespoon of oil and remaining onions. Cook, stirring often until fragrant (1 min). Add chicken broth and rice, cover, and bring to a boil over high heat. Once boiling, reduce heat to low and leave covered until rice is tender and liquid is absorbed (12-14 mins). Remove pot from heat, still covered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While rice cooks, heat a large non-stick pan over medium heat. When hot, add almonds to the dry pan. Toast, stirring occasionally until golden brown (2-3 mins). When almonds are done, transfer to a plate and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While almonds toast, pat chicken dry with paper towel. Sprinkle with Turkish Spice blend and the remaining garlic salt. Season with pepper. With the pan used in the last step, increase heat to medium-high. Add a tablespoon of oil and the chicken. Pan-fry until golden brown (1-2 min per side). Transfer chicken to another baking sheet. Roast on the top rack of the oven until chicken is cooked through (10-12 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While chicken roasts, zest and juice half the lemon. Cut remaining lemon into wedges. Roughly chop parsley. Add yogurt, half the parsley, sugar, lemon zest and juice to a small bowl. Season with salt and pepper, and whisk to combine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fluff rice with a fork, then stir in almonds and remaining parsley. Slice chicken. Divide rice between plates, then top with sweet potatoes and chicken. Spoon yogurt sauce over top. Squeeze over a lemon wedge, as desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Turmeric Flatbread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</guid><description>&lt;p>A great companion to Turkish Red Lentil Soup.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 cup Wheat Flour (white or whole)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Tbsp Ground Turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp Kosher Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp Baking Powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine flour, turmeric, salt and baking powder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in 1/3 cup water and the olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knead until smooth (1-2 min). Cover and set aside 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the dough into 4 pieces; flatten each into a 6-inch round.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook one at a time in an oiled skillet over medium-high heat, flip when browned (2 mins).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>yogurt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/3 cup rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoon flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg yolk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>wash the rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put water in the pot and wait for water to boil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add some salt and rice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>wait for 15 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add water from the soup and mix by warming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well&lt;/li>
&lt;li>serve warm&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>