<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fruit on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/fruit/</link><description>Recent content in fruit on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/fruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strawberry Compote</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</guid><description>Strawberry Compote (клубничный компот) is a chilled sweet drink that is popular in many post-soviet countries. It is similar to strawberry jam or conserves in taste (less sweet/concentrated flavor), but resembles fruit punch in looks and consistency. It is very easy to adjust this recipe and scale it up/down.
FYI, I suggest using organic strawberries for this (may be on the expensive side), it makes a world of difference in flavor.</description></item><item><title>Orange jam</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</guid><description>This jam is a traditional topping for the Polish mazurek, but can be used as a generic sweet spread.
Ingredients 4 medium sized oranges 1 lemon 1 1/2 cup sugar Directions Zest all fruit. Peel off the albedo (the white part under the skin). Blend the fruit (not too much, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to become an even mush, just cut up into small pieces). Combine the blended fruit, zest, and sugar in a pot.</description></item><item><title>Belgian pear syrup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</guid><description>A delicious syrup that can be eaten on bread and used in a multitude of recipes.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 hours Ingredients 7 pears (Quality doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter; you can argue that overripe pears are better because they have more sugar content.) 3 apples a small handful of dates, raisins, dried apricots or prunes (optional &amp;ndash; you can experiment with these; they can bring out some nice flavors.</description></item><item><title>Savory Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/savory-squash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/savory-squash/</guid><description>Prep Time: 5 mins Cook Time: 1 Hour Ingredients 1 Butternut Squash 1/2 Stick of butter Salt, to taste St. Augur Blue Cheese Chives Directions Peel Butternut squash and discard both ends. Cut in half lengthwise, scoop and discard seeds. Cut in half lengthwise again. Place face down on greased baking sheet. Rotate to roast the other face after 20 minutes, Check at 45 mins with a toothpick for softness.</description></item></channel></rss>