<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tomato on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/tomato/</link><description>Recent content in tomato on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/tomato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn 4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced 1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced 1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced 1 small Onion, sliced 1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped 3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 6 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar 1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp dill weed 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper 2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh Directions Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Gypsy Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</guid><description>The vegetables used in this soup are flexible. Any orange vegetable can be combined with green. Such as peas or green beans to replace peppers, or carrots and/or squash to replace the sweet potato.
⏲️ Prep time: 40 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 2 cup Chopped Onion 2 cloves Chopped Garlic 2 cup Sweet Potatoes, chopped and peeled 1/2 cup Chopped Celery 1 cup Chopped Fresh Tomatoes 3/4 cup Chopped Sweet Peppers 1-1/2 cup Cooked Chickpeas 3 cup Stock or Water 2 tsp Paprika 1 tsp Turmeric 1 tsp Basil 1 tsp Salt dash Cinnamon dash Cayenne 1 Bay Leaf 1 Tbsp Tamari Soy Sauce Directions In a soup kettle or large saucepan, saute onions garlic, celery, and sweet potatoes in olive oil for about five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 12 min 🍳 Cook time: 75 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 3 1/2 lbs Tomatoes 1 1/2 lbs Eggplant 1 lb Zucchini 3 Bell Peppers 2 lbs Onions 6 cloves Garlic Herbes de Provence (Basil, Thyme, Parsley) Olive Oil Salt Pepper 140g Tomato Paste (optional if tomatoes aren&amp;rsquo;t yummy) Directions Peel and drain the tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t mind the seeds): cut out the stem cores; drop the whole tomatoes into boiling water for 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Red Lentil Dahl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 medium Yellow Onion 1 Tbsp Fresh Ginger, grated 4 Garlic Cloves, minced 2 Tbsp Yellow Curry (mild madras) 1 tsp Sea Salt 1 cup dried Red Lentils 4 - 5 cups Water 5 Plum Tomatoes, chopped juice of 1 Lemon 1 cup Fresh Cilantro, chopped and lightly packed Dried Red Chili&amp;rsquo;s or cayenne pepper, to taste 1/4 tsp Ground Cinnamon Directions Heat oil in a soup pot and saute onions for 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp and Chicken Jambalaya</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</guid><description>Warm up your stock with raw shrimp shells to infuse additional flavour, if desired. Serve dish with french bread and your favourite beer.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min Ingredients 1/4 tsp Cayenne 3/4 tsp White Pepper 1 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Thyme 1/2 tsp Rubbed Sage 1/4 tsp Dried Basil 1/2 tsp Black Pepper 1 Tbsp Unsalted Butter 1/2 cup Diced Andouille (or Chirozo sausage) 1/2 cup Diced Onion 1/2 cup Diced Bell Pepper 1/2 cup Diced Celery 1/2 cup Diced Fresh Tomatoes 1/2 cup Tomato Sauce 3/4 cup Enriched Long Grain Rice 1-1/4 cup Chicken Stock 1 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 2 Tbsp Minced Fresh Garlic 1/2 cup Diced Chicken (cooked or raw) 1-1/2 cup Medium Shrimp 1 Tbsp Finely Chopped Italian Parsley 3 Tbsp Finely Sliced Green Onions Directions Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Farcies tomatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</guid><description>Farcies tomates with rice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 tomatoes per person. 300g of ground beef meat. 1 or 2 onions. Condiments of your choice: Parsley, origan or cumin. Olive oil Gruyere cheese. Salt and pepper. Optional: Butter. Directions Heat the oven to 200C. Slice the top to the tomatoes and place them in the oven tray.</description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 14 Ingredients 1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes 1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes 1 green onion 1 red onion 1 jalapeño pepper 1 handfull fresh cilantro 1 clove garlic 1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional) 1 chili pepper (optional) 1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional) Directions Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.</description></item><item><title>Ragu Napoletano</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid><description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 Ingredients Tomato Sauce 6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional) Aromatics and Herbs 8 cloves garlic 1.</description></item></channel></rss>