<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bread on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/bread/</link><description>Recent content in bread on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/bread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Keto Coconut Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-flour-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-flour-bread/</guid><description>I created this recipe looking for a bread alternative not using any grains, processed sugar and processed oils. It is sitting between bread and cake feel and my wife loved it. I used pasture-raised eggs to my recipe, just because it is more nutritious. But regular eggs should be fine.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 6 Medium Eggs (or 5 Extra Large) 1 Tbsp Coconut Oil ¾ cup Coconut Flour 1 tsp Baking Powder Pinch of Salt ½ tsp or less of Xanthan Gum (optional, to have a more stick bread) Directions Mix all dry ingredients in a big bowl.</description></item><item><title>Turmeric Flatbread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</guid><description>A great companion to Turkish Red Lentil Soup.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 cup Wheat Flour (white or whole) 1/2 Tbsp Ground Turmeric 1/2 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Baking Powder 2 Tbsp Olive Oil Directions Combine flour, turmeric, salt and baking powder. Stir in 1/3 cup water and the olive oil. Knead until smooth (1-2 min). Cover and set aside 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Torta Frita Criolla (Argentinian frybread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</guid><description>A &amp;ldquo;merienda&amp;rdquo; (afternoon meal) that is intertwined with the history of colonization on the River Plate region. Never have it by yourself, instead with friends or family, and a cup/gourd of Mate.
⏲️ Prep time: 1h 10min or 2h 10min, (depending on how long you leave it to rest.) 🍳Cook time: 10 minutes. 🍽️ Servings : 10. Ingredients 1.1 pound (1/2 kilo) of all-purpose flour. 4 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>Challah Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</guid><description>A kind of braided bread preparation.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 2-4 NOTE: Prep time does not account for the 3-4 hours the dough must be left to rise and cool (see directions 5, 10, &amp;amp; 12).
Ingredients 600ml ( 1 Pint ) warm water 1 tablespoon dry active baking yeast 7 tablespoons honey 1.5kg flour 3 eggs 1 tablespoon salt 1 tablespoon poppy seeds 4 tablespoons olive oil Directions Fill a large bowl with the water, and sprinkle with the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Italian Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2.5 - 3.25 hr 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients 600g or 5 cups bread flour (or all-purpose if not available) 1 packet (appr. 2 1/4 tsp or 7g) active dry yeast olive oil for greasing Directions Follow directions on the packet to activate yeast in a bowl large enough for mixing the dough Add enough water for a total of 400g or 1 3/4 cups (i.</description></item><item><title>Bolo do Caco (Caco Bread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</guid><description>A traditional Madeiran-Portuguese Bread
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 💤 Rest time: 3 days 🍽️ Servings: 10 breads Ingredients Imperial
1¾ lb sweet potato 8 cups all-purpose flour ⅔ cup water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry - yeast 3 teaspoons salt Metric
750 g sweet potato 1 kg all-purpose flour 150 ml water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry yeast 3 teaspoons salt Directions Peel the sweet potatoes.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</guid><description>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette) Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil) Garlic salt Directions Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F). Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil. Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil. Season with garlic salt, to taste.</description></item><item><title>Potato sourdough bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min Ingredients 150g boiled potatoes in there skin 350g wheat flour 50g whole rye flour 11g salt 150g water 250g sourdough Directions Boil the potatoes Peel of the skin of the potatoes (let them cool down a bit) Stir all ingredients and knead them well. Let the dough rest for 5 hours in warm (25-30°C) conditions. Preheat the oven to 250°C.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough bread with seeds and grains</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-bread-with-seeds-and-grains/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-bread-with-seeds-and-grains/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 120 min Ingredients For the preparation 100g grain of choice (e.g. rye, spelt and wheat) 40g linseed 30g sesame 30g sunflower seeds 600g water For the bread 400g sourdough 200g water (25-35°C) 200g rye flour 300g wheat flour 20g sea salt 2tsp bread spice soaked seeds and grains Directions Preparations (the day before) Feed your sourdough starter for the next day. Boil the grain in 500g water for 45 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough starter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</guid><description>This recipe contains instructions for sourdough starter needed for all sourdough breads. The starter can be done with either wheat flour or rye flour for rye breads. Prefer organic flours as they contain most wild yeasts.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min/day ⏲️ Wait time: 4 days Ingredients Wheat or rye flour Water Directions Day 1: mix 80g of water to 50g of flour and put a cover on the container loosely.</description></item><item><title>Kvass</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</guid><description>Kvass is a Slavic fermented beverage which is both simple to make and rich in flavour.
⏲️ Prep time: ~30 min ⌛ Fermentation time: ~1 week Ingredients 100 g of raisins 100 g of sugar 3 slices of black bread (e.g. pumpernickel bread, rye bread) 1-2 lemons 1 pkg (7 g) of active dry yeast Optional: A handful of coffee beans Non-citrus fruits (e.g. plums, apples, kiwi) Directions Bring 1 L of water in a pot to a boil.</description></item><item><title>No-knead Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 13 h 🍳 Cook time: 50 m 🍽️ Servings: 8-12 slices Ingredients 3 c flour 1 tsp salt 1/4 tsp instant yeast or 1.25/4 tsp active dry yeast 1 1/2 cups warm water Oven-safe pan Directions Mix the dry ingredients then add the hot water. It should come out as a firm dough. Leave the dough at room temperature for 12 hours. You can then keep the dough in the fridge for up to 48 hours before cooking.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough Table Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-loaf/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve never made your own sourdough bread, it can be intimidating! But I believe it is absolutely worth the time and effort. You can look up videos to explain some of the methods listed, such as the stretch and fold, or different ways to shape your loaf. Fermenting grains has been a tradition of home cooking for millennia, and an art only lost in recent years. Fermenting grains has numerous health benefits, is much easier to digest, and even contains natural preservatives.</description></item><item><title>Naan Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</guid><description>A curry serves best with naan that is unleavened bread. Traditionally made in ‘Tandoor or clay oven&amp;rsquo; but at home, we will be making it in the oven and/or on the stovetop. Naan is not eaten solely but acts as assortments with meat, veggies, or egg items.
⏲️ Prep time: 90 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients All-purpose flour 3 cups Active dry yeast 1 tbsp Sugar 2 tbsp Warm Milk 1 cup Butter melted 2 tbsp Oil - little to grease Directions Put the yeast and sugar to warm milk in a large mixing bowl and stir well.</description></item><item><title>Spatchcock Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (3 1/2) pound whole chickens, wingtips removed 2 teaspoons salt 1 teaspoon dried tarragon 1 teaspoon paprika 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 4 teaspoons olive oil 2 lemons, thinly sliced and seeded Directions Preheat oven to 450 degrees F (230 degrees C). Line a large rimmed baking sheet with foil. Place chicken, breast side down, on a work surface. Starting at the tail end, cut along both sides of backbone with kitchen shears.</description></item><item><title>Zopf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (plus one hour rising) 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 1kg white wheat flour ½L milk 125g butter 14g dry yeast 1½T salt 1 egg Directions Cut or tear up butter and put in skillet with milk on low heat (This is so the ingredients are not too clod, temperature should not exceed 31 C). Put the flour in a large bow with the yeast, salt, milk and butter.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</guid><description>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.
Ingredients 2 cups all purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda Spices: 1 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/4 teaspoon ginger 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas) 2 eggs 1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine) 1/2 cup butter 1/4 cup crushed walnuts Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C) Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, butter, sugar) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a basic loaf of bread. The dough itself can be used however. I&amp;rsquo;ve made buns, rolls, and whole bread loafs using this same exact dough every time without a problem. Eat within 3 days as it will probably be going stale around then (as bread without preservatives and other junk should).
Ingredients 1 1/2 cups warm water 2 and 1/4 teaspoons Active Dry Yeast 1 Tsp sugar 2 Tbsp maple syrup, agave, or honey 1/2 Tbsp salt 3 3/4 cups Unbleached All-Purpose Flour (plus more for rolling / dusting) Directions Proof the yeast.</description></item></channel></rss>