<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>basic on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/basic/</link><description>Recent content in basic on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.
Ingredients 2-3 medium potatoes 4 eggs 2 long or 4 short cucumbers 3 strands of spring onions 10-12 radishes bunch of dill 2 Kefir or 1 kvass 500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat 1 mineral water (optional) Directions Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled) Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat) Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.</description></item><item><title>Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</guid><description>The success of this recipe depends entirely on the quality of the milk. The fresher the milk the better. Your regular UHT milk won&amp;rsquo;t work, because the necessary bacteria have been killed.
You do not necessary need cow milk, basically every animal milk will work, but the cheese will have vastly different (not necessarily worse) characteristics.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of milk 25g of table salt (optional with aging) 2g of rennet Some coarse salt Oil and vinegar (for aging) Directions Preparation Pour the milk and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 35°C.</description></item><item><title>Cream Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</guid><description>Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 250ml of fresh, non-UHT milk 250ml of yogurt 1lt of fresh cream 5g of table salt 6g of of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Mix the yogurt, the milk, the cream, the salt, and the sugar into a bowl. Heat the bowl to 80°C while stirring. Once the temperature has been reached, add the citric acid and mix well. Heat up to 90°C, then let it cool down until it reaches room temperature.</description></item><item><title>Greek Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h pour the newly obtained yogurt into the cheesecloth.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</guid><description>The ricotta is an Italian cheese made by cooking the whey (liquid byproduct of the cheese production), by cooking it at an high temperature (80-90°C), hence the name &amp;ldquo;ricotta&amp;rdquo;, which means &amp;ldquo;cooked again&amp;rdquo;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s typically made from the whey, you can make it directly from the milk as well.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of whey 500ml of milk (or if not using whey, 2l of milk) 10g of table salt 6g of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Preparation Pour the milk (and/or whey) and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 80°C.</description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 14 Ingredients 1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes 1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes 1 green onion 1 red onion 1 jalapeño pepper 1 handfull fresh cilantro 1 clove garlic 1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional) 1 chili pepper (optional) 1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional) Directions Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.</description></item><item><title>Tzatziki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</guid><description>
A traditional greek dip that goes well with crackers, celery and carrots or in a greek gyro. Great for parties and sharing with your family friends. Can be eaten immediately after preparation or after a few hours of being in the fridge for enhanced flavor.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Greek yogurt, 2 cups Cucumber, 3 inches Dill Garlic, 1 clove/teaspoon Olive oil, 1 teaspoon Lemon/lime or vinegar Salt and pepper Directions Finely grate the cucumber and chop the dill Strain the cucumber thoroughly with a clean kitchen towel Mash the garlic and the olive oil in a mortar and pestle Add all three to the Greek yogurt Squeeze in some lemon/lime or vinegar Add a generous pinch of salt and small pinch of pepper Optionally add some extra olive oil Stir and enjoy with your favorite snack</description></item><item><title>Aussie Snags (sausage sizzle)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</guid><description>An Australian BBQ classic tradition that is simple and very easy to make. Great for parties and outdoor events especially national events. Sometimes served at hardware chains.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: Depends Ingredients Sausages (thin) Onions (4g per sausage) Tomato sauce Mustard (optional) White sliced bread Butter Oil Wood chips (optional, fuel for smokey flavour) Directions Chop up the onions into rings Bring the sausages to the grill, turning once every 5 mins Add oil of your choice to the hotplate then add the onions Use your tongs to toss the onions until they are golden brown When the onions are golden brown turn off the hotplate When the sausages are cooked, butter the bread, then the onions, and add a sausage (optionally split) Finally tomato sauce on top</description></item><item><title>Hamburger dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</guid><description>
A delicious home made hamburger dressing 🍔
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min Ingredients 3 tbsp mayonnese or aioli 2 tbsp ketchup 1 tbsp sriracha 1 clove garlic, if using mayonnese and not aioli (optional) Directions Mix ingredients in a bowl</description></item><item><title>Mayonnaise or aioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</guid><description>Aioli is pretty much just mayonnaise with garlic, although traditional aioli only includes olive oil and garlic, and no eggs or acid. This recipe uses raw eggs, so if that is sketchy in your region use pasteurized eggs 🥚.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min Ingredients 1 whole egg or 2 egg yolks, preferably at room temperature 2.5 dl/ 1 cup neutral oil 1-2 tbsp vinegar or lemon juice 1 tbsp pickle juice (optional) 2-4 cloves of garlic for aioli, don&amp;rsquo;t include for mayonnaise 1 tsp dijon mustard (optional) Directions Place egg, vinegar, mustard a pinch of salt and pepper in a beaker or narrow and tall container.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Turkey</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkey-smoked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkey-smoked/</guid><description>Turkey, smoked on a charcoal grill
⏲️ Prep time: 120 min 🍳 Cook time: 90-180 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 4-15 Ingredients 1 turkey, 5-15 lb. (thawed) 1-2 cups whipped butter (room temperature) 2 cup chicken broth 1-4 tbsp garlic powder (optional) 1 lb mixed vegetables (carrots, potatoes, broccoli, etc.) (optional) Directions Mix garlic powder into the whipped butter. Remove giblets and other materials from the turkey cavity. Rinse the turkey and pat dry with a towel.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Mayo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</guid><description>A simple sauce that is at almost every sushi bar in the United States.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min Ingredients chili sauce (e.g Sriracha) mayonnaise sesame oil Directions Add 2 parts mayonnaise to 1 part chili sauce in a bowl. Add 1 tbsp of sesame oil for every cup of mayonnaise you use. Mix all of the ingredients together, and taste test it for more chili sauce or mayonnaise. Note This is just a basic guide, adapt this recipe to your liking.</description></item><item><title>Demi-glace</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</guid><description>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.
These are the basic proportions &amp;ndash; multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.
Ingredients 1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) low-sodium broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods) 1 1/4 oz (7g) packet unflavored, unsweetened gelatin 1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste 1 teaspoon (5mL) low-sodium soy sauce 1/2 teaspoon onion powder (very optional) Directions Put the tomato paste in a large pot, then turn the heat on medium Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown Deglaze with the broth Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume Freeze in ice cub trays</description></item><item><title>Basic Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid><description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste Directions Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</guid><description>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 5-6 Ingredients Ricotta cheese One large egg Parmesan cheese Oregano (Optional) Directions Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handful of finely grated parmesan. Add the oregano and the egg and mix. Add salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</guid><description>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette) Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil) Garlic salt Directions Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F). Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil. Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil. Season with garlic salt, to taste.</description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 mins 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended) Flour (Wheat flour recommended) Directions Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan. Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan. Stir and turn on maximum heat. Keep stirring until it becomes thick. If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough starter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</guid><description>This recipe contains instructions for sourdough starter needed for all sourdough breads. The starter can be done with either wheat flour or rye flour for rye breads. Prefer organic flours as they contain most wild yeasts.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min/day ⏲️ Wait time: 4 days Ingredients Wheat or rye flour Water Directions Day 1: mix 80g of water to 50g of flour and put a cover on the container loosely.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps) Ingredients 2 sausages 2 bacon rashers 1 egg 2 wraps milk ketchup (optional) Directions Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through. Next, fry the bacon. Next, possibly while the bacon is frying, crack an egg into a bowl, add a dash of milk and whisk it Then, put the egg mixture into the microwave for a minute, take it out and whisk it again, do this twice again or until the scrambled egg is ready.</description></item><item><title>Classic béchamel sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid><description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min Ingredients 5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg Directions Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description></item><item><title>No-knead pizza dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</guid><description>Perfect for pan pizza in an 11 inch iron skillet.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 7-24 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 pizza Ingredients 200g flour 2g instant yeast (dry) 5g salt 5g olive oil 140g luke warm water Directions Mix dry ingredients in a bowl. Mix in olive oil and water. No need for hands or kneading! Cover bowl air tight, and let it sit in room temperature for at least 7 hours, and up to 24 hours.</description></item><item><title>Pan pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</guid><description>Pan pizza gives a thick and crispy crust 🍕. For this recipe, start early with the dough, preferably the night before. It takes a lot of time, but little effort and gives a fantastic result.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hours Ingredients no-knead pizza dough pizza sauce cheese olive oil pepperoni (optional) mushrooms (optional) pineapple (optional) &amp;hellip;really whatever you like (optional) Directions Preheat oven to max temp.</description></item><item><title>Pizza sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0.5-2 hours Ingredients 400g canned tomatoes, preferebly skinned and whole 150g tomato puré 1 medium sized onion olive oil garlic oregano chili pepper (optional) Directions Dice onion and fry in olive oil on medium heat. Add chopped garlic and chili pepper (optional) for some minutes. Mix in tomato puré, salt, pepper, and oregano. Cook until puré gets oily. Add canned tomatoes, and crush with spatula.</description></item><item><title>Chimichanga</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</guid><description>Essentially, just a fried burrito. Use whatever your favorite filling is.
⏲️ Prep time: 120min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Servings: 4 Ingredients taco-meat 1 Onion Diced Tomatoes 1 Bell Pepper Burrito sized tortilla Plain Greek Yogurt or Sour Cream Any other vegetables you want Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers, tomatoes, and onions and saute Add in meat. Season and cook until browned or fully cooked through Warm your tortilla and place small layer of yogurt, cheese, and filling on the bottom half of the tortilla Wrap by folding bottom over filling, folding sides in, and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties
Ingredients 1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio Onion, chopped or powder (optional) Garlic, chopped or powder (optional) Directions Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil. Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature. Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings. Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.</description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.
Ingredients Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended) Mayonnaise Horseradish Worchestershire sauce Paprika Dijon mustard Onion powder Pickle relish (optional) Directions Put ingredients into bowl or cup. Mix together thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Baked Salmon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-salmon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-salmon/</guid><description>Simple method for making a good serving of salmon. Goes well with just about anything.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 19 min Ingredients Salmon Steaks Red Pepper Flakes Lemon Juice Butter Cooking oil / spray Aluminum Foil Directions Season salmon with salt, black pepper, and red pepper to taste. Spray or rub in cooking oil on aluminum foil and place on cookie sheet or in baking pan. Squeeze lemon juice and place a teaspoon of butter on each salmon steak.</description></item><item><title>Cooked Chickpeas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</guid><description>Easy recipe for cooked chickpeas. Can be add to salads, rice, or almost anything else.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 can chickpeas / garbanzo beans, drained 1 tbsp olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper Directions Heat oil in pan. Add chickpeas and seasonings. Cook over medium-high heat for 10-15 minutes. Salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Fajita Seasoning</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</guid><description>Simple seasoning mix similar to Old El Paso. Can be used for any Mexican dishes or plain meats.
Ingredients 1/2 tsp Garlic Powder 1/2 tsp Onion Powder 1/2 tsp Paprika 1/2 tsp Smoked Paprika 1/2 tsp Ground Cumin 1/2 tsp Ground Coriander 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Salt 1 tsp Brown Sugar 1.5 tsp Chili Powder Directions Mix seasonings in a bowl. Adjust amounts depending on how much is needed.</description></item><item><title>Lemon juice salad dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</guid><description>A dressing that goes well on lettuce or any other mixed greens.
Ingredients Lemon juice from half a lemon Tablespoon of olive oil Clove of garlic Directions Combine lemon juice and oil in small bowl. Add salt and pepper to taste. Add the garlic, pressed or finely minced. Mix well before adding to salad.</description></item><item><title>Pickled Red Onions</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</guid><description>A good way to use up older red onions and goes great with just about anything.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings Varies Ingredients Red Onions Vinegar Water Directions Cut onion in half and slice root to stem and place in a jar Mix equal parts of water and vinegar in a pot and bring to a boil. Add salt to taste As soon as it begins to boil, turn off and pour the mix into the jar and allow to cool.</description></item><item><title>Simple Tuna Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 (7 oz) can white tuna, drained 6 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 tablespoons sweet pickle relish A pinch of garlic powder (optional) 2 tablespoons white vinegar or lemon juice (optional) 1 cup shredded cheese (optional) 1 chopped hard-boiled egg (optional) Directions In a medium bowl, stir together tuna, mayonnaise, and relish. Add optional ingredients like vinegar, cheese or hard-boiled eggs if wanted.</description></item><item><title>Spatchcock Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (3 1/2) pound whole chickens, wingtips removed 2 teaspoons salt 1 teaspoon dried tarragon 1 teaspoon paprika 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 4 teaspoons olive oil 2 lemons, thinly sliced and seeded Directions Preheat oven to 450 degrees F (230 degrees C). Line a large rimmed baking sheet with foil. Place chicken, breast side down, on a work surface. Starting at the tail end, cut along both sides of backbone with kitchen shears.</description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>Ingredients One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas) 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina) 1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons&amp;rsquo; worth 1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry) 1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding) 1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it) 1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving Fresh parsley (optional for serving) Directions Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts Directions Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350°F (175°C) for ten to twelve minutes While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds. Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Simple sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid><description>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.
Ingredients Tomato sauce. Mayonaise Directions Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity.</description></item><item><title>Ketchup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</guid><description>Ketchup/Catsup Ingredients 2 1/2 quart (15 to 17 medium-sized) sliced tomatoes 1 large garlic clove, chopped 1 cup vinegar 1/4 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup sugar 3 - inch piece stick cinnamon 1 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon paprika 1 teaspoon whole cloves a dash cayenne pepper Directions Simmer together tomatoes and onion for 20 to 30 minutes; press through a sieve. Put the cinnamon, cloves, and garlic loosely in a clean, thin, white cloth; tie top tightly; add to vinegar and simmer 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h store in the fridge</description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</guid><description>Here is a simple pizza dough recipe. Basically you use a 2/1 ratio of flour/liquid. If you use other flour like rye, you may need more liquid.
Ingredients 400g flour (basic wheat flour) 200ml lukewarm water 1 pkg (7g) dry yeast 1 spoon olive oil 1 teaspoon salt a teensy bit of sugar (to feed the yeast) Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough. Let it rest for about 30 minutes somewhere lukewarm Add some flour to a table and roll the dough out there.</description></item><item><title>Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a basic loaf of bread. The dough itself can be used however. I&amp;rsquo;ve made buns, rolls, and whole bread loafs using this same exact dough every time without a problem. Eat within 3 days as it will probably be going stale around then (as bread without preservatives and other junk should).
Ingredients 1 1/2 cups warm water 2 and 1/4 teaspoons Active Dry Yeast 1 Tsp sugar 2 Tbsp maple syrup, agave, or honey 1/2 Tbsp salt 3 3/4 cups Unbleached All-Purpose Flour (plus more for rolling / dusting) Directions Proof the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Stock or Bone Broth</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</guid><description>Chicken stock, or &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; is not a final dish in itself, but is used in many soups and other dishes to add great taste to something otherwise very simple. While it is easy to make, it sells for very expensive in the store, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to know to make by yourself since it can be done very cheaply.
Ingredients a whole raw chicken with organs removed (Drumsticks or thighs alone might suffice if a whole chicken is unavailable.</description></item><item><title>Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid><description>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the homepage.
Ingredients eggs butter cheese(optional) milk (optional) Directions Boiled eggs Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged). Place eggs in water. Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency (about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium runny, 10+ for hard boiled).</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea. Bring water to a rolling boil.</description></item><item><title>Pasta sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid><description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced) Directions Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crushed and sliced garlic until translucent. Add San Marzano tomatoes, include the liquids from the can if possible.</description></item><item><title>Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</guid><description>Rice is easy to make in any pot. The simple use of different spices can change its use or what it accents.
Ingredients rice chicken stock (optional) onion or garlic (optional) lime and cilantro (optional, for a Mexican taste) Directions Add some amount of rice to a pot that has a cover. Add twice as much liquid to the same pot. Water is typical, but for extra flavor, use stock or broth.</description></item></channel></rss>