<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spicy on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/spicy/</link><description>Recent content in spicy on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/spicy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spicy Sausage Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</guid><description>A delicious spicy pasta dish, super easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a student and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap for how much food you get. I found it in a newspaper a while back and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it with you guys because it&amp;rsquo;s my favourite meal. I also like to drink the excess red wine while cooking which adds to the enjoyment of cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 red onions, chopped Olive oil 6 spicy Italian sausages 1 sprig rosemary, needles finely chopped 1 red chilli, deseeded and diced A large glass of red wine (approx.</description></item><item><title>Honey Sriracha Chicken Thighs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</guid><description>This recipe yields a batch of relatively spicy chicken thighs. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy foods, you can add more honey and less sriracha. Conversely, if you like spicy foods, consider a 1:1 ratio of sriracha and honey.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40-45 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 5-6 bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs 1 tablespoon olive oil 1/3 cup honey 2 tablespoons sriracha hot sauce 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt 1/2 teaspoon black pepper Sesame seeds as a garnish (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 350°F Season the chicken.</description></item><item><title>Sardine Cakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</guid><description>Can be served with a Spicy Yogurt Sauce as Tapas or Hors D’Oeuvres.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🧊 Chill time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 15 Ingredients Sardine Fish Cakes 2 tins sardines (~4oz) ½ cup mayonnaise ½ cup Panko breadcrumbs 2 teaspoons Old Bay seasoning 1 egg lemon juice (optional) Spicy Yogurt Sauce ½ cup plain yogurt (whole milk) 1 tablespoon sriracha 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce minced garlic (optional) Directions Remove sardines from tin, reserving oil, and place fish in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Yibin Burning Noodles</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yibin-burning-noodles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yibin-burning-noodles/</guid><description>This is a dry noodle dish from the town of Yibin in Sichuan, China.
Ingredients Yibin Chili Oil Sichuan ground chilies, 1/3 cup Roasted rapeseed oil (caizi you) or Chinese peanut oil, 2/3 cup Peeled and smashed ginger, 2 inches Cassia bark (or cinnamon stick), 2 inches Star anise, 2 Chinese black cardamom (optional), 1 Sichuan peppercorn, 1 tsp Roughly chopped walnut pieces, 2 tbsp High-quality melted pork lard, 1/3 cup Noodles Fresh alkaline noodles, 150g Yibin Chili Oil, 2 tbsp Light soy sauce, 1 tbsp White sesame oil, 1 tbsp Toasted yacai, 2 tbsp Mixed toasted crushed peanuts/sesame, 2 tbsp Sliced scallion greens, 2 tbsp MSG, 1/4 tbsp Directions Yibin Chili Oil Add ground chilies to a heat-proof jar or bowl.</description></item><item><title>Lenten Lentil Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</guid><description>Simple green lentil recipe. Suitable for Lent.
Prep time: 5 min Cook time: 30-35 min Servings : 2 Ingredients 200 g (7 oz) green lentils 50 g (1¾ oz) vermicelli 1 tsp curry powder ½ tsp paprika powder ½ tsp cinnamon powder ½ tsp ground sumac Directions Thoroughly rinse the lentils and drain the water. Put the lentils in the pot, and add 1 L (0.26 gal) of water. Bring to a boil, and gently boil for about 15-20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Coriander Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Boneless chicken marinated in a gravy of yoghurt and coriander
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 500g boneless chicken breast 250g fat free yoghurt 250g coriander leaves Mustard oil / Sunflower oil Sugar Ginger Garlic 2 medium onions Green chillies Garam masala 2/3 Cardamom pods 1 Bayleaf 1 Cinnamom stick Directions Cut the boneless chicken into small bite sized pieces. In a mixer, put 250g coriander leaves, 2/3 green chillies, 250g yoghurt, 20g ginger, 9/10 cloves of garlic, 2 medium sized onions and mix well.</description></item><item><title>Hoisin Pork Belly</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</guid><description>Melt-in-mouth fatty pork in a sweet and spicy glaze.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 15 mins 🍽 Servings: 2 Ingredients 400g high fat pork belly (no skin) large thumb of ginger 4 cloves of garlic 1 scotch bonnet chili 2 tbsp ketchup 2 tbsp hoisin sauce 2 tbsp honey 2 tsp sesame oil 1 spring onion Directions Cut pork belly into 1 inch cubes. In a small frying pan place pork cubes fattiest side down in dry pan, put gas on lowest level possible flame, cover with lid.</description></item><item><title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients 250g cubes paneer 1 onion 1 capsicum 200ml tomato puree 1 tsp red chilli powder 1 tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp coriander powder 1/2 tsp garam masala powder 100ml thick yogurt 1 tsp fenugreek powder dry fenugreek leaves cardamom cumin seeds shaved ginger 20ml garlic paste 1 bowl corn Directions Take a glass container, and mix the cubed paneers with half a tea spoon of red chilli powder, turmeric powder, coriander powder, garam masala powder, fenugreek powder, and 50g yogurt.</description></item><item><title>Nashville Chicken Sandwich</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</guid><description>If you love spicy foods and chicken then this Nashville Hot Chicken sandwich recipe is just for you. It takes some time with prepping and process but when you take that first bite all the effort will be worth it. It’s unlike any other fried chicken recipe that includes double frying your chicken and using the same cooking oil from your fry as a sauce for the Nashville Hot Chicken spice.</description></item></channel></rss>