<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uzbek on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/uzbek/</link><description>Recent content in Uzbek on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/uzbek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pilaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Popular central asian and middle eastern dish.
High in nutrition, designed to be prepared and eaten communally.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>150ml cooking oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1kg long grain &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/rice">rice&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1.5kg meat (lamb or any other kind of meat)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500g carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>raisins, cardamom, paprika, coriander, cinnamon, cumin, turmeric (all optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put the cooking oil in a cauldron and heat it until the oil is boiling, add a head of onion until it is black, then throw it out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Throw coarsely chopped meat into the cauldron and let it boil until it&amp;rsquo;s golden brown, then add a pinch of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the chopped onions, then wait 2 minutes and add the sliced carrots, boil for another 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add 500 ml of water diluted with tomato paste, boil for 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rinse the rice and put it into the cauldron but do not mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add another 500 ml of water diluted with tomato paste and wait until it is boiling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce the heat to minimum, then add two table spoons of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Close the cauldron and leave it on low heat for 1.5-2 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 hour before it is ready(or when you can&amp;rsquo;t see water above the rice), add the garlic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can now turn over the rice if it is undercooked and add some raisins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep boiling until all water is evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>