<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spanish on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/spanish/</link><description>Recent content in spanish on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/spanish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pulpo a la gallega</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 to 40 min 🍽️ Servings: Ingredients 1 octopus (1.7 to 2kg) Potatoes 2 bay leaves Sweet and spicy red pepper Salt oil Directions Boil water along with salt and the bay leaves Once the water is boiling, introduce the octopus 3 times by putting it on and taking it out, then let it cook for 35 to 40 minutes by puncturing it to see whether it is already soft or we need to leave it a little longer turn off the fire and let it rest for 20 minutes more with the same water.</description></item><item><title>Apple Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</guid><description>Baked chicken with apples and onions. Suprinsingly good and simple combination.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Chicken breast or similar. Onions. Nuez moscada. Apples. Potatoes. Cream or creme fraiche. Salt. Pepper. One glass (33c) of wine or cognac. Directions Heat the oven to 200C and prepare an oven tray. Mix the chicken with nuez moscada, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Tarta de Santiago</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</guid><description>Delicious Spanish almond cake or famously known as tarta de Santiago. This is a cake from Galicia and it is super easy to make, with only 3 main ingredients. I always feel this type of cake is just perfect for the holiday season.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 3 eggs ¾ cup sugar (150 gr) 1 ½ cup almond meal (150 gr) ½ teaspoon cinnamon powder ¼ teaspoon salt Zest of 1 lemon Zest of 1 clementine Icing sugar, for dusting on top Directions Add eggs and sugar into a bowl and whisk until the mixture turns pale.</description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying Directions Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter). It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min Ingredients Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf. Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.) Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.</description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 White onion 1 Eggplant Olive oil Egg (optional) Directions Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring) Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long (Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top (Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg.</description></item><item><title>Sopa de Lentejas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</guid><description>Traditional-spanish dish. Typical spanish!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 1 carrot, chopped 1 green bell pepper, chopped 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 large onion, chopped 1 cup dry brown lentils, soaked overnight and drained 2 plum tomatoes, chopped 2 cups water, or as needed 1 bay leaf 1 tbsp extra-virgin olive oil 1/2 tsp of paprika 1/4 spicy chorizo (optional) Directions Heat olive oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 8 free-range eggs 1 kg of potatoes 1 white onion Extra virgin olive oil Directions Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes. Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir. Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.</description></item></channel></rss>