<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spanish on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/spanish/</link><description>Recent content in Spanish on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/spanish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pulpo a la gallega</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/pulpo-gallega.webp" alt="pulpo a la gallega">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 to 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 octopus (1.7 to 2kg)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 bay leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweet and spicy red pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Boil water along with salt and the bay leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the water is boiling, introduce the octopus 3 times by putting it on and taking it out, then let it cook for 35 to 40 minutes by puncturing it to see whether it is already soft or we need to leave it a little longer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>turn off the fire and let it rest for 20 minutes more with the same water. Meanwhile we will have boiled the potatoes with skin for about 25 minutes depending on the size.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will remove the octopus from the water and let it cool, and once it is cold, we will cut it in slices with scissors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To assemble the dish we will laminate the potatoes by placing them at the bottom of the plate, on top and we will put the octopus slices seasoning it with salt, the sweet and spicy red pepper and a good squirt of olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Apple Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/apple_chicken.webp" alt="Applechicken">
Baked chicken with apples and onions. Suprinsingly good and simple combination.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chicken breast or similar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nuez moscada.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Apples.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cream or creme fraiche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One glass (33c) of wine or cognac.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat the oven to 200C and prepare an oven tray.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the chicken with nuez moscada, salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the center of the apples, fill with nuez moscada and butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the chicken in the oven tray.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the chicken, onions and apple in the oven tray.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook in the oven for 40 min.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the chicken is the oven prepare mushed potatoes. First you boil them until they are soft (keep the skin on). Once they are soft, peel them. Then mush them with a fork and add milk or creme fraiche.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the wine or the cognac. Cook until the chicken is well cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tarta de Santiago</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tarta-de-santiago.webp" alt="Tarta de Santiago">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Delicious Spanish almond cake or famously known as tarta de Santiago. This is a cake from Galicia and it is super easy to make, with only 3 main ingredients. I always feel this type of cake is just perfect for the holiday season.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 8&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Â¾ cup sugar (150 gr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Â½ cup almond meal (150 gr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Â½ teaspoon cinnamon powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Â¼ teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zest of 1 lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zest of 1 clementine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Icing sugar, for dusting on top&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add eggs and sugar into a bowl and whisk until the mixture turns pale.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the rest of the ingredients, except for icing sugar and using a spatula, gently fold everything until well combine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour batter into a 7 inch (18 cm) springform pan that has been buttered and floured. Bake in a preheated oven at 360ÂºF (180ÂºC) for 40 minutes or until golden brown and fully cooked.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool completely. Place the Santiago cross cut out on top and dust generous amount of icing sugar all over the cake. Carefully remove the cut out. Slice and serve, enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>As I mentioned earlier, this cake is dusted with icing sugar with an imprint of Santiago&amp;rsquo;s cross on its top surface. You can also make an imprint of a scallop shell. Or with no imprint at all. Your choice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recommend serving with corn bread.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chorizo Sausage(s)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ginger&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Paprika, 2 Tsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cumin, Parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Juice from whole Lemon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chickpeas, 400g ( drained )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter and sunflower oil, for frying&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow to boil for 5 or so min. Add Parsley and then salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/torrijas.webp" alt="Torrijas">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter).
It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 1 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grated lemon rind (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mull the milk with cinnamon and a bit of sugar (not too much, the milk is already sweet). Add the lemon rind if you want.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool down the milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the milk is cooling, beat the eggs and heat up half a pan of olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the dry bread in slices. Soak it in the milk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coat the bread soaking it in the beaten eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry the soaked &amp;amp; coated bread with the heated oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally sprinkle some sugar onto the Torrijas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy when they are cooled down. Don&amp;rsquo;t eat too much, it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy resisting!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10-15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 White onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Eggplant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Egg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg. If it breaks just scramble it, the recipe doesn&amp;rsquo;t call for anything fancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can serve the dish with that oil (provided it is not burnt) or keep it for cooking other stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Sopa de Lentejas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/lentejas.webp" alt="Lentejas">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditional-spanish dish. Typical spanish!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4-6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 carrot, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 green bell pepper, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large onion, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup dry brown lentils, soaked overnight and drained&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 plum tomatoes, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups water, or as needed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bay leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tbsp extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp of paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 spicy chorizo (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat olive oil in a large pot over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the onion, carrot, and bell pepper; cook and stir until vegetables begin to soften, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in the garlic, tomatoes, chorizo and bay leaf; cook about 4 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add lentils and water (water should be about an inch deeper than the level of the lentils).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a boil over high heat. Reduce heat to low; simmer, uncovered, until lentils are just cooked, 15 to 20 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spanish-tortilla.webp" alt="Spanish Tortilla">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 free-range eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 kg of potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potato slices already salted and let them cook for approximately 20 minutes over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the potatoes are frying, beat the eggs in a bowl. Peel and cut the onion as finely as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add olive oil in another frying pan and slowly fry the onion until it gets a slightly golden color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the onion and add it to the bowl with the beaten egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the potatoes from the pan with a slotted spoon, draining the oil away as much as possible, and add them to the bowl with the onion and egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the mixture rest for at least 5 minutes so all the flavors come together. Give it a very gentle stir from time to time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the oil from the pan you used to fry the potatoes. Use the pan to cook the mixture over medium-high fire for about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip it over with the help of a big plate and cook the other side for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Things like the slicing of the potato, the amount of salt and how curdled is the inner part of the tortilla depend on your own taste. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to experiment!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>