<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fasting on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/fasting/</link><description>Recent content in fasting on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/fasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</guid><description>Easy recipe to expand - black turtle beans and chickpeas also work well here.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1/3 cup Salad Oil (olive oil, canola, or sunflower) 1/2 cup Cider Vinegar 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Pepper 1/4 cup Sugar 1/2 tsp Celery Seed 1 can Cut Green Beans 1 can Cut Waxed Beans 1 can Red Kidney Beans 1 Carrot, thinly sliced 1 small Onion, chopped 1 Bell Pepper Directions Put dressing ingredients in a large salad bowl an whisk until blended.</description></item><item><title>Fall Vegetable and Chickpea Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fall-vegetable-and-chickpea-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fall-vegetable-and-chickpea-curry/</guid><description>Can be served over rice or on its own with a dollop of yogurt.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 Tbsp Butter 1 Onion, chopped 2 Tbsp Thai Red Curry Paste 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 1 large Sweet Potato, peeled and cut into half-inch chunks 1 small Zucchini, cut into half-inch chunks 1 Red Pepper, cut into half-inch pieces 28 oz can Chickpeas, rinsed and drained 1 Lime 3 Tbsp Wheat Flour 1 1/2 cup Milk 1/2 cup Fresh Coriander, chopped Directions In a large non-stick frying pan, heat butter over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Gypsy Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</guid><description>The vegetables used in this soup are flexible. Any orange vegetable can be combined with green. Such as peas or green beans to replace peppers, or carrots and/or squash to replace the sweet potato.
⏲️ Prep time: 40 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 2 cup Chopped Onion 2 cloves Chopped Garlic 2 cup Sweet Potatoes, chopped and peeled 1/2 cup Chopped Celery 1 cup Chopped Fresh Tomatoes 3/4 cup Chopped Sweet Peppers 1-1/2 cup Cooked Chickpeas 3 cup Stock or Water 2 tsp Paprika 1 tsp Turmeric 1 tsp Basil 1 tsp Salt dash Cinnamon dash Cayenne 1 Bay Leaf 1 Tbsp Tamari Soy Sauce Directions In a soup kettle or large saucepan, saute onions garlic, celery, and sweet potatoes in olive oil for about five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Ray Peat's Carrot Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</guid><description>A raw carrot salad to support digestive, hormone and thyroid health
&amp;ldquo;Endotoxin formed in the bowel can block respiration and cause hormone imbalances contributing to instability of the nerves, so it is helpful to optimize bowel flora, for example with a carrot salad; a dressing of vinegar, coconut oil and olive oil, carried into the intestine by the carrot fiber, suppresses bacterial growth while stimulating healing of the wall of the intestine.</description></item><item><title>Italian Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2.5 - 3.25 hr 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients 600g or 5 cups bread flour (or all-purpose if not available) 1 packet (appr. 2 1/4 tsp or 7g) active dry yeast olive oil for greasing Directions Follow directions on the packet to activate yeast in a bowl large enough for mixing the dough Add enough water for a total of 400g or 1 3/4 cups (i.</description></item><item><title>Lenten Lentil Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</guid><description>Simple green lentil recipe. Suitable for Lent.
Prep time: 5 min Cook time: 30-35 min Servings : 2 Ingredients 200 g (7 oz) green lentils 50 g (1¾ oz) vermicelli 1 tsp curry powder ½ tsp paprika powder ½ tsp cinnamon powder ½ tsp ground sumac Directions Thoroughly rinse the lentils and drain the water. Put the lentils in the pot, and add 1 L (0.</description></item><item><title>Tofu Stir Fry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-stir-fry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-stir-fry/</guid><description>A vegetarian dish that is easy to make and very flavorful. Goes well with rice or noodles
Serves 3 to 5.
Cooking time: ~10 to 20 minutes
Ingredients One block of extra firm tofu Three eggs Vegetables per your choice, recommendations include: Sugar snap peas Chopped cabbage Sliced carrots Broccoli Cauliflower Soy or teriyaki sauce 2 tbsp minced garlic Coconut oil Directions (Optional) Deep freeze tofu at least 24 hours prior and then thaw.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Alla Norma</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid><description>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 aubergines (900g) 300g spaghetti 100ml olive oil 5 garlic cloves, minced 1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes) 2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon caster sugar Fresh basil Directions Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</description></item><item><title>Lenten Chili</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-chili/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-chili/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 large onion, chopped 3 cloves garlic, minced 4 15oz cans of kidney beans (or 6 cups cooked beans) 1 29oz large can tomato sauce (or 4 cups fresh tomato sauce) 1 15oz can diced tomatoes (or 1 large diced tomato with skin removed) 1/2 can of sweet corn 1 cup cooked white or brown rice 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp smoked paprika 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp onion powder 1 tbsp chili powder 1 tbsp crushed red pepper 2-3 tbsp olive oil Directions Chop the large onion and mince the garlic cloves.</description></item><item><title>Cooked Chickpeas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</guid><description>Easy recipe for cooked chickpeas. Can be add to salads, rice, or almost anything else.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 can chickpeas / garbanzo beans, drained 1 tbsp olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper Directions Heat oil in pan. Add chickpeas and seasonings. Cook over medium-high heat for 10-15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Fajita Seasoning</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</guid><description>Simple seasoning mix similar to Old El Paso. Can be used for any Mexican dishes or plain meats.
Ingredients 1/2 tsp Garlic Powder 1/2 tsp Onion Powder 1/2 tsp Paprika 1/2 tsp Smoked Paprika 1/2 tsp Ground Cumin 1/2 tsp Ground Coriander 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Salt 1 tsp Brown Sugar 1.5 tsp Chili Powder Directions Mix seasonings in a bowl. Adjust amounts depending on how much is needed.</description></item><item><title>Lemon juice salad dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</guid><description>A dressing that goes well on lettuce or any other mixed greens.
Ingredients Lemon juice from half a lemon Tablespoon of olive oil Clove of garlic Directions Combine lemon juice and oil in small bowl. Add salt and pepper to taste. Add the garlic, pressed or finely minced. Mix well before adding to salad.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli with Ginger and Garlic Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</guid><description>Asian inspired broccoli dish with tasty sauce. Sauce can be used for all kinds of Asian inspired sauted vegetables.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1-2 Broccoli (fresh best, frozen works too) Minced garlic (1 tablespoon) Minced ginger (1 tablespoon) Sherry or regular white wine (you cook with what you drink with!) (1 tablespoon) Soy sauce (1-2 tablespoon) Directions Cut broccoli into little flourettes (hold the broccoli upside down and cut around the stem with a pairing knife) Fill your pan (or wok) around half inch (1.</description></item><item><title>Naan Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</guid><description>A curry serves best with naan that is unleavened bread. Traditionally made in ‘Tandoor or clay oven' but at home, we will be making it in the oven and/or on the stovetop. Naan is not eaten solely but acts as assortments with meat, veggies, or egg items.
⏲️ Prep time: 90 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients All-purpose flour 3 cups Active dry yeast 1 tbsp Sugar 2 tbsp Warm Milk 1 cup Butter melted 2 tbsp Oil - little to grease Directions Put the yeast and sugar to warm milk in a large mixing bowl and stir well.</description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>Ingredients One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas) 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina) 1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons' worth 1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry) 1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding) 1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it) 1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving Fresh parsley (optional for serving) Directions Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts Directions Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350°F (175°C) for ten to twelve minutes While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds. Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed Round Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</guid><description>Round Squash, Zucchini, or Courguettes can be served as main dish (2 servings per person) or as accompaniment. The amount of squash should be adjusted according to their size. This recipe uses ones the size of a fist.
⏲️ Prep time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Onions 1 Carrot 4 Round squash 1 Cup of rice 100gr of Cheese (optional) Directions Cook the rice.</description></item><item><title>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 3 bananas 100 g / ½ cups butter 150 g / ¾ cups sugar 2 eggs 1½ tsp. cooking powder 260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour 50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate 50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate some vanilla sugar (optional) Directions Peel the bananas and mush them together. Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sweet Potato Fries Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</guid><description>A simple, tasty, and healthy carb based snack.
Ingredients 1-2 Sweet Pototoes (try different types) Olive Oil Cinnamon Rosemary (optional) Directions Set oven heat to 425°F (220°C). Grab a pan and put a layer of parchment paper (or aluminum foil) on it. Chop the potato(es) on your cutting board with a sharp knife throwing them onto the pan. Drizzle the fries with olive oil. Toss the fries with clean hands to coat the fries in olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:
2 Hass avocados 1/4 medium onion 1 small tomato Cilantro 1 lime And of course, some totopos to eat with.
Directions Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Fried Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients Potatoes Oil or Crème Fraîche Onions Directions Peel and cut the potatoes to desired size. Cut the onions. Put a bit of Oil or Crème Fraîche in your pan. Put both the potatoes and the onions into the pan. Cook them until they&amp;rsquo;re golden-brown. Enjoy</description></item><item><title>Ketchup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</guid><description>Ketchup/Catsup Ingredients 2 1/2 quart (15 to 17 medium-sized) sliced tomatoes 1 large garlic clove, chopped 1 cup vinegar 1/4 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup sugar 3 - inch piece stick cinnamon 1 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon paprika 1 teaspoon whole cloves a dash cayenne pepper Directions Simmer together tomatoes and onion for 20 to 30 minutes; press through a sieve. Put the cinnamon, cloves, and garlic loosely in a clean, thin, white cloth; tie top tightly; add to vinegar and simmer 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Maque Choux</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/maque-choux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/maque-choux/</guid><description>An old cajun recipe for stewed corn &amp;amp; tomatoes. Enjoyable at any time of year, but I love to make it on hot summer afternoons as a side to a sausage dish. Pairs well with brown ales.
Ingredients A little sugar A good bit of grease (about a handful) Handful of chopped onion Handful of chopped bell pepper Eight ears of corn Handful of chopped tomatoes Salt &amp;amp; Pepper (to taste) Directions Clean the corn and cut lengthwise about a thumbnail (1/4 in) from the top and scrape down using the soft end of a knife (to keep the juices).</description></item><item><title>Refried Beans</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</guid><description>One of my favorite dishes that works either as an appetizer or side dish is refried beans. A classic from Mexican cuisine, that is best eaten with some totopos, or tortilla chips.
Ingredients As usual, the ingredients here are for about two adult portions:
400-500g can of pre-cooked beans 1/4 onion 3-4 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika 2-4 spoonfuls butter Cooking oil (can be olive oil) Directions Add the oil and the butter to the frying pan and heat to medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</guid><description>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.
Ingredients 2 cups all purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda Spices: 1 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/4 teaspoon ginger 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas) 2 eggs 1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine) 1/2 cup butter 1/4 cup crushed walnuts Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C) Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, butter, sugar) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Potato and Eggplant (Aubergine) Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</guid><description>A simple and tasty curry that is easy to customise.
Ingredients 1 large eggplant (aubergine) 2 medium potatoes 3 tbsp olive oil 2 onions (finely sliced) 2 garlic cloves (crushed) 2 tsp garam masala 2 tsp turmeric 2 tsp ground coriander 400 ml can chopped tomatoes 400 ml can coconut milk rice Optional extras carrots red peppers (capsicums) paneer Directions Heat the oven to approximately 200 °C (392 °F).</description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil Directions Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat.</description></item><item><title>Sauerkraut</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sauerkraut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sauerkraut/</guid><description>Sauerkraut is a based lacto-fermented food that is healthy and has a long shelf live.
Ingredients 1 head of cabbage 2-4% sea salt by cabbage weight Directions Prepare and clean as many glass jars as you think you&amp;rsquo;ll need. Chop or shred cabbage and rinse under cold water. Sprinkle with salt. Knead the cabbage with clean hands for about 10 minutes until there is enough liquid to cover it.</description></item><item><title>Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a basic loaf of bread. The dough itself can be used however. I&amp;rsquo;ve made buns, rolls, and whole bread loafs using this same exact dough every time without a problem. Eat within 3 days as it will probably be going stale around then (as bread without preservatives and other junk should).
Ingredients 1 1/2 cups warm water 2 and 1/4 teaspoons Active Dry Yeast 1 Tsp sugar 2 Tbsp maple syrup, agave, or honey 1/2 Tbsp salt 3 3/4 cups Unbleached All-Purpose Flour (plus more for rolling / dusting) Directions Proof the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Gnocchi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</guid><description>Gnocchi is a pasta based on potato, making it a less bloating alternative to other kinds of pasta. They are substantial and can be roasted in butter and other ingredients.
Ingredients potatoes flour tomato parmesan butter sage or oregano or thyme Directions Boil potatoes (with their skins) until mashable. Slice potatoes in two and scoop them out of their skin. Mash with a potato-masher while adding kosher salt.</description></item><item><title>Oats</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid><description>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do with oats.
We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.
Ingredients oats water pinch of salt Pick and choose additional ingredients:</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea.</description></item><item><title>Pasta sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid><description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced) Directions Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crushed and sliced garlic until translucent.</description></item><item><title>Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</guid><description>Rice is easy to make in any pot. The simple use of different spices can change its use or what it accents.
Ingredients rice chicken stock (optional) onion or garlic (optional) lime and cilantro (optional, for a Mexican taste) Directions Add some amount of rice to a pot that has a cover. Add twice as much liquid to the same pot. Water is typical, but for extra flavor, use stock or broth.</description></item></channel></rss>