<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eggs on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/</link><description>Recent content in eggs on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tajine Maadnous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</guid><description>Similar to an Italian frittata or Spanish tortilla, Tunisian tajine maadnous is an easy &amp;amp; delicious egg omelette filled with chicken, parsley, and spices.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 1 lb chicken breasts diced 1 medium onion chopped 1 large potato peeled and diced 1 cup water 1 small bunch parsley (about 1.5 cups, chopped, loosely packed) 8 large eggs 6 oz cheese 2 tbsp olive oil Spice Blend 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp coriander 1 tsp turmeric 1 tsp salt 1/2 tsp paprika or cayenne pepper if you want some heat 1/2 tsp black pepper 1/4 tsp caraway 1/4 tsp thyme 1/4 tsp cinnamon Directions Mix the spices together (grinding any whole spices if necessary) and set them aside.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Quiche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 60 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 3/4 cups Flour 1 cup + 2 1/2 Tbsp Butter, divided Up to 1/3 cup Water, chilled 1/2 cup Onion, finely chopped 14 ounces Smoked Salmon, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Chives, chopped 1 clove Garlic, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Basil, chopped 5 whole Eggs 1 cup Milk 1 cup Whipping Cream Directions Combine all pastry ingredients in a food processor (mix flour and butter, then add water gradually while mixing).</description></item><item><title>Tahini short bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</guid><description>This short bread recipe uses sesame paste called Tahini, a minimal amount of white sugar is necessary in order to get a crunchy/caramelized short-bread. For better results, a food processor is welcome for this recipe. IMPORTANT Butter is what makes this recipe complicated when cooking the dough, make sure it is not liquid or that the room is not to warm and make sure that the shortbreads are cold before putting in the oven.</description></item><item><title>Soleier (pickled eggs)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</guid><description>Soleier are a german pub dish. They are typically enjoyed between two beers.
⏲️ Preparation time: 10min 🍳 Cook time: 10min 🍽️ Servings: 10 Ingredients peels of five onions 10 eggs 2 loorber leaves 3 cloves 4 allspice 1Tbsp peppercorns 1Tbsp caraway seeds 1Tbsp mustard seeds 1tsp of Szechuan pepper (optional) 1tsp lovage (optional) 1tsp nutmeg (optional) 100mL vinegar 3 cloves of garlic Directions Put 750mL of water and the peels of five onions in a pot and let them cook for five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps) Ingredients 2 sausages 2 bacon rashers 1 egg 2 wraps milk ketchup (optional) Directions Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through. Next, fry the bacon.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 8 free-range eggs 1 kg of potatoes 1 white onion Extra virgin olive oil Directions Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes. Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir. Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.</description></item><item><title>Frittata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid><description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6 Ingredients 4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer Directions Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets Ingredients 2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 3/4 cup milk, scalded 1 tablespoon butter, or margarine 4 egg yolks, beaten until thick 4 egg whites, beaten stiff Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet) Directions Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.</description></item><item><title>Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid><description>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the homepage.
Ingredients eggs butter cheese(optional) milk (optional) Directions Boiled eggs Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged). Place eggs in water. Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency (about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium runny, 10+ for hard boiled).</description></item></channel></rss>