<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eggs on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/</link><description>Recent content in Eggs on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/eggs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tajine Maadnous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Similar to an Italian frittata or Spanish tortilla, Tunisian tajine maadnous is an easy &amp;amp; delicious egg omelette filled with chicken, parsley, and spices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tajine-maadnous.webp" alt="tajine maadnous">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 12&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lb chicken breasts diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 medium onion chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large potato peeled and diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small bunch parsley (about 1.5 cups, chopped, loosely packed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 large eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 oz cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="spice-blend">Spice Blend&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 tsp cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp paprika or cayenne pepper if you want some heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp caraway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix the spices together (grinding any whole spices if necessary) and set them aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large frying pan or pot over medium heat, saute the onions in about 1 tbsp of olive oil until tender.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toss chicken with 1/2 of the spice mix. Add this to the pan and brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potatoes and the water to the pan. Bring to a gentle simmer, then cook uncovered until potatoes are tender and most of the liquid has evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir chopped parsley into the cooked mixture and set aside to cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 350Â°F (180Â°C), and grease a medium (2 quart/liter) baking pan with the remaining olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thoroughly whisk the eggs in a large bowl, then mix in the cheese. Stir in the chicken, potato, and parsley mixture, along with the remaining spice mixture. Stir until well-combined, then pour into the oiled baking dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 30-35 minutes, or until set in the center. Allow to cool, and serve warm or at room temperature. Serve with some harissa, if you like.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Quiche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 60 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 3/4 cups Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup + 2 1/2 Tbsp Butter, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Up to 1/3 cup Water, chilled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Onion, finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>14 ounces Smoked Salmon, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Fresh Chives, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove Garlic, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Fresh Basil, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 whole Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Whipping Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine all pastry ingredients in a food processor (mix flour and butter, then add water gradually while mixing).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gather into a ball, cover with plastic wrap and chill 1 hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute onion until shiny in the butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in salmon, chives, garlic, and basil. Cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven to 400F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out the dough to fit a 10&amp;quot; tart pan. Prick with a fork.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the salmon mixture in the pre-baked tart shell.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk eggs with milk and cream, season with pepper and pour in the tart shell.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake about 30 minutes at 325F, until puffed and golden.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tahini short bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tahini-short-bread.webp" alt="Tahini biscuits">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This short bread recipe uses sesame paste called Tahini, a minimal amount of white sugar is necessary in order to get a crunchy/caramelized short-bread.
For better results, a food processor is welcome for this recipe. &lt;strong>IMPORTANT&lt;/strong> Butter is what makes this recipe complicated when cooking the dough, make sure it is not liquid or that the room is not to warm and make sure that the shortbreads are cold before putting in the oven.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soleier (pickled eggs)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/soleier.webp" alt="Soleier">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soleier are a german pub dish. They are typically enjoyed between two beers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Preparation time: 10min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 10&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>peels of five onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 loorber leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 allspice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Tbsp peppercorns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Tbsp caraway seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1Tbsp mustard seeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1tsp of Szechuan pepper (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1tsp lovage (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1tsp nutmeg (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100mL vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put 750mL of water and the peels of five onions in a pot and let them cook for five minutes. Remove the peels about twenty minutes later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the eggs, one teaspoon of sugar, two tablespoons of salt and all spices (but vinegar and garlic) in the pot, bring it to a boil and cook them for seven minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use a spoon to remove the eggs from the pot and crack them all around. Do not remove the eggshell!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the eggs and the garlic in a jar, fill it with the spiced water and add the vinegar. Add water, if needed, so that the eggs are covered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let them rest for at least three days and at most two weeks at room temperature or slightly below.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="consumption-recommendation">Consumption Recommendation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel the egg and cut it in half.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the yolk and fill the egg with mustard, oil, salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the yolk on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 1 (2 wraps)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 sausages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 bacon rashers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 wraps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ketchup (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Next, fry the bacon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Next, possibly while the bacon is frying, crack an egg into a bowl, add a dash of milk and whisk it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then, put the egg mixture into the microwave for a minute, take it out and whisk it again, do this twice again or until the scrambled egg is ready.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the sausage, bacon and scrambled egg to a wrap (I recommend two sausage halves, a bacon rasher and half the bowl of scrambled egg per wrap). Add ketchup if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/spanish-tortilla.webp" alt="Spanish Tortilla">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 free-range eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 kg of potatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potato slices already salted and let them cook for approximately 20 minutes over low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the potatoes are frying, beat the eggs in a bowl. Peel and cut the onion as finely as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add olive oil in another frying pan and slowly fry the onion until it gets a slightly golden color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drain the onion and add it to the bowl with the beaten egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the potatoes from the pan with a slotted spoon, draining the oil away as much as possible, and add them to the bowl with the onion and egg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the mixture rest for at least 5 minutes so all the flavors come together. Give it a very gentle stir from time to time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the oil from the pan you used to fry the potatoes. Use the pan to cook the mixture over medium-high fire for about 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip it over with the help of a big plate and cook the other side for another 5 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Things like the slicing of the potato, the amount of salt and how curdled is the inner part of the tortilla depend on your own taste. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to experiment!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Frittata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid><description>&lt;p>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings:4-6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>4-6 Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Bell Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp Heavy Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shredded cheese of choice (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add in meat to the pan and set oven to low broil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beat eggs, cream, salt, and pepper together in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add in egg mixture to the pan and mix together until even.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook egg and vegetable mixture in pan until eggs begin to firm up and edges begin to pull away. Place into oven&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep in Oven until completely firm. At this point you can add shredded cheese on top and put back into the oven until melted (about 2 more minutes)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Flip out of pan and cool to room temperature to ensure settling.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Other good vegetables include spinach, tomatoes, mushrooms, broccoli rabe&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If adding tomatoes, try to keep as much of the juice out to prevent it from being too watery and falling apart&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An easy way to get it out of the pan is flip upside down on to a plate and then flip again onto another plate/cooling rack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is possible to use ground meat as well, but it may have to cook a bit longer in the over to ensure firmness.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether
or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever
suits your lifestyle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Green onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loaf of French Bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tabasco&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While the pan heats up, use your hands and tear off pieces of bread that are roughly the size of your hand.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure you have one piece of bread per egg you want to make. I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled with the egg:bread ratios, and this seems to work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the olive oil starts smelling a bit (or smoke comes off of it), crack in however many eggs you care to eat. Turn down the heat to medium.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Act fast! As the eggs start cooking, prepare a plate with two handfuls of chopped green onion and Tabasco.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After about four minutes (or when the tops of the eggs start to set), take out eggs and place on top of bed of onions &amp;amp; Tabasco.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn heat back to medium-high and add a touch more olive oil. Place pieces of bread in pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every so often, move the pieces of bread around to soak up the oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the bread is about to turn a good shade of golden-brown, add a generous sprinkle of Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s to the plated eggs (on top of them).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat and move the pan off the burner. Take out bread pieces and place on the same plate as the eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with glass of ice-cold beer.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Ideally, you won&amp;rsquo;t even need a fork! Simply use the bread to guide the eggs on top of each piece, break the yolk into the piece, and take a large
bite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: â‰ˆ 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 4 Omelets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/8 teaspoon pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 cup milk, scalded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon butter, or margarine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 egg yolks, beaten until thick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 egg whites, beaten stiff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow it to cool; combine with egg yolks, stirring occasionally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold in egg whites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set oven for moderate 350Â°F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour egg mixture into hot buttered frying pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook over low heat 3 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer to oven; bake 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Omelet is done when an inserted knife comes out clean.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut across at right angles to handle of pan, being careful not to cut all the way through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fold carefully from handle to opposite side and serve on hot platter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="for-cheese-omelet">For Cheese Omelet&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add 1/2 cup grated sharp Cheddar Cheese just before folding in egg whites.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before putting omelet in oven, sprinkle top with an additional 1/2 cup of grated cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an
egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the
&lt;a href="/android_asset/html/index.html">homepage&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cheese(optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>milk (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="boiled-eggs">Boiled eggs&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place eggs in water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency
(about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium
runny, 10+ for hard boiled).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Tip: if your eggs are cracking when you put them in boiling water, you might
improve your chances of them not doing so by first warming them up in warm water
for a few minutes beforehand.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>