<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vegetables on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/vegetables/</link><description>Recent content in vegetables on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/vegetables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Autumn Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</guid><description>You can cook the veggies on the stove instead of baking them, just pay more attention to avoid burning. You can also use pumpkin instead of squash.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 Medium Squash 3 Potatoes 4 Carrots 1 Small Onion 1 Chicken Bullion Cube 1 cup Water 2 cups Milk Salt Pepper Directions Peel and chop squash, potatoes, carrots, and onion, add to oven-safe pot.</description></item><item><title>Red Lentil Dahl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 medium Yellow Onion 1 Tbsp Fresh Ginger, grated 4 Garlic Cloves, minced 2 Tbsp Yellow Curry (mild madras) 1 tsp Sea Salt 1 cup dried Red Lentils 4 - 5 cups Water 5 Plum Tomatoes, chopped juice of 1 Lemon 1 cup Fresh Cilantro, chopped and lightly packed Dried Red Chili&amp;rsquo;s or cayenne pepper, to taste 1/4 tsp Ground Cinnamon Directions Heat oil in a soup pot and saute onions for 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Fennel White Bean and Kale Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup with lots of veggie and protein.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 bowls Ingredients ½ cup olive oil 2 small fennel bulbs, small-diced 2 small yellow onions, small-diced 4 teaspoons minced fresh rosemary or thyme 10 cloves of garlic, minced or pressed ½-1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes. 10-12 oz kale, (escarole, swiss chard, or spinach can also be used). 4 cans cannellini beans, rinsed 4 cups chicken broth.</description></item><item><title>Ray Peat's Carrot Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</guid><description>A raw carrot salad to support digestive, hormone and thyroid health
&amp;ldquo;Endotoxin formed in the bowel can block respiration and cause hormone imbalances contributing to instability of the nerves, so it is helpful to optimize bowel flora, for example with a carrot salad; a dressing of vinegar, coconut oil and olive oil, carried into the intestine by the carrot fiber, suppresses bacterial growth while stimulating healing of the wall of the intestine.</description></item><item><title>Collard Greens with Smoked Duck and Parsnips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips/</guid><description>This dish was a pandemic leftover invention loosely inspired by Ethiopian gomen. It can be served as a side dish, but we eat it an an entree. If you intend it as a side dish, then this serves 4. The smoked duck adds a bit of saltiness, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to season to taste after cooking. Serve with good quality, crusty bread.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1/2 smoked duck breast (skin on) chopped 1 large onion sliced 1 small parsnip julienned 1 large bunch collard greens chopped into ribbons 1/2 green cabbage cut into ribbons (optional) 1–2 tablespoons olive oil and/or butter 1 teaspoon ground coriander 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon 1/2 teaspoon garam masala Directions In a large dutch oven (or a big pot with a lid) on low heat, add the chopped duck breast and olive oil and/or butter to the pot for a couple of minutes.</description></item><item><title>Erwtensoep (Dutch pea soup)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</guid><description>Erwtensoep, also called snert, is the Dutch version of pea soup. Slices of rookworst (smoked sausage) are added before serving. The soup, which is traditionally eaten during the winter, is emblematic of Dutch cuisine. It is customarily served with Frisian rye bread (roggebrood) and bacon, cheese or butter. Pancakes are sometimes served with pea soup; this dish is called snert met struif, struif referring to the pancakes.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 7 1/2 cups / 1.</description></item><item><title>Potato Leek Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 1 quart chicken or veggie stock 11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes 1 bay leaf ¾ cup heavy cream white pepper (optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg (optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed Directions Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed Round Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</guid><description>Round Squash, Zucchini, or Courguettes can be served as main dish (2 servings per person) or as accompaniment. The amount of squash should be adjusted according to their size. This recipe uses ones the size of a fist.
⏲️ Prep time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Onions 1 Carrot 4 Round squash 1 Cup of rice 100gr of Cheese (optional) Directions Cook the rice. This usually takes 20 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>