<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sauce on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/sauce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sauce on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/sauce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes
 ⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours  Ingredients  extra virgin olive oil 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 large onion 2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional) 200 grams pancetta (optional) 300 grams beef mince 350 grams pork mince 350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork) 140 grams concentrated tomato paste 690 grams diced tomatoes water 1 can peeled tomatoes 1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open) 1 glass of milk (optional) 1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional)  Directions  Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic béchamel sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
 ⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min  Ingredients  5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg  Directions  Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corn Salsa</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 Minutes 🍳 Cook time: 1 Hour+ in fridge  Ingredients  2 pounds frozen corn, defrosted 1/2 Red onion, finely chopped 4 Radishes, sliced thin and chopped Few pinches of Cilantro, finely chopped 1-2 Jalepenos, finely chopped (optional) Juice of 2-3 Limes Salt and pepper, to taste  Directions  Chop everything to pieces smaller than the corn kernels. Mix well and let sit covered in the fridge for at least an hour, even better overnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curry sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I like to make double this amount and freeze the rest.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  25g butter 1 onion, sliced 2 garlic cloves, sliced Thumb of ginger, sliced 2 tbsp curry powder 1/2 tsp turmeric 1 tbsp malt vinegar 1 star anise 250ml chicken stock 1 tbsp cornflour 2 tbsp water Lemon juice (optional)  Directions  Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demi-glace</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</guid>
      <description>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.
These are the basic proportions &amp;ndash; multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.
Ingredients  1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) low-sodium broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods) 1 1/4 oz (7g) packet unflavored, unsweetened gelatin 1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste 1 teaspoon (5mL) low-sodium soy sauce 1/2 teaspoon onion powder (very optional)  Directions  Put the tomato paste in a large pot, then turn the heat on medium Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown Deglaze with the broth Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume Freeze in ice cub trays  Contribution Dan - ETH 0xC86468549c180A296384aAC2F76c8F581691Bc1b</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburger dressing</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</guid>
      <description>A delicious home made hamburger dressing 🍔
 ⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min  Ingredients  3 tbsp mayonnese or aioli 2 tbsp ketchup 1 tbsp sriracha 1 clove garlic, if using mayonnese and not aioli (optional)  Directions  Mix ingredients in a bowl  Contribution  brox - xmr: 8AaUvC4JPfTVgy66FLd8mVfsPwT7RXJuPK2xySoKnFEhDZPNafpgn6rh8VPBVauyNP17EQQ1HGhMCZdtUJNoD7xnVt1cSLo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ketchup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</guid>
      <description>Ketchup/Catsup  Ingredients  2 1/2 quart (15 to 17 medium-sized) sliced tomatoes 1 large garlic clove, chopped 1 cup vinegar 1/4 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup sugar 3 - inch piece stick cinnamon 1 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon paprika 1 teaspoon whole cloves a dash cayenne pepper  Directions  Simmer together tomatoes and onion for 20 to 30 minutes; press through a sieve. Put the cinnamon, cloves, and garlic loosely in a clean, thin, white cloth; tie top tightly; add to vinegar and simmer 30 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mayonnaise or aioli</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</guid>
      <description>Aioli is pretty much just mayonnaise with garlic, although traditional aioli only includes olive oil and garlic, and no eggs or acid. This recipe uses raw eggs, so if that is sketchy in your region use pasteurized eggs 🥚.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min  Ingredients  1 whole egg or 2 egg yolks, preferably at room temperature 2.5 dl/ 1 cup neutral oil 1-2 tbsp vinegar or lemon juice 1 tbsp pickle juice (optional) 2-4 cloves of garlic for aioli, don&amp;rsquo;t include for mayonnaise 1 tsp dijon mustard (optional)  Directions  Place egg, vinegar, mustard a pinch of salt and pepper in a beaker or narrow and tall container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</guid>
      <description>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&amp;rsquo;s quite similar to a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&amp;rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it provides as a sweet and cooling effect.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  500 gm of Greek Yogurt One Red onion 50 gm of Cucumber Sprigs of Mint Dash of Honey Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option)  Directions  Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid>
      <description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients  a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced)  Directions  Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crush and sliced garlic until translucent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pepper Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pepper-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pepper-sauce/</guid>
      <description>A very basic pepper sauce that is great for steaks and other dishes
 ⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  1 tablespoon freshy ground rose pepper, green pepper and black pepper 1 teaspoon dijon mustard 1dl bouillon 2dl cream Salt if needed  Directions  Ground the peppers and put them on the pan and roast them for about one minute while moving the peppers with your spatula Mix in the mustard and bouillon and bring to a boil Add in the cream and let the sauce thicken on medium heat for about 10-20 minutes Taste the sauce and add salt if needed  Contribution  Vili Kangas  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ragu Napoletano</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12  Ingredients Tomato Sauce  6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional)  Aromatics and Herbs  8 cloves garlic 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Sauce (Ragu all&#39;Italiana)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</guid>
      <description>My great-grandma&amp;rsquo;s red sauce. All purpose: good for pastas, lasagnas, subs, etc.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 12 mins 🍳 Cook time: Simmer all day 🍽️ Servings: 7  Ingredients  1/3 lb salt pork 2 lb chuck roast 3 Cloves of garlic Crushed hot red pepper Sweet onion Large carrot 2 Bay leaves 2 tbsp. Olive oil (she used mazola oil) 12 oz. Can tomato paste 29 oz. Diced tomatoes 29 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 mins 🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended) Flour (Wheat flour recommended)  Directions  Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan. Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan. Stir and turn on maximum heat. Keep stirring until it becomes thick.
If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.
Ingredients  Tomato sauce. Mayonaise  Directions  Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Mayo</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</guid>
      <description>A simple sauce that is at almost every sushi bar in the United States.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 3 min  Ingredients  chili sauce (e.g Sriracha) mayonnaise sesame oil  Directions  Add 2 parts mayonnaise to 1 part chili sauce in a bowl. Add 1 tbsp of sesame oil for every cup of mayonnaise you use. Mix all of the ingredients together, and taste test it for more chili sauce or mayonnaise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
