<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breakfast on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/breakfast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breakfast on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/breakfast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Banana Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people  Ingredients  1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas  Directions  Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid>
      <description>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps)  Ingredients  2 sausages 2 bacon rashers 1 egg 2 wraps milk ketchup (optional)  Directions  Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through. Next, fry the bacon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Breakfast Skillet</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/country-skillet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/country-skillet/</guid>
      <description>If you are feeling quite hungry after just waking up and want to have a breakfast to fill your HP and stamina bars for the day, I&amp;rsquo;ve got just the perfect recipe for you.
To be honest, this is more of a build-your-own dish. What I am providing here, I would say, is more of a starting point and you&amp;rsquo;re more than welcome to add (or remove) anything you&amp;rsquo;d like. I also have to say that this is not exclusively a breakfast dish, I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for breakfast, for lunch, for supper, for dinner, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Country Crisp Cereals</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/country-crisp-cereals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/country-crisp-cereals/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe for making Jordan&amp;rsquo;s Country Crisp-like cereals.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 2 h 🍽️ Servings: 7  Ingredients  Oat Flakes (270 g - 800 mL) Rice Flour (or any other flour) (20 g - 55mL) Sugar (100 g) Crushed Hazelnuts (20 g) Oil (any type) (60 g - 75 mL) Water (50 g) Chocolate (70 g) (optional) Vanilla Extract (1/2 tsp) (optional)  Directions  Preheat the oven at 120°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danish Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid>
      <description>Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients  375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 Eggs  Directions  Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or Margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Crêpes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid>
      <description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients  300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil  Directions  Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Toast</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>This recipe results in five slices of easy to make french toast.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  2 Eggs 1/2 Cup of milk 5 Slices of bread Maple Syrup (Optional) Butter  Directions  Butter up a frying pan and set it on the burner with low-medium heat.(May need to add more butter in-between slices) Take your two eggs and crack them into a bowl together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glutenfree Pfannkuchen (pancakes)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/glutenfree-pfannkuchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/glutenfree-pfannkuchen/</guid>
      <description>A very easy recipe for glutenfree Pfannkuchen (german pancakes).
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1  Ingredients  100g glutenfree flour 200ml milk 50g sugar 2 eggs a pinch of salt  Directions  Mix all ingredients in a bowl Let the dough rest for ~15 mins Heat a pan with a bit butter For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides  Served with  Syrup Cinnamon and sugar  Contribution  Lxgr - github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal </title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</guid>
      <description>If your Oatmeal isn&amp;rsquo;t Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal&amp;hellip; Is it even Oatmeal?
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Serving: 1 hearty serving  Ingredients  1/2 cup Large Flake Oats (no partially cooked quick-oats allowed!) Almonds Pecans 1 Tbsp Roasted Flax Seed 1 Tbsp Hemp Hearts Cranberries (adjust amount to preference) 1/2 Banana (mashed) 1 cup Milk (3.25% if possible) Cinnamon (adjust amount to preference) 1 Egg ON Vanilla Ice Cream Protein Powder (optional)  Directions  Chop or mash nuts and fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 8  Ingredients  2 eggs 40g sugar (3 tbsp) 20g honey (1 tbsp) 60ml milk (4 tbsp) (you can use water instead) 120g oat flour (1 cup) 1 tsp baking powder (or baking soda + some acid to activate it) Raspberry jam (optional)  Directions  Mix eggs, sugar, honey and milk. In another bowl mix oat flour and baking powder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oats</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid>
      <description>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do with oats.
We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.
Ingredients  oats water pinch of salt  Pick and choose additional ingredients:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oaty Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted)  Directions  Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid>
      <description>Here is a simple Pancake recipe
Ingredients  200g wheat flour 200 ml milk 2 Eggs 2 teaspoon sugar 1 teaspoon baking soda a little bit of salt  Directions  combine all ingredients all in a bowl and stir preheat a pan and add some oil Pour or scoop the batter onto the pan Brown on both sides  Contribution BeFe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Breakfast Spaghetti</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</guid>
      <description>A quick breakfast spaghetti recipe that covers a healthy amount of carbs, fat, and spices. Eggs and/or bacon can be added to cover some protein, you should cook those while the boiler is cooking the spaghetti for time efficiency.
Ingredients  Spaghetti (any kind you prefer) Ground spices (I like to use cumin, turmeric, paprika, and garlic) Tomato Paste/Sauce (preferably one with basil and without preservative) Extra Virgin Olive Oil  Directions  Boil some water fully and prepare a pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shakshouka</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</guid>
      <description>Shakshouka is a dish of eggs poached in a sauce of tomatoes, olive oil, peppers, onion and garlic, and commonly spiced with cumin, paprika, cayenne pepper, and nutmeg. This recipe is a quick and simple version for a delicious breakfast.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  5 small tomatoes 5 eggs 1 peeled white onion some chives cumin powdered sweet pepper  Directions  Scald the tomatoes so they are easier to peel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Morning Milkshake</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</guid>
      <description>A sweet and refreshing milkshake that barely requires any effort to make. You&amp;rsquo;re not required to make it and drink it on Sunday, it was just almost a tradition in my family to make it on the weekends, and it somehow does taste better on a Saturday or Sunday morning.
Ingredients These are for about 4 glasses or 1 liter:
 1 banana (or 2 if they are small) ~120 grams of berries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swedish Pancakes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/swedish-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/swedish-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  3 Eggs, beaten 1 tsp Salt 1 tbsp Sugar 1 cup Flour 1 - 2/3 cups Milk 6-8 tbsp Butter  Directions  At medium/low heat begin melting the butter, and continue with beating eggs in large bowl, add salt, sugar, milk, flour and mix. Add melted butter while stirring batter. Use about 1/2 cup batter on griddle and tilt until spread evenly over griddle surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yogurt</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1l milk 100ml yogurt  Directions  bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h store in the fridge  Contribution  italian boy  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
