<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Argentinian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/argentinian/</link><description>Recent content in Argentinian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/argentinian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dulce de Leche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</guid><description>&lt;p>Delicious milk toffee used on desserts or as a spread. Substitute for Nootella or similar &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;. It is very demanding, so i only recommend you make it if you either can&amp;rsquo;t buy industrial dulce de leche (It will be way more natural than other sweets anyway), or have the time and interest to go through the process. It can be made more easily with sweetened condensed milk, but if you have access to it, you can get DDL anyways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Torta Frita Criolla (Argentinian frybread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</guid><description>&lt;p>A &amp;ldquo;merienda&amp;rdquo; (afternoon meal) that is intertwined with the history of colonization on the River Plate region. Never have it by yourself, instead with friends or family, and a cup/gourd of Mate.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 1h 10min or 2h 10min, (depending on how long you leave it to rest.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³Cook time: 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings : 10.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1.1 pound (1/2 kilo) of all-purpose flour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tablespoons of lard or butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup of water mixed with a teaspoon of salt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil or grease of choice for frying. (Modern Argentines use refined tallow or sunflower seed oil, but for the real gaucho way, unrefined lard or tallow is the right choice)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sugar, cinnamon, or herbs and spices of choice (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add the flour on a bowl, and the grease in ambient temperature in the middle.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix flour and grease with your fingertips, while slowly adding the salt water, until you end up with a dough ball.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knead it energically, until the dough forms bubbles on its surface.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it rest for 1 or 2 hours, and then form little balls, the size you&amp;rsquo;d do for a chocolate chip cookie, smash them to a disc shape, then poke a small hole in the middle.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry it on abundant grease until golden brown, remove it with a perforated spoon, then put it on a bowl with paper towels to absorb excess grease.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add garnishes, but it is not essential, due to how rich and filling the dish is.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>