<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cheese on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/cheese/</link><description>Recent content in cheese on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/cheese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients For the bechamel 50g Butter 50g Flour 1 Liter of milk Salt Ground Pepper Nutmeg For the bites 12 Slices of bread 2 Tbsp of Mustard 12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs 80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette Directions Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan. As soon as it foams, sprinkle it with flour, salt, pepper, add a pinch of nutmeg, mix.</description></item><item><title>Quiche Lorraine - Lothringer Käsetorte</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 160 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 200g Flour (full sight) 100g Butter or Margarine 5 Tablespoons of Water 200g of Ham (alternatively cooked ham) 4 Eggs 1/4 Cream 125g grinded Edamer Cheese For the Baking Tin: More Butter and Flour Directions Spread some butter on a 26cm Ø or two smaller baking tins and cover it with flour Sieve the flour, mingle the butter/margarine in small flakes.</description></item><item><title>Fondue</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</guid><description>A swiss classic for cold winter dinners. Traditionally cooked in a &amp;ldquo;Caquelon&amp;rdquo; pot and served on a candle heated stove, to keep the cheese from going solid again.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 garlic clove 4 dl (1.5 cups) white wine 800 g (1.7 lbs) swiss cheese (50/50 mix of Gruyère and Emmentaler recommended) 1 shot of kirsch (cherry brandy) 1 tsp lemon juice 1-2 tbsp starch flour 1 loaf (~800g/~1.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</guid><description>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 5-6 Ingredients Ricotta cheese One large egg Parmesan cheese Oregano (Optional) Directions Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handful of finely grated parmesan. Add the oregano and the egg and mix. Add salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential) 50g Butter 100g Flour 200ml Milk 400g Cheddar Cheese 6 Rashers of bacon (optional) Directions Grate the cheese. Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares. Start cooking the pasta. Start melting the butter in another saucepan. Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Potato Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</guid><description>Potatoes baked in a dish smothered with cheese, what&amp;rsquo;s not to love?
You will need a deep dish that is oven safe
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 30g+ Butter 250g Cheddar Cheese 275ml Milk 16g Flour 600g Potatoes As much bacon as you want to garnish Directions Preparation: Preheat to 180C Butter deep baking dish Peal and thinly slice potatoes Grate Cheese Sauce: Melt Butter in Pot Slowly add flour and stir constantly After 2 min or bubbly remove from heat Add milk slowly, stirring constantly Add 3/4 of the cheese Salt and Pepper to taste Assembly: Add a thin layer of potatoes to the dish Add a layer of cheese sauce Add bacon Repeat steps 1-3 of assembly until there are no more potatoes/sauce Add the remaining 1/4 cheese to the top Put in oven for 45 min.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Meatballs with Tomato Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</guid><description>Nothing beats meat, cheese and tomato combined together to create the best combination of flavors that man has created.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about two adult portions. That is, if you are also making some side dish, like in the photo.
For the meatballs:
300-400g of ground beef meat 1/4 of an onion ~70g of cheese; I have made with different cheese types, but usually I use Gouda Parsley 1-2 garlic cloves 1 egg ~1/5 metric cups (~50ml) of bread crumbs For the sauce:</description></item></channel></rss>