<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pork on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/pork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pork on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/pork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo &amp;amp; Chickpea Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid>
      <description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min  Ingredients  Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying  Directions  Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flammkuchen</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid>
      <description>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up. I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.
 🍽️ Servings:2  Ingredients  400g Pizza dough (either bought or from Pizza Dough) 1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons) 150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables) 2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche  Directions  we start by flattening the dough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid>
      <description>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.
 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  porkchops: 4 shallots: 2 gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup mustard: 2tbsp butter vegetable oil  Directions  Cut the shallots into small dices. Cut the gherkins into long strips. Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Pork Belly</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</guid>
      <description>Melt-in-mouth fatty pork in a sweet and spicy glaze.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 15 mins 🍽 Servings: 2  Ingredients  400g high fat pork belly (no skin) large thumb of ginger 4 cloves of garlic 1 scotch bonnet chili 2 tbsp ketchup 2 tbsp hoisin sauce 2 tbsp honey 2 tsp sesame oil 1 spring onion  Directions  Cut pork belly into 1 inch cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapo Tofu (麻婆豆腐)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/mapo-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients Marinated Pork  450 g (1 lb) ground pork 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp Shaoxing cooking wine 1 tsp cornstarch 1 tsp white pepper powder  Braise  2 tbsp spicy doubanjiang (la doubanjiang) 1 tsp dou-chi 2-3 chopped scallions white and green separated) 2-4 minced garlic cloves 2 inch minced ginger (similar amount as garlic) 400 ml chicken broth or water 340 g (1 package) soft tofu cut into 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marinated pork steaks </title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/marinated-pork-steaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/marinated-pork-steaks/</guid>
      <description>A tasty simple marinade that fits well with pork.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 35 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 3-4 people  Ingredients  6 tablespoons olive oil ¼ cup soy sauce ¼ cup of honey Juice from 1 lime 3 peeled cloves garlic 4 ¼ inch thick boneless pork shoulder steaks  Directions  Mix olive oil, soy sauce, honey and lime juice until you have an even marinade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ragu Napoletano</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12  Ingredients Tomato Sauce  6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional)  Aromatics and Herbs  8 cloves garlic 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Rolls</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/sausage-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sausage-rolls/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30-60 min  Ingredients  Eggs Puff pastry Pork meat / sausage meat  Directions  Place baking paper onto a tray Whisk eggs Lay out pastry, brush or pour egg whisk so it lightly covers the pastry Prepare sausage meat onto pastry Fold pastry around the meat, apply extra egg whisk to the &amp;lsquo;seal&amp;rsquo; where the pastry is folded together Bake until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow-cooked Pork Carnitas</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</guid>
      <description>This recipe makes a lot and is super easy. A whole roast usually makes enough for a few meals (depending on how many people will be eating it). Leftovers can be refrigerated for 4-5 days.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hr 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-11  Ingredients  2 ½ lbs. boneless pork shoulder 6 cloves of garlic, cut into slivers 1 ½ teaspoons cumin ½ teaspoon sazon ¼ teaspoon dry oregano ¾ cup low sodium chicken broth 2-3 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce 2 bay leaves ¼ teaspoon dry adobo seasoning  Directions  Season pork with kosher salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6  Ingredients For the sauce  ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional)  For the meatballs  1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Porkchops</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</guid>
      <description>Simple chinese inspired sticky porkchops.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 3 hours 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  4 Pork chops 2 heaped tbsp Set honey 3 Garlic cloves, crushed Soy sauce Ginger (thumb sized piece), sliced 1 tbsp Chinese Five Spice  Directions  Fill a shallow dish with soy sauce to about half the thickness of your porkchops. The level shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fully submerge them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuscan Style Pork Roast</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</guid>
      <description>An herbaceous pancetta stuffed pork roast with a crispy exterior. Finished with a lemon vinaigrette. Adapted from Binging With Babish whose instructions are notoriously bad.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 people  Equipment  Food processor Fine mesh strainer Cast iron skillet Butchers twine  Ingredients  1 pork Roast 2-3 Tbsp fresh rosemary 8 cloves garlic, minced ⅓ cup high quality olive oil 1 lemon 4 oz pancetta or bacon 1 tsp fresh parsley  Directions  Preheat oven to 275°F (135°C) Butterfly the roast by cutting into three parts by cutting into the side starting a third of the way up the roast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid>
      <description>A swiss favorite, Älplermagronen combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet. It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.
 🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  ~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes 3 onions (medium size) 400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy) 1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk 400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight) ~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
