<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>greek on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/greek/</link><description>Recent content in greek on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/greek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn 4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced 1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced 1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced 1 small Onion, sliced 1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped 3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 6 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar 1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp dill weed 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper 2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh Directions Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 Ingredients Pasta layer 600g penne rigate salted water Meat layer 1 large onion, finely diced 700g lean ground beef .5 TB ground allspice .5 TB ground cinnamon .25 TSP ground clove (optional) 340g tomato paste Béchamel layer 226g butter 226g flour 1L cold milk 237ml chicken stock freshly grated nutmeg (optional) grated cheese (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 190°C In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions.</description></item><item><title>Baba's Feta Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</guid><description>Greek Pasta Recipe with sauce made out of feta, stock, cream cheese and other ingredients. Uses mixed spice for special flavour, and is a great dinner or mid-day meal.
⏲️ Prep time: 15-30 min 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients Serves Around 3 People. You can scale up to 4 If you increase most quantities by +1/4.
Medium Sweet Onion (Finely Chopped) Virgin olive oil (not extra-virgin) White Sugar 3 Fresh Medium Garlic Cloves (Chopped Fine) 15-20 Kalamon/Kalamata Olives (Cut into thirds) Whole small courgette (Cut to small pieces) 6 Medium Mushrooms (Cut smallish and small stalk) 1/2 Broccli (Chopped small) 8-10 Finely sliced cherry tomatoes 1/2 Block of feta (Washed) 1 Chicken stock (Added to 3/4 Mug boiling water) Overfilled Teaspoon Mixed Spice 3/4 Bowls fusilli pasta Overfilled tablespoon Creme Cheese 1/3 Mug whole milk Directions Make sure to prepare &amp;amp; chop most ingredients before you start.</description></item><item><title>Greek Easter Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid><description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies Ingredients 1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more) Directions Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description></item></channel></rss>