<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chicken on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/chicken/</link><description>Recent content in chicken on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Galinha Caipira</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/galinha-caipira/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/galinha-caipira/</guid><description>Chicken stew ubiquitous in rural Brazil. Perfect pair with rice and beans, polenta or boiled cassava root.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2h 30min 🍽️ Servings: Usually enough for a family of five. Ingredients A whole ckicken weighing close to 2,5kg (roughly 3 pounds). Avoid industrially grown birds, as those can make the stew very greasy and flavorless. A cup of diced onions of any kind.</description></item><item><title>Exotic Ginger Cumin Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/exotic-ginger-cumin-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/exotic-ginger-cumin-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 Tbsp Vegetable Oil, divided 2 lbs Boneless Skinless Chicken, cut bite-size 2 tsp Garlic, minced 1/2 cup Onion, chopped 1 Tbsp Ginger Root, minced 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Cumin 1 tsp Turmeric 1/2 cup Chicken Stock 1 can (19oz) Stewed Tomatoes 2 Tbsp Tomato Paste 1 tsp Sugar 3/4 cup Low Fat Plain Yogurt Directions In large saucepan heat 2 tsp oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>One-Pot Chicken Tetrazzini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Butter 8 oz Mushrooms, sliced 1 small Red Pepper, chopped 1 small Onion, finely chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 4 cups Milk 2 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 8 oz Extra Broad Egg Noodles 5 oz Boursin Garlic and Fine Herbs 3 cup Deli Chicken, cooked and cut into bite-size pieces 1/2 cup Frozen Peas 1/2 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped Small Fresh Basil Leaves (optional) Parmesan, grated Directions Melt butter in a large saucepan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Kung Pao-Style Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 4 Chicken Thighs 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 4 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 2 small Sweet Peppers, chopped 3 ribs Celery 2 cloves Garlic 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 2 whole Green Onions, thinly sliced 2 Tbsp Chili Garlic Sauce, divided 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce 1/4 cup Peanuts, chopped Oil Directions Heat a medium pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Chicken Breasts 1 cup Bulghur Wheat 1 oz Mixed Olives, drained 4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped 2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend 2 Roma Tomatoes 1 Lemon 1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated 2 Tbsp White Vinegar 1 tsp Sugar Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot.</description></item><item><title>Fajitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time:15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/4 cup + 1/2 tsp Lime Juice, divided 3 Tbsp Olive Oil, divided 4 cloves Garlic, crushed 3 tsp Soy Sauce, divided 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Liquid Smoke 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1/4 tsp Black Pepper 1 lb Chicken Breasts or Skirt Steak, bones/skin removed 2 Tbsp Water 1 large Spanish Onion, thinly sliced 1/2 each Green, Red, and Yellow Bell Pepper, thinly sliced Directions Combine 1/4 cup lime juice, 2 Tbsp of the oil, garlic, 2 tsp soy sauce, the salt, liquid smoke, cayenne pepper, and black pepper in a resealable container, add chicken/steak, cover, and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or overnight.</description></item><item><title>Cheddar-Crusted Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheddar-crusted-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheddar-crusted-chicken/</guid><description>Suggested sides: Roasted green beans as well as sweet potatoes mashed with sour cream and butter
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 Chicken Breasts 2 Tbsp Mayonnaise 1/4 cup Panko Breadcrumbs 1/4 cup Cheddar Cheese, shredded 1 Tbsp Smoked Paprika-Garlic Blend Directions Combine panko, cheese, and smoked paprika-garlic blend in a shallow dish. Preheat oven to 425F.</description></item><item><title>Easy Chicken and Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 cup Onion, chopped 1/2 cup Celery, chopped 2 Tbsp Butter or margarine 2 cups Chicken, cooked and chopped 1 3/4 cups Hot water 2/3 cup Long Grain White Rice 1 can (10 oz) Mushrooms with liquid 1 cup Frozen Peas and Carrots 1 tsp Dried Thyme and Rosemary Directions In large fry pan, cook onion and celery in butter until soft.</description></item><item><title>Turkish-Style Spiced Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Chicken Breasts 1 Tbsp Turkish Spice Blend 1 oz Almonds, sliced 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 12 oz Sweet Potato 2 oz Onion, chopped 100 mL Greek Yogurt 2 Tbsp Parsley 1 Lemon 1/2 tsp Garlic Salt 1 1/2 cup Chicken Broth 1 tsp Sugar Directions Cut sweet potatoes into 1/2 inch pieces.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp and Chicken Jambalaya</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</guid><description>Warm up your stock with raw shrimp shells to infuse additional flavour, if desired. Serve dish with french bread and your favourite beer.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min Ingredients 1/4 tsp Cayenne 3/4 tsp White Pepper 1 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Thyme 1/2 tsp Rubbed Sage 1/4 tsp Dried Basil 1/2 tsp Black Pepper 1 Tbsp Unsalted Butter 1/2 cup Diced Andouille (or Chirozo sausage) 1/2 cup Diced Onion 1/2 cup Diced Bell Pepper 1/2 cup Diced Celery 1/2 cup Diced Fresh Tomatoes 1/2 cup Tomato Sauce 3/4 cup Enriched Long Grain Rice 1-1/4 cup Chicken Stock 1 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 2 Tbsp Minced Fresh Garlic 1/2 cup Diced Chicken (cooked or raw) 1-1/2 cup Medium Shrimp 1 Tbsp Finely Chopped Italian Parsley 3 Tbsp Finely Sliced Green Onions Directions Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Apple Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</guid><description>Baked chicken with apples and onions. Suprinsingly good and simple combination.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Chicken breast or similar. Onions. Nuez moscada. Apples. Potatoes. Cream or creme fraiche. Salt. Pepper. One glass (33c) of wine or cognac. Directions Heat the oven to 200C and prepare an oven tray. Mix the chicken with nuez moscada, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Satay with Peanut Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 lbs boneless chicken breast or thigh 1.5 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tbsp ground tumeric 2 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp coconut milk 3 tbsp peanut butter (creamy) 1 tbsp massaman curry paste water to thin peanut sauce Directions Cut the chicken into 1/2 inch thick strips. Mix chicken with oyster sauce, tumeric, 1 tbsp sugar and coconut milk.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Paprikash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-paprikash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-paprikash/</guid><description>Chicken Paprikash is a delicious meal from Hungary, and I hope you are also Hungary! I make it all the time when I have guests.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 8 bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs salt to taste pepper to taste 2 cups chicken or beef broth 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 medium sized onions 1 tablespoon powdered garlic 3 tablespoons tomato paste 1/4 cup Hungarian paprika or regular paprika 1 tablespoon cayenne pepper (optional) 1 cup sour cream (optional) Directions Pat raw chicken thighs with paper towels for crispier skin.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🍳 Cook time: 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 can (29 ounces) tomato puree 1-1/2 cups plain yogurt 1/2 large onion, finely chopped 2 tablespoons olive oil 4-1/2 teaspoons minced fresh gingerroot 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 tablespoon garam masala 2-1/2 teaspoons salt 1-1/2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 teaspoon paprika 3/4 teaspoon pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2-1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 1-1/2-inch cubes 1 jalapeno pepper, halved and seeded 1 bay leaf 1 tablespoon cornstarch 1 cup heavy whipping cream Hot cooked basmati rice Chopped fresh cilantro, optional Directions In a 5-qt.</description></item><item><title>Honey Sriracha Chicken Thighs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</guid><description>This recipe yields a batch of relatively spicy chicken thighs. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy foods, you can add more honey and less sriracha. Conversely, if you like spicy foods, consider a 1:1 ratio of sriracha and honey.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40-45 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 5-6 bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs 1 tablespoon olive oil 1/3 cup honey 2 tablespoons sriracha hot sauce 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt 1/2 teaspoon black pepper Sesame seeds as a garnish (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 350°F Season the chicken.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tenders Airfried</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Raw chicken strips Flour Egg wash Bread crumbs Olive oil Seasoning: salt and pepper with cayenne or paprika (optional) Directions In a plate, mix a little over a table spoon of spices into your flour. Dip the chicken into the flour one strip at a time coating the entire surface. Dip the floured chicken into the eggwash.</description></item><item><title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid><description>Very easy, high protein.
Servings: 2 Ingredients 1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice 1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas 1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli) 2 chicken breasts 1 tbsp honey 1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce 1 tbsp minced garlic Directions Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in. While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube.</description></item><item><title>Asian Style Chicken with Sticky Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</guid><description>Asian style crispy coated chicken with sweetish sauce recipe. Served with boiled rice.
Ingredients Chicken with crispy coating Around 14 ounces or 400 grams of chicken breast 1 Egg 3 tbsp of cornflour 10 tbsp all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp garlic powder 2 tsp paprika powder Around 5 tbsp of sesame oil for frying the chicken Sauce 1 tbsp sesame oil 2 garlic cloves, mashed to paste. 1 tbsp Chinese rice vinegar or alternatively white wine vinegar 3 tbsp honey 2 tbsp ketchup 2 tbsp brown sugar 4 tbsp soy sauce Directions Prepare the sauce by mixing the ingredients together in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Lemon and oregano chicken traybake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (in 10 minute intervals) 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 8 chicken thighs (skin on) 500g new potato 100g bacon lardon 8 shallots 5 oregano sprigs / heavy sprinkle of oregano leaves 2 tbsp olive oil 2 lemons 200ml chicken stock 100ml white wine Directions Heat oven to 220C/200C with fan/gas 7. While oven is heating up cut the new potatoes into 0.</description></item><item><title>Kalderetang Manok</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kalderetang-manok/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kalderetang-manok/</guid><description>Classic Filipino dish, great paired with freshly cooked rice and a bottle of Coca Cola.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min. 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr. 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 1 lb of chicken 2 chopped potatoes 2 chopped carrots 1 chopped onion 2 chopped cloves of garlic 1 chopped tomato (optional) 3 cups of water Tomato sauce Chopped bell pepper Dried peas Liver spread Fish sauce Grated cheese Directions Sauté onions, garlic and (optional) tomato, in a pan of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Nashville Chicken Sandwich</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</guid><description>If you love spicy foods and chicken then this Nashville Hot Chicken sandwich recipe is just for you. It takes some time with prepping and process but when you take that first bite all the effort will be worth it. It’s unlike any other fried chicken recipe that includes double frying your chicken and using the same cooking oil from your fry as a sauce for the Nashville Hot Chicken spice.</description></item><item><title>Simple Chicken Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</guid><description>An easy chicken curry recipe which scales very well (double it, triple it, etc.). Best served with rice.
Servings: 3-4
Ingredients Spices
1 ½ tsp Coriander 1 tsp Cumin ½ tsp Turmeric ½ tsp Ground Fennel Seeds ½ tsp Cinnamon ½ tsp Black Pepper ½ tsp Ginger ¼ tsp Mustard ¼ tsp Ground Cloves Sriracha Sauce (optional) Main Ingredients
¼ cup (½ stick) Butter 1 large Onion 4 cloves Garlic 2-3 cups Chicken Broth 2-3 cups Crushed or Pureed Tomatoes 1 ½ lbs Boneless Skinless Chicken Breasts Directions Mince the garlic and dice the onion.</description></item><item><title>Pozharskiye Cutlets</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</guid><description>Famous Russian cutlet recipe, favoured by Nicholas I. Despite what seems to be a massive amount of butter required, they&amp;rsquo;re rather light, yet creamy.
Ingredients Chicken mince Butter (originally, 1 part butter per 2 parts chicken; 1/4 works perfectly fine) Eggs (~1 egg per 500g chicken, plus 3-5 for the breading) A couple white bread loaves (store-bought breadcrumbs also suffice, but require more eggs) Spices/salt (optional, recommended) Non-lard based, non-chunky sauce (optional) Onions (optional) Directions Prepare 2 medium-sized and 1 extra large bowl, a few plates and a regular frying pan.</description></item><item><title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter 1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs) 4 shallots, finely chopped 1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar 1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream Finely chopped parsley (optional) Directions Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup that is adaptable to customizing to your desired vegetables or other additions
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: Ingredients 2 chicken breasts 1 Onion 2 carrots 2 celery stalks 32 oz / 950ml Chicken Stock or Broth Pasta (Optional) Directions Cook chicken breasts, shred, and set aside in a bowl. Cut up carrots and celery, place in pot and saute.</description></item><item><title>Stir Fried Chicken with an Orange Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</guid><description>I could have called this Orange Chicken but I feel like some people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t classify my recipe that way.
Ingredients Chicken (a pound or two) Oranges An Onion Two Red Bell Peppers Soy Sauce Honey Butter Flour Directions Chop your onion and red bell peppers into small bits and throw them in a large frying pan to cook with a pat of butter, stirring occasionally. Chop your chicken into small bite sized pieces, add them to your pan once your onions begin to become translucent.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken Masala Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</guid><description>Butter chicken Masala is one of India&amp;rsquo;s most popular chicken recipes, a mild curry with a tomato-onion-cream base and boneless chicken pieces cooked in it to perfection.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients Boneless Chicken 1/2lb, cubed Butter Melted 2 tbsp Onions 2 medium-sized, minced Tomato 2 medium-sized, pureed Oil 2 tbsp Lemon juice 1 tbsp Garlic cloves 3, minced/crushed Ginger 1tbsp, minced/paste Garam Masala/Chicken Masala 1 tbsp Cream 4tbsp (or cashew paste) Chilli Powder 1 tbsp Turmeric powder 1/4 tbsp Crushed fenugreek leaves 1/4 tbsp 1 small bunch of coriander leaves / cilantro, for ganish Directions In a bowl, mix chicken with salt, pepper, 1/2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1/2 tbsp chili powder, turmeric powder, and lemon juice for the chicken marinade; let marinate for an hour.</description></item><item><title>Spatchcock Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (3 1/2) pound whole chickens, wingtips removed 2 teaspoons salt 1 teaspoon dried tarragon 1 teaspoon paprika 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 4 teaspoons olive oil 2 lemons, thinly sliced and seeded Directions Preheat oven to 450 degrees F (230 degrees C). Line a large rimmed baking sheet with foil. Place chicken, breast side down, on a work surface. Starting at the tail end, cut along both sides of backbone with kitchen shears.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid><description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Noodle Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</guid><description>This is a very easy and simple Japanese style ramen noodle soup. This is very cheap to make, and you can really customise this however you wish with the garnish. This is my own spin inspired by other recipes that I found.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 20 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 750ml Chicken stock 4 Pork chops OR 4 Chicken Breasts Set honey 3 Garlic cloves Soy sauce Worcestershire sauce Ginger, sliced Chinese 5 Spice 1 Red Chilli, sliced and deseeded (Optional, but recommended) 375g Ramen Noodles (Medium Egg Noodles work well too) 100g Spinach (Optional) 4 Tbsp Sweetcorn (Optional) Sesame seeds (Optional) 4 Boiled Eggs (Optional) 1 Sheet of Dried Nori (Optional) Spring Onion, chopped (Optional) Directions For the broth, add 700ml of chicken stock to a large boiling pot with the garlic, ginger, soy sauce, chinese five spice, chili, and 300ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Pan-seared Chicken Fillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</guid><description>This is a quick and easy recipe to prepare delicious chicken fillets that are juicy on the inside, and crisp on the outside.
Ingredients For this recipe I don&amp;rsquo;t use any exact proportions, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of cooking it one time to get a sense of what the ideal proportions for you are.
Chicken fillet(s); I normally use chicken breasts Wheat flour Paprika Garlic powder Herbes de Provence Directions Rinse the chicken fillets.</description></item><item><title>Roasted chicken breast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</guid><description>How to roast chicken breast with a &amp;ldquo;leave-in&amp;rdquo; probe thermometer. The thermometer ensures the chicken comes out juicy and delicious.
Ingredients Boneless skinless chicken breast(s) 1/4 stick of butter per chicken breast Seasoning (optional) Directions Fill a large bowl with enough water to submerge the chicken. Add salt to the water until it&amp;rsquo;s fully saturated. Put the chicken under the water and let it sit for 20-40 minutes at room temperature.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Biscuit Potpie Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</guid><description>Ingredients 1-2/3 cups frozen mixed vegetables, thawed 1-1/2 cups cubed cooked chicken 1 can (10-3/4 ounces) condensed cream of chicken soup, undiluted 1/4 teaspoon dried thyme 1 cup biscuit/baking mix 1/2 cup whole milk 1 large egg Directions Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). In a large bowl, combine the vegetables, chicken, soup and thyme. Pour into an ungreased deep-dish 9-in. pie plate. Combine the biscuit mix, milk and egg; spoon over chicken mixture.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Parmesan</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</guid><description>The recipe that started this very site.
Ingredients chicken breasts tomatoes (San Marzano is best) mozzarella cheese parmesan cheese bread crumbs eggs flour pasta sauce Directions Slice the chicken breasts through their width so that they are as flat as possible. Pound breasts as flat as possible. Add flour to a bowl or basin large enough to fit a breast, add pepper. Crack eggs into another large bowl or basin and whisk them.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Stock or Bone Broth</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</guid><description>Chicken stock, or &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; is not a final dish in itself, but is used in many soups and other dishes to add great taste to something otherwise very simple. While it is easy to make, it sells for very expensive in the store, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to know to make by yourself since it can be done very cheaply.
Ingredients a whole raw chicken with organs removed (Drumsticks or thighs alone might suffice if a whole chicken is unavailable.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Wings</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</guid><description>Perfectly cooked fall off the bone buffalo wings.
Ingredients Chicken wings and drums Enough Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot Sauce to marinate and top dress* Reynold&amp;rsquo;s Oven Bag Directions Soak your wings in Franks RedHot overnight Preheat your oven to 350°F (175°C) Transfer wings to the Reynold&amp;rsquo;s bag, seal it, and put it in the oven for an hour Crank up your grill† to high heat Throw the wings on the grill to char the skin and dress with a light top coat of Franks * Not the &amp;ldquo;wing sauce&amp;rdquo; version</description></item><item><title>Chicken, Tomato and Spinach Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tomato-spinach-curry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tomato-spinach-curry/</guid><description>This dish is a very simple and tasty curry that can be made with minimal ingredients, but pairs amazingly with anything else one may want in a curry (i.e. ginger, lemongrass). Note: You may also need a blender / food processor.
Ingredients 500g or 1lb of chicken breast Virgin olive oil (1/2 cup or ~100ml) Fresh tomatoes of any variety (10 - 15 medium sized) Two medium sized onions 250g or 1/2lbs of fresh spinach Curry powder of your favourite variety Red chilies (or red chilli paste) Any extra herbs or spices to your taste Directions Dice your onions, begin to fry in the pot at a medium-low temperature.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Chicken Tacos</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients chicken breasts two or three onions (preferably red) seasoning: adobo seasoning paprika cheese (either shredded Mexican blend or crumbling cheese) small tortillas lime cilantro, tomato, lettuce, other desired taco contents Directions Quarter two onions and spread on the bottom of a slow-cooker. Place chicken breasts on top of onions. Season slow-cooker contents liberally with adobo seasoning, paprika and any other desired seasonings, squeeze half of a lime too if desired.</description></item></channel></rss>