<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lamb on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/lamb/</link><description>Recent content in lamb on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/lamb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need a good-sized lidded pot that can go in the oven for this. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that then you can use a large roasting tray with sides and cover it with foil, sealing it as best you can. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent celebration or Sunday meal.
Ingredients Lamb shoulder, or something similar, like lamb shank, preferably on the bone. Get something that will fit in your pot, with room for vegetables around it.</description></item><item><title>Shepherd's Pie</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shepherds-pie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shepherds-pie/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 50 - 60 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 - 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 600 grams (g) of mealy/floury potatoes 2 onions 2 carrots 4 tablespoons (tbsp.) of oil 800 g of minced lamb 100 g of frozen peas 2 tbsp. of tomato paste/puree 300 milliliters (ml) beef stock 1 tbsp. of sweet or smoked paprika 30 g of butter 200 ml of milk 1 pinch of nutmeg Directions Peel potatoes, cut into cubes and boil in saltwater for 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Tuh'u</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuhu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuhu/</guid><description>Tuh&amp;rsquo;u (Akkadian for possibly &amp;ldquo;beetroot&amp;rdquo;) is an ancient Mesopotamian spring festival dish, a lamb stew of sorts, extracted by historians at Yale Babylonian Collection from tablets from Babylonia, ca. 1740 BC.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 60-90 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 450 g of lamb leg meat, diced 4 tbsp of sesame oil, olive oil, or rendered fat 350 mL of prepared water 350 mL of sour-tasting beer (e.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Biriyani</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</guid><description>This recipe makes an Southern Indian (Tamil) style Lamb biriyani that has been adapted to a more western audience (aka a bit less spicy) and can be made with either Lamb or Mutton. Best served with a sauce such as an onion raitha.
A plated rendering of the dish, made with Mutton. Makes a really hearty ,meaty and delicious dish. The dishes uses a rice to meat ratio of 2:3. PS: the biriyani tastes better the longer it&amp;rsquo;s allowed to soak in it&amp;rsquo;s flavour after cooking.</description></item><item><title>Pilaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</guid><description>Popular central asian and middle eastern dish. High in nutrition, designed to be prepared and eaten communally.
Ingredients 150ml cooking oil 1kg long grain rice 1.5kg meat (lamb or any other kind of meat) 500g onions 500g carrots 2 tbsp salt 5 cloves of garlic raisins, cardamom, paprika, coriander, cinnamon, cumin, turmeric (all optional) Directions Put the cooking oil in a cauldron and heat it until the oil is boiling, add a head of onion until it is black, then throw it out.</description></item><item><title>Traditional beef or lamb stew</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a typical Irish stew. This is traditionally made with lamb since it&amp;rsquo;s cheaper however, beef tastes a lot better and is more readily available in North America I&amp;rsquo;ve been told. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 2 or 3 days. Besides browning the meat this is really just throwing stuff into a pot in a certain order.</description></item></channel></rss>