<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stew on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/stew/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stew on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/stew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carbonade Flamande (Traditional Flemish beef stew)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</guid>
      <description>This one is a delicious slow cooked beef stewed in beer. The smoked bacon is not in the traditional recipe but it&amp;rsquo;s good. Don&amp;rsquo;t add it if you want the real deal.
 🍳 Cook time: 4-8 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  beef (chuck, brisket, oxtail&amp;hellip;): 1kg | 2 1/4lb gingerbread: 5 slices brown sugar: 1tbsp brown beer (try to get a strong, tasty one): 1L | 4 cups onions: 400g | 1lb diced smoked bacon: 250g | 1/2lb (optional) mustard butter vegetable oil thyme cloves(not garlic cloves, just cloves): 5 juniper berries: 5 bay leaves: 2  Directions  Cut meat into big chunks Dice onions Sear the meat on high heat in a large stainless or cast iron pot until golden brown, using vegetable oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoofvlees</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</guid>
      <description>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions. Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 to 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  2 Large onions 1 tablespoon butter 1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces 2 33cl bottles of brown beer 2 bayleaves 2 twigs of thyme 1 clove (spice) 2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon) 2 teaspoons of vinegar 1 slice of bread mustard  Directions  Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&amp;rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traditional beef or lamb stew</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe for a typical Irish stew. This is traditionally made with lamb since it&amp;rsquo;s cheaper however, beef tastes a lot better and is more readily available in North America I&amp;rsquo;ve been told. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 2 or 3 days. Besides browning the meat this is really just throwing stuff into a pot in a certain order.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
