<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salad on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/salad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salad on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/salad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Caesar Salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid>
      <description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients  Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing  Directions  Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crab salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 3  Ingredients  Сrab meat (300 grams) Egg (3) Rice (50 grams) Corn (1 can) Cucumber (1) Carrot (1) Onion (1) Mayonnaise (100 grams)  Directions  Boil rice, eggs and carrot Chop crab meat and all other ingredients Combine and mix all ingredients Add mayonnaise Chill before serving  Contribution Anonymous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Croutons</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid>
      <description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients  Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices  Directions  Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dianne&#39;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</guid>
      <description>Dianne&amp;rsquo;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad is as colorful as it is delicious.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 🥶 Chill: 2 hrs  Ingredients  1 (6-ounce) package Mexican cornbread mix 1 (1-ounce) envelope buttermilk Ranch salad dressing mix 1 small head romaine lettuce, shredded 2 large tomatoes, chopped 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (8-ounce) package shredded Mexican four-cheese blend 6 bacon slices, cooked and crumbled 5 green onions, chopped  Directions  Prepare cornbread according to package directions, cool, and crumble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon juice salad dressing</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</guid>
      <description>A dressing that goes well on lettuce or any other mixed greens.
Ingredients  Lemon juice from half a lemon Tablespoon of olive oil Clove of garlic  Directions  Combine lemon juice and oil in small bowl. Add salt and pepper to taste. Add the garlic, pressed or finely minced. Mix well before adding to salad.  Contribution  Martin Chrzanowski &amp;ndash; website, donate  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
