<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>french on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/french/</link><description>Recent content in french on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smoked Salmon Quiche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 60 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 3/4 cups Flour 1 cup + 2 1/2 Tbsp Butter, divided Up to 1/3 cup Water, chilled 1/2 cup Onion, finely chopped 14 ounces Smoked Salmon, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Chives, chopped 1 clove Garlic, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Basil, chopped 5 whole Eggs 1 cup Milk 1 cup Whipping Cream Directions Combine all pastry ingredients in a food processor (mix flour and butter, then add water gradually while mixing).</description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 12 min 🍳 Cook time: 75 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 3 1/2 lbs Tomatoes 1 1/2 lbs Eggplant 1 lb Zucchini 3 Bell Peppers 2 lbs Onions 6 cloves Garlic Herbes de Provence (Basil, Thyme, Parsley) Olive Oil Salt Pepper 140g Tomato Paste (optional if tomatoes aren&amp;rsquo;t yummy) Directions Peel and drain the tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t mind the seeds): cut out the stem cores; drop the whole tomatoes into boiling water for 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Farcies tomatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</guid><description>Farcies tomates with rice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 tomatoes per person. 300g of ground beef meat. 1 or 2 onions. Condiments of your choice: Parsley, origan or cumin. Olive oil Gruyere cheese. Salt and pepper. Optional: Butter. Directions Heat the oven to 200C. Slice the top to the tomatoes and place them in the oven tray.</description></item><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients For the bechamel 50g Butter 50g Flour 1 Liter of milk Salt Ground Pepper Nutmeg For the bites 12 Slices of bread 2 Tbsp of Mustard 12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs 80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette Directions Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan.</description></item><item><title>Quiche Lorraine - Lothringer Käsetorte</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 160 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 200g Flour (full sight) 100g Butter or Margarine 5 Tablespoons of Water 200g of Ham (alternatively cooked ham) 4 Eggs 1/4 Cream 125g grinded Edamer Cheese For the Baking Tin: More Butter and Flour Directions Spread some butter on a 26cm Ø or two smaller baking tins and cover it with flour Sieve the flour, mingle the butter/margarine in small flakes.</description></item><item><title>Demi-glace</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</guid><description>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.
These are the basic proportions &amp;ndash; multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.
Ingredients 1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) low-sodium broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods) 1 1/4 oz (7g) packet unflavored, unsweetened gelatin 1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste 1 teaspoon (5mL) low-sodium soy sauce 1/2 teaspoon onion powder (very optional) Directions Put the tomato paste in a large pot, then turn the heat on medium Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown Deglaze with the broth Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume Freeze in ice cub trays</description></item><item><title>French Onion Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 6-7 Onions, cut into quarter moons 1 stick of butter 1/2 cup Olive oil Salt, to taste 1 Baguette Loaf, sliced 1 Can of Chicken Broth 3 Garlic cloves, finely chopped 1/4 cup brown sugar Balsamic vinegar, to taste Worcestershire Sauce, to taste Soy Sauce, to taste 64oz Beef Broth 2-3 Bay Leaves Melty cheese, preferably guereye or swiss Directions Sweat the onions in a covered Dutch oven over med-low heat, salt them, with 1 whole stick of butter and some olive oil for about 2 hours stirring occasionally but increasing in frequency as the heat gets raised over time.</description></item><item><title>Lobster bisque</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid><description>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 🍳Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 litres Ingredients 1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams 2 onions 2 carrots 1 shallot 2 garlic cloves cognac 3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree 4 tomatoes 3 tbsp flour 1 glass dry white wine 2 litres fish stock 1 bayleaf 2 twigs of thyme fresh parsley heavy cream olive oil 2 tbsp butter Directions Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.</description></item><item><title>Classic béchamel sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid><description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min Ingredients 5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg Directions Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description></item><item><title>French Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</guid><description>This recipe results in five slices of easy to make french toast.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 2 Eggs 1/2 Cup of milk (1/4 for a more solid consistency) 5 Slices of bread Maple Syrup (Optional) Butter Directions Butter up a frying pan and set it on the burner with low-medium heat.(May need to add more butter in-between slices) Take your two eggs and crack them into a bowl together.</description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).
🍽️ Servings:1-4 Ingredients for 1 liter of Glühwein
300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice 1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :) 50 g Sugar 25 g Raisins 1 orange 1 cinamon bark 1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger) 1 spoon cloves 5 star anise if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre Directions cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration) throw everything in a pot warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil) enjoy</description></item><item><title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter 1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs) 4 shallots, finely chopped 1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar 1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream Finely chopped parsley (optional) Directions Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.</description></item><item><title>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</guid><description>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionally garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).
~15/20 galettes.
Ingredients 500g buckwheat flour 1 egg 70cl water Directions Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Let it rest one hour at room temperature. Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan. When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.</description></item><item><title>French Crêpes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid><description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients 300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil Directions Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description></item><item><title>Flammkuchen</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid><description>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up. I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.
🍽️ Servings:2 Ingredients 400g Pizza dough (either bought or from Pizza Dough) 1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons) 150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables) 2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche Directions we start by flattening the dough.</description></item><item><title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid><description>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.
🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients porkchops: 4 shallots: 2 gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup mustard: 2tbsp butter olive oil Directions Cut the shallots into small dices. Cut the gherkins into long strips. Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.</description></item></channel></rss>