<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>French on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/french/</link><description>Recent content in French on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smoked Salmon Quiche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 60 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 3/4 cups Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup + 2 1/2 Tbsp Butter, divided&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Up to 1/3 cup Water, chilled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Onion, finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>14 ounces Smoked Salmon, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Fresh Chives, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove Garlic, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tsp Fresh Basil, chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 whole Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup Whipping Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Combine all pastry ingredients in a food processor (mix flour and butter, then add water gradually while mixing).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gather into a ball, cover with plastic wrap and chill 1 hour.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Saute onion until shiny in the butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in salmon, chives, garlic, and basil. Cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven to 400F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roll out the dough to fit a 10&amp;quot; tart pan. Prick with a fork.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the salmon mixture in the pre-baked tart shell.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk eggs with milk and cream, season with pepper and pour in the tart shell.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake about 30 minutes at 325F, until puffed and golden.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 12 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 75 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 12&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 1/2 lbs Tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 lbs Eggplant&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lb Zucchini&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Bell Peppers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 lbs Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 cloves Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Herbes de Provence (Basil, Thyme, Parsley)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>140g Tomato Paste (optional if tomatoes aren&amp;rsquo;t yummy)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Peel and drain the tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t mind the seeds): cut out the stem cores; drop the whole tomatoes into boiling water for 2 minutes. Remove into a colander. The skin should split for easy removal; otherwise, make an X cut in the top, then peel off the skin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chop the onion and garlic. Clean the bell pepper, cut into small strips.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large cooking pot with thick bottom, put in olive oil, onions, and chopped garlic. Add in the bell pepper. Cover to keep in the moisture. Cook for 20 minutes, stirring frequently, and add olive oil as necessary to prevent burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the tomatoes and Herbes de Provence. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have good garden tomatoes with flavour, add a small can of tomato paste. Stir well and cook for another 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the eggplant into disks. Cut zucchini into disks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the eggplant and zucchini to the pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for about 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Farcies tomatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/farci_tomatoes.webp" alt="Farci tomatoes">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Farcies tomates with rice.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 tomatoes per person.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>300g of ground beef meat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 or 2 onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Condiments of your choice: Parsley, origan or cumin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gruyere cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optional: Butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heat the oven to 200C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slice the top to the tomatoes and place them in the oven tray.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Empty the tomatoes using a spoon and reserve the interior of the tomatoes in a bowl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix the interior of the tomatoes with the rest of the ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restuff the tomatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optionally add a thin layer of butter on top of the tomatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the &amp;ldquo;lid&amp;rdquo; on the tomatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 40 minutes in the oven.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoy!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/croque-monsieur.webp" alt="croquemsr">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 10 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For the bechamel
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>50g Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50g Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Liter of milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ground Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the bites
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>12 Slices of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tbsp of Mustard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As soon as it foams, sprinkle it with flour, salt, pepper, add a pinch of nutmeg, mix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then pour in the milk, little by little (especially not all at once), stirring with a whisk each time, until the sauce thickens.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn on the oven on th. 6/180°, take the baking sheet out of the oven and line it with aluminum foil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread 6 slices of bread in front of you, spread them with a little mustard, add a layer of béchamel, 1 slice of ham folded in 4, grated cheese, a layer of béchamel, put the other 6 slices of bread on the on top, add a thin layer of béchamel and distribute the rest of the grated cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the croque-monsieur on the baking sheet and put them in the oven for about 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can place them under the broiler for 3-4 minutes at the end.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Quiche Lorraine - Lothringer Käsetorte</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 160 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>200g Flour (full sight)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100g Butter or Margarine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Tablespoons of Water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>200g of Ham (alternatively cooked ham)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>125g grinded Edamer Cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the Baking Tin: More Butter and Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Spread some butter on a 26cm Ø or two smaller baking tins and cover it with flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sieve the flour, mingle the butter/margarine in small flakes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form a depression in the middle of the flour and add spoons of water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix all ingredients by hand until the dough becomes a homogenious mass.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wrap the dough in aluminium foil and let it rest in the fridge for two hours (around -4 °C).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat the oven at 200°C.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread the dough on a flour-covered surface. Roll it until it has a thickness of around 4mm. Form a crust on the sides.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use a fork to prick the dough for a more thorough heat penetration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the ham in slices and distribute them evenly on the dough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide the yolk from the egg white.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk the yolk with cream.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the grinded cheese.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whisk the egg white until it becomes foamy. Add it to the yolk-pepper-salt-cheese mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover the ham in the baking tin with the mixture. Equalize the surface.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake the Quiche in the oven on the middle rail for 30 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After baking leave it to rest for a few minutes, then serve while it&amp;rsquo;s still warm.
I recommend serving it with a glass of white wine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Demi-glace</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are the basic proportions &amp;ndash; multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) &lt;strong>low-sodium&lt;/strong> broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/4 oz (7g) packet &lt;strong>unflavored, unsweetened&lt;/strong> gelatin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon (5mL) &lt;strong>low-sodium&lt;/strong> soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 teaspoon onion powder (&lt;em>very&lt;/em> optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put the tomato paste in a large pot, &lt;em>then&lt;/em> turn the heat on medium&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with the broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freeze in ice cub trays&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>French Onion Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 3 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 5&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>6-7 Onions, cut into quarter moons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 stick of butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup Olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Baguette Loaf, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Can of Chicken Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Garlic cloves, finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup brown sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Balsamic vinegar, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worcestershire Sauce, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Soy Sauce, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>64oz Beef Broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 Bay Leaves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Melty cheese, preferably guereye or swiss&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sweat the onions in a covered Dutch oven over med-low heat, salt them, with 1 whole stick of butter and some olive oil for about 2 hours stirring occasionally but increasing in frequency as the heat gets raised over time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the onions are soft and mostly shrunken down, and mostly covered by the butter, oil, and onion juice, strain and collect the juice in a bowl. Brush the onion juice over each side of slices of baguette bread.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return the strained onions to med-high heat, uncovered, stirring and deglazing with chicken broth frequently but not so frequent that they turn to mush. When the entire can of chicken broth has been added for deglazing, add 3 finely chopped garlic cloves, 1/4 cup brown sugar, balsamic vinegar, Worcestershire sauce, soy sauce. Wait until the pot dries and a fond is formed in between adding each liquid ingredient slowly. Keep slowly deglazing with the wooden spoon and caramelizing those onions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After onions are thoroughly caramelized and there are no more liquid ingredients to add, pour in 64oz beef broth and 2-3 Bay leaves. Cover on medium heat until it simmers. It is now ready to serve!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put sliced (and onion-juice brushed) bread in 400F oven until toasted, then under the broiler covered in cheese until melted. Soup can be served poured over the bread slices or the bread floating on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Lobster bisque</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 20&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳Cook time: 30 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 2 litres&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 shallot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 garlic cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cognac&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tomatoes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 glass dry white wine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 litres fish stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bayleaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 twigs of thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fresh parsley&lt;/li>
&lt;li>heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blanche the lobster in boiling water for 2 minutes, remove from the water and let it leak.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut it down the middle and remove the meat from the shell, set the meat aside for later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place a stockpot on medium high heat and heat up enough oil to cover the bottom of the pan, add the lobster shells and cook them until they are bright red.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the oil from the pan and discard it, add your butter to the shells.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add all diced vegetables and let it sauté for 2 minutes, add a dash of cognac and flambé, lower the heat to medium low.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roughly dice the tomatoes and add them together with the tomato puree, once again let it sauté for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the flour and give it all a stir, let it dry up in the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze the pan with the white wine and once the wine has dried up a bit add the fish stock.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tie up your herbs using kitchen twine and add them to your pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it simmer on low heat for 30 minutes, while the soup is boiling take the lobster meat and dice it into bite-sized pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After the soup is done boiling run it through a fine sieve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring the strained soup back to a light boil and add the diced lobster pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the soup boil for 4 more minutes to heat up the lobster and serve, add pepper and salt to taste.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finish off in the plate with a bit of heavy cream.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Classic béchamel sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;p>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 0m&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>5 Teaspoons unsalted butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Teaspoons flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 litre whole milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pepper to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pinch of nutmeg&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep stiring your roux on medium low heat until it gets lightly golden brown and starts melling a bit nutty.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add about a glass of your whole milk and stir until combined, repeat this process until you have a thick sauce in your pan and new milk you add easily combines. Never stop stirring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At this point you can add the rest of your milk, if you skip the previous step you will end up with lumps of roux that are hard to get out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lower your heat to low and keep stiring don&amp;rsquo;t forget to get in the corners of the pot because your sauce will burn easily.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once your sauce has the desired thickness give it a taste and add your salt and pepper until it is to your liking. A pinch of nutmeg, preferably freshly grated, will also go a long way.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>French Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/french-toast.webp" alt="French Toast">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This recipe results in five slices of easy to make french toast.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 Eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup of milk (1/4 for a more solid consistency)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Slices of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maple Syrup (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Butter up a frying pan and set it on the burner with low-medium heat.(May need to add more butter in-between slices)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take your two eggs and crack them into a bowl together.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour milk in the bowl with the eggs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Break the yolks and stir the eggs and milk well with a beater until it&amp;rsquo;s a smooth, yellow liquid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dip one side of bread into the bowl, making sure the liquid gets into all of the surface area of that side.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Immediately bring the side back up and scrape off any access liquid on the side with a butter knife.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat steps 5-6, but for the other side of the bread.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drop into the hot pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook both sides until golden brown, then plop onto a plate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat steps 5 to 9 until you have cooked all of your bread.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Drench french toast stack in Maple syrup (Optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings:1-4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>for 1 liter of Glühwein&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>50 g Sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>25 g Raisins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 orange&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cinamon bark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 spoon cloves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 star anise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>throw everything in a pot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enjoy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍳 Cook time: 25 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 shallots, finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finely chopped parsley (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat oil and melt butter in deep-sided, 12-inch (~30 centimeter) sauté pan on medium-high heat. When the oil is hot, but not smoking, use tongs to add chicken skin side down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brown both sides until skin is golden brown and chicken is cooked, about 12-15 minutes. Remove chicken to a platter and cover loosely with aluminum foil to keep warm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour out half of oil from pan, and use other half to brown shallots over medium-high heat. Slowly add vinegar and boil until reduced to almost a syrup. Add crème fraîche/cream and cook until blended and brown, about 5 minutes. Return chicken to pan to coat and heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return chicken to platter. Add garnish if available, and serve.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionally garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>~15/20 galettes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>500g buckwheat flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>70cl water&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it rest one hour at room temperature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Always keep the crepe-maker&amp;rsquo;s T stick in water while cooking so the dough doesn&amp;rsquo;t dry on it.
It will then be easier to spread the dough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>French Crêpes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like pancakes, but very thin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>15 crêpes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>300g white flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>60cl milk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>20cl beer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let it rest one hour. (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="tips">Tips&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Oil the pan frequently with an oiled piece of fabric.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the pan to be hot before cooking the first crêpe.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait until the crêpe has dried up to flip it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When pouring the dough, follow the pan rotation with the ladle to evenly spread a thin layer of it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/croutons.webp" alt="croutons">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hearty White Bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extra Virgin Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spices&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread. Spices can be anything but I recommend oregano, paprika, black pepper, garlic powder or freshly minced garlic, and a small pinch of cayenne.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread seasoned bread squares large face down onto a baking sheet evenly and put in oven for 6-8 minutes. Once the bread has crisped flip each square and put back in oven for another 6-8 minutes or until crispy throughout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once fully baked, let rest until cool. These can be eaten immediately or saved in a sandwich bag for later.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Flammkuchen</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up.
I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings:2&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>400g Pizza dough (either bought or from &lt;a href="/android_asset/html/pizza-dough">Pizza Dough&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>we start by flattening the dough. Even if you buy thin crust that is already sold as &amp;lsquo;super thin&amp;rsquo; you have to make it even thinner. Make it so thin that you can fill 2 baking sheets with it (yes, you will make two large flammkuchen - since they are thin you need one per person) :) I take two pieces of parchment paper, put the dough in between and flatten it using a bottle (e.g. wine). It has to be as thin as possible (1-2 mm).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>once the dough is flat, put it on your baking tray and preheat the oven at 450 to 500 Fahrenheit (230 to 260 Celsius)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>distribute the sour cream evenly (it should be a very thin layer, just barely covering the dough&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cut the onion and bacon into small pieces and distribute onion, bacon/vegetables (also in small pieces) evenly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put in the oven for 10 minutes and take it out when it is getting a bit dark. The thin parts will get a bit brown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>put salt and pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I usually take it down from the baking tray and let it cool down for 2-5 minutes before eating&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid><description>&lt;p>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>porkchops: 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>shallots: 2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones&lt;/li>
&lt;li>white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mustard: 2tbsp&lt;/li>
&lt;li>butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the shallots into small dices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the gherkins into long strips.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the porkchops are cooked, set them aside in a warm environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sweat the shallots in the same pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze with white wine, let it reduce until there&amp;rsquo;s about two teaspoons left.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the stock.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the gherkins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in the mustard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Let the sauce reduce until it gets a coating consistency.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mix in a knob a butter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Put the chops back in, flip them to coat them in sauce, warm them up for 30 seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve with a nice mashed potato or saute potatoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>