<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>French on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/french/</link>
    <description>Recent content in French on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</guid>
      <description>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionally garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).
~15/20 galettes.
Ingredients  500g buckwheat flour 1 egg 70cl water  Directions  Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Let it rest one hour at room temperature. Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan. When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 6  Ingredients  3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter 1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs) 4 shallots, finely chopped 1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar 1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream Finely chopped parsley (optional)  Directions  Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic béchamel sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
 ⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min  Ingredients  5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg  Directions  Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Croutons</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid>
      <description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients  Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices  Directions  Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flammkuchen</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid>
      <description>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up. I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.
 🍽️ Servings:2  Ingredients  400g Pizza dough (either bought or from Pizza Dough) 1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons) 150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables) 2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche  Directions  we start by flattening the dough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Crêpes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid>
      <description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients  300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil  Directions  Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid>
      <description>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.
 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  porkchops: 4 shallots: 2 gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup mustard: 2tbsp butter vegetable oil  Directions  Cut the shallots into small dices. Cut the gherkins into long strips. Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Onion Soup</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</guid>
      <description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 5  Ingredients  6-7 Onions, cut into quarter moons 1 stick of butter 1/2 cup Olive oil Salt, to taste 1 Baguette Loaf, sliced 1 Can of Chicken Broth 3 Garlic cloves, finely chopped 1/4 cup brown sugar Balsamic vinegar, to taste Worcestershire Sauce, to taste Soy Sauce, to taste 64oz Beef Broth 2-3 Bay Leaves Melty cheese, preferably guereye or swiss  Directions  Sweat the onions in a covered Dutch oven over med-low heat, salt them, with 1 whole stick of butter and some olive oil for about 2 hours stirring occasionally but increasing in frequency as the heat gets raised over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lobster bisque</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid>
      <description>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 🍳Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 litres  Ingredients  1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams 2 onions 2 carrots 1 shallot 2 garlic cloves cognac 3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree 4 tomatoes 3 tbsp flour 1 glass dry white wine 2 litres fish stock 1 bayleaf 2 twigs of thyme fresh parsley heavy cream canola oil 2 tbsp butter  Directions  Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
