<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>southwest on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/southwest/</link><description>Recent content in southwest on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/southwest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fajitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time:15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/4 cup + 1/2 tsp Lime Juice, divided 3 Tbsp Olive Oil, divided 4 cloves Garlic, crushed 3 tsp Soy Sauce, divided 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Liquid Smoke 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1/4 tsp Black Pepper 1 lb Chicken Breasts or Skirt Steak, bones/skin removed 2 Tbsp Water 1 large Spanish Onion, thinly sliced 1/2 each Green, Red, and Yellow Bell Pepper, thinly sliced Directions Combine 1/4 cup lime juice, 2 Tbsp of the oil, garlic, 2 tsp soy sauce, the salt, liquid smoke, cayenne pepper, and black pepper in a resealable container, add chicken/steak, cover, and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or overnight.</description></item><item><title>Mexican Meat Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 lb Lean Ground Beef 1 cup Black Beans (canned), rinsed and drained 1 cup Salsa, divided 1/2 cup Corn (frozen) 1/2 cup Bread Crumbs Cooking Spray Directions In bowl, place all ingredients except spray and using 3/4 cup of the salsa - mix well. Spray a loaf pan (approx. 5&amp;quot;x9&amp;quot;), and add above mix. Bake for 50 to 60 minutes - sit 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Dianne's Southwestern Cornbread Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</guid><description>Dianne&amp;rsquo;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad is as colorful as it is delicious.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 🥶 Chill: 2 hrs Ingredients 1 (6-ounce) package Mexican cornbread mix 1 (1-ounce) envelope buttermilk Ranch salad dressing mix 1 small head romaine lettuce, shredded 2 large tomatoes, chopped 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (8-ounce) package shredded Mexican four-cheese blend 6 bacon slices, cooked and crumbled 5 green onions, chopped Directions Prepare cornbread according to package directions, cool, and crumble.</description></item><item><title>Loaded Mexican Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</guid><description>A tex-mex style mexican rice with beans and meat. Adding the beans and meat take it from a side dish to good good burrito filling. :x
Ingredients 5 serving
1 Cup uncooked long grain white rice 1/2 Cup frozen peas 1/2 Cup frozen corn 2 Caned adobo chilies chopped 5 Tbsp tomato paste 1 Can of black or pinto beans 1/2 Cup ground meat (optional) 1/4 Onion diced (optional) Directions Cook rice per manufactures instructions.</description></item></channel></rss>