<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>beef on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/beef/</link><description>Recent content in beef on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/beef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zurich-Style Meat Saute</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</guid><description>Originally called &amp;ldquo;Züri Gschnätzlets&amp;rdquo; (Zurich chopped) from the city of Zurich in Switzerland, this is a tasty and practical recipe from simple ingredients. You can use any kind of meat really, depending on your taste. Very traditionally, finely sliced liver and kidney is also mixed in with the meat and mushrooms.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 600g Beef, finely sliced 250g Mushrooms, finely sliced 1 Onion 1 tbsp Flour 200ml White whine 200ml Cream 1 tbsp chopped parsley Directions Fry the meat in butter at high heat until it starts loosing liquid.</description></item><item><title>Hakka-Style Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1/2 lb Ground Beef 1/4 cup Panko Breadcrumbs 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce, divided 4 tsp Chili Garlic Sauce 1/2 oz Ginger, minced 2 medium Green Bell Peppers 1 small Onion, chopped 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 2 oz Green Peas 1/2 cup Cilantro, loosely packed 1 Tbsp Moroccan Spice Blend, divided 4 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F.</description></item><item><title>Beef and Broccoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1/2 lb Beef, cut into strips 2 Tbsp Vegetable Oil 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 2 cloves Garlic, minced 1 cup Carrots, sliced Snow Peas Bean Sprouts 1 cup Broccoli Pieces 1/2 cup Beef Bouillon 1 Tbsp Corn starch 1 Tbsp Soy Sauce Directions Heat oil, add beef and stir-fry until meat is browned and push to sides of pan.</description></item><item><title>Fajitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time:15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/4 cup + 1/2 tsp Lime Juice, divided 3 Tbsp Olive Oil, divided 4 cloves Garlic, crushed 3 tsp Soy Sauce, divided 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Liquid Smoke 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1/4 tsp Black Pepper 1 lb Chicken Breasts or Skirt Steak, bones/skin removed 2 Tbsp Water 1 large Spanish Onion, thinly sliced 1/2 each Green, Red, and Yellow Bell Pepper, thinly sliced Directions Combine 1/4 cup lime juice, 2 Tbsp of the oil, garlic, 2 tsp soy sauce, the salt, liquid smoke, cayenne pepper, and black pepper in a resealable container, add chicken/steak, cover, and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or overnight.</description></item><item><title>Mexican Meat Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 lb Lean Ground Beef 1 cup Black Beans (canned), rinsed and drained 1 cup Salsa, divided 1/2 cup Corn (frozen) 1/2 cup Bread Crumbs Cooking Spray Directions In bowl, place all ingredients except spray and using 3/4 cup of the salsa - mix well. Spray a loaf pan (approx. 5&amp;quot;x9&amp;quot;), and add above mix.</description></item><item><title>Teriyaki Beef Wok</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/teriyaki-beef/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/teriyaki-beef/</guid><description>If you have no wok, a regular pan will suffice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 dL water 2 tbsp cornstarch 1 tbsp honey 1/4 tsp ginger 3 tbsp soy sauce Sesame oil Beef slices or strips Carrot, sliced (optional) Broccoli, florets (optional) Baby corn (optional) Water chestnut, sliced (optional) Bean sprouts (optional) Chili pepper, diced (optional) Noodles or rice Directions Whisk water, cornstarch, honey, ginger and soy sauce.</description></item><item><title>Panang-Style Beef Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 315 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 lb Ground Beef 1 can (400mL) Coconut Milk 1 Red Chili Pepper 1/2 cup Red Curry Paste 4 tsp Peanut Butter 3/4 cup Jasmine Rice 2 Tbsp Cilantro 1 Sweet Bell Pepper 1/2 Onion (2 oz), chopped 1 Tbsp Garlic Puree 1 oz Peanuts, chopped 1/2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Mild Curry Paste Directions Start rice.</description></item><item><title>Chipolata Sausage in Balsamic Vinegar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</guid><description>Easy to prepare Italian dish with lots of flavour great for a relaxing evening dipping bread and sipping wine.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 12 chipolata sausages 4 red onions 500g of cherry tomatoes (preferably mixed species) 4 garlic cloves Fresh basil leaves Black balsamic vinegar 1 loaf of ciabatta bread Directions Pre-heat the oven to 200c (400f) Put the chipolata sausages in an oven dish Cut 4 red onions into quarters spread them out in the oven dish.</description></item><item><title>Scouse</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/scouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scouse/</guid><description>A hearty and cheap stew, that&amp;rsquo;s easy to make and is my go to dish to make and freeze on weeknights. This dish is really flexible and goes with virtually any vegetables you&amp;rsquo;ve got in your cupboard. Originated around Stoke and Liverpool as Lobscouse and later split into the dishes Lobby and Scouse.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients beef mince a white onion garlic bayleaf potatoes carrots beef stock ~1 pint beef gravy granules parsnips(optional) swede(optional) cabbage(optional) Directions Finely dice the onions and garlic.</description></item><item><title>Steak Tartare</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</guid><description>Steak Tartare is a dish prepared using raw ground / minced beef and egg yolk. A popular dish in Europe, this recipe is a good stepping stone into the world of raw meats, organs and pates.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Ground Beef (Lean as possible) Eggs Onion or Shallots Capers Gherkin / Cornichons Parsley (Optional) Ketchup (Optional) Mustard (Optional) Worcestershire Sauce (Optional) Directions Dice your onions or shallots.</description></item><item><title>Beef Wellington</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-wellington/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-wellington/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep Time: 10 min 🍳Cook Time: 2 hours 🍽️Servings: 4 Ingredients 1lb of Fillet Beef Extra Virgin Olive Oil 1lb of mushrooms 4 Thinly Cut Slices of Ham 2tbsp of Yellow Mustard 7oz of Puff Pastry 2 Egg Yolks Beaten Side note: Fillet beef is preferred. It gives the beef wellington a soft, tender and juicy flavour. Trust me, using fillet is worth it.
Directions Season the fillet with salt and black pepper.</description></item><item><title>Medieval Beef Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</guid><description>Medieval beef soup with turnips and turnip greens.
Ingredients One beef roast Around three to four large turnips with their greens attached Two cups of chicken stock 1/10 grams of Saffron 1/4 a stick of butter A slow cooker A bowl of warm water. Directions Cube the roast into bite sized pieces and place them in a large skillet with the butter. Heat the pan on medium-high heat and brown the meat with the melted butter until the outside is evenly cooked, sprinkle with pepper as it browns.</description></item><item><title>Beef Kidney</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</guid><description>My wife&amp;rsquo;s beef kidney recipe
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 beef kidney 60g butter 2 onions 2 shallots 1 sprig of fresh parsley 3 bay leaves 400g croutons or toasted bread in pieces Directions clean the kidney and remove the fat cut the kidney into small chunks (2cm or 3/4&amp;quot;) put butter in a casserole dish add kidney, parsley, bay leaf, salt, pepper brown in the casserole for 10 minutes while stirring (don&amp;rsquo;t burn) add 2 glasses of dry white wine add half a glass of water so that the mixture is well-bathed simmer for 35 minutes add about 400g of toasted bread in pieces simmer for another 10 minutes</description></item><item><title>Basic Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid><description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste Directions Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Meatloaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</guid><description>This recipe will result in two or three glass dishes of tasty, moist meatloaf. Great for family suppers.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 6+ Ingredients 4 1/2 pounds Ground beef 1 Onion 2 Slices of bread 4 Eggs 1/4 Cup of milk Garlic salt Onion powder Mustard Sugar free ketchup 3 Cubes of brown sugar 1 Can of Campbell&amp;rsquo;s tomato soup Franks RedHot sauce (Optional) Directions Once thawed, put all of your beef into a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Pho Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pho-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pho-soup/</guid><description>Vietnamese Pho Soup is a tea-like, beef based soup with a flavor profile that differentiates it from the traditional Western palette. This recipe is designed to be as easy to make as possible, while simultaneously being as based as possible.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings:4 Ingredients Garlic (4-8 large cloves) Spring Onions Cardamom Seeds (10 or so) Star Anise (4-5) Ginger Cinnamon Sticks (3-5 sticks) Diced Beef (300g) Beef Bones with marrow (3x) Beef bouillon cubes (1-3) Coriander (to taste) 1 Lime (to taste) Fish/Oyster Sauce Honey or Brown Sugar Rice noodles Directions Heat your oven and place the spices (garlic, cardamom seeds, cinnamon sticks, star anise and ginger) on a tray and bake them until browned or decently toasted.</description></item><item><title>Pâté Chinois (Quebec Style Shepherd’s Pie)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</guid><description>This is the most traditional dish that every household eats in Quebec. As a kid, you would eat Pâté Chinois at least once a week, either at home or at the school&amp;rsquo;s cafeteria,. It is very similar to a Shepherd’s Pie, as it is divided in 3 layers of ingredients: meat, legumes and mashed potatoes. The literal translation of the name is something like chinese pie. You can search for the origin of the name on the internet, I&amp;rsquo;m not an history teacher.</description></item><item><title>Francesinha</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</guid><description>Francesinha is a traditional dish from the city of Porto. The francesinha in its special sandwich variation consists of linguiça, ham, cold meat and beef steak, covered with melted cheese.
Ingredients Based Ingredients bread linguiça (type of Portuguese sausage) ham Portuguese cheese beef meat Sauce Ingredients blonde beer fried tomato sauce port wine beef broth salted butter onion minced garlic cornstarch olive oil piripiri (Portuguese chili) Directions Directions for the sauce In a big saucepan, heat the olive oil and add the garlic and the onions.</description></item><item><title>Stoofvlees</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</guid><description>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions. Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 to 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Large onions 1 tablespoon butter 1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces 2 33cl bottles of brown beer 2 bayleaves 2 twigs of thyme 1 clove (spice) 2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon) 2 teaspoons of vinegar 1 slice of bread mustard Directions Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&amp;rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</description></item><item><title>Chimichanga</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</guid><description>Essentially, just a fried burrito. Use whatever your favorite filling is.
⏲️ Prep time: 120min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Servings: 4 Ingredients taco-meat 1 Onion Diced Tomatoes 1 Bell Pepper Burrito sized tortilla Plain Greek Yogurt or Sour Cream Any other vegetables you want Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers, tomatoes, and onions and saute Add in meat. Season and cook until browned or fully cooked through Warm your tortilla and place small layer of yogurt, cheese, and filling on the bottom half of the tortilla Wrap by folding bottom over filling, folding sides in, and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties
Ingredients 1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio Onion, chopped or powder (optional) Garlic, chopped or powder (optional) Directions Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil. Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature. Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings. Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.</description></item><item><title>Schnitzel</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/schnitzel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/schnitzel/</guid><description>Original Austrian breaded meat, pan-fried in butter.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 veal cutlets (1 ~ 150g) 2 eggs 1 lemon 100g flour 150g bread crumbs 100g butter (or even better clarified butter) Directions Prepare 3 bowls. (One with flour, one with beaten eggs, one with bread crumbs seasoned with salt and paprika) Wash the veal and gently dry it with kitchen roll.</description></item><item><title>Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</guid><description>This is a based, easy and relatively quick to make meal. Great for making in large batches with a big pot and eating throughout the week.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6+ Ingredients 1/4 lb. Pork Sausage 1 lb. Med ground beef 1 3/4 Cups Elbow macaroni 1 Can of tomato sauce Diced half onion Diced half bell pepper Oregano leaves Paprika Sage Thyme Marjoram Rosemary leaves 2 Large grated garlic cloves Onion powder Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot sauce (optional) Mozzarella Cheese (optional) Better than Bulion 1 3/4 cups of Macaroni Elbows Directions Season the meat with the paprika, sage, thyme, marjoram, rosmary leaves, oregano leaves, and black pepper Saute the onion and the bell pepper until they become soft.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 6 patties
Ingredients 1 cup soft bread crumb 1/2 cup milk 1 1/2 pound ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1/2 teaspoon salt dash pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 2 tablespoons of fat or salad oil Directions Combine all ingredients except fat: mix well; shape into 6 patties. Heat fat in skillet. Brown patties on all sides; lower heat; cook to desired degree of doneness.</description></item><item><title>Hellfire Steak</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</guid><description>I first learned this recipe from a Bishop I had growing up. It produces quite a good steak despite the unconventional ingredients.
Ingredients Steak Kosher Salt Mustard Powder Tabasco Sauce Directions Rub a generous amount of salt all over the steak Coat the entire steak with mustard powder Pour Tabasco Sauce onto both sides of the steak, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to put more on than you think you might otherwise be comfortable with the salt will cancel out a lot of the spice while grilling.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6 Ingredients For the sauce ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional) For the meatballs 1 lb.</description></item><item><title>Beef Goulash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</guid><description>Although it takes some time to make, it is actually quite easy to make, and it is a really hearty and delicious recipe, if I do say so myself.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 2/3 Ingredients 500g beef 300-400g potatoes 1 carrot 1 medium onion 12 tablespoons tomato paste 500ml water 3-4 garlic cloves 3-4 bay leaves Curcuma Paprika Oregano Parsley Caraway Basil (optional) Cilantro (optional) 2-3 champignon mushrooms (optional) Directions Heat up the frying pan and add some oil.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Meatballs with Tomato Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</guid><description>Nothing beats meat, cheese and tomato combined together to create the best combination of flavors that man has created.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about two adult portions. That is, if you are also making some side dish, like in the photo.
For the meatballs:
300-400g of ground beef meat 1/4 of an onion ~70g of cheese; I have made with different cheese types, but usually I use Gouda Parsley 1-2 garlic cloves 1 egg ~1/5 metric cups (~50ml) of bread crumbs For the sauce:</description></item><item><title>Pasta Navy Style</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</guid><description>This is one of the three pasta dishes that I usually cook. It&amp;rsquo;s a Russian pasta recipe that is fast and easy to make and is quite tasty.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two hearty adult portions:
250g pasta. Usually I prefer to use fusilli or penne, but any short-cut pasta should do. 300-400g ground beef 3-4 tomatoes 1 carrot 1/2 onion 2-3 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika Directions Add olive oil to your frying pan, heat it to medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Taco Meat</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound (about 500 g) ground beef or turkey 1 medium onion, finely chopped (or 1 1/2 teaspoon onion powder) 1 medium tomato, chopped (or 1 small can of tomato sauce) 1 teaspoon chili powder (or 1/3 teaspoon each oregano, cumin, garlic powder) 1 teaspoon oregano (ground or leaf) 1/4 teaspoon cumin dash of pepper (1/8 teaspoon or less) Directions Brown beef and onion together. Drain grease.</description></item><item><title>Beef Jerky</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</guid><description>Beef Jerky is ideal for road trips and camping, as it will not perish as readily as fresh meat. It is suitable not only as a snack but also as a meal. This recipe for jerky is not heavily brined and flavored as commercial jerky is.
Ingredients ¾ tsp. salt ¼ tsp. pepper 1 tbsp. brown sugar ¼ tsp. garlic 2 tbsp. Worcestershire sauce or Teriyaki sauce ¼ tsp. Liquid Smoke 1 Lb.</description></item><item><title>Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</guid><description>Tender chunks of meat in a rich brown gravy poured over sour cream mashed potatoes, made in a pressure cooker. This recipe is a modification of the Texas Cafe Classics Sirloin Tips Recipe by Mark Rippetoe.
Ingredients Any lean, tough cut of meat (ex. round steak) Unprocessed animal fat of some kind (ex. beef suet, mutton fat) Potatoes Sour cream Butter Milk Shredded cheese of your choice Small amount of flour Beef bouillon (optional) Red wine (optional) Directions Beef Tips in Gravy</description></item><item><title>Chili Con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients Canned Whole Peeled Tomatoes Red Peppers White Onions Chili Pepper Garlic Ground Beef Kidney Beans Dark Chocolate Chili Powder Tomato Paste Beef Stock (optional) Neutral Oil Cilantro Sugar seasoning cumin paprika chili flakes Directions Brown the beef by adding it to a pot with neutral oil. Start breaking it into small pieces. Allow water to leave the meat. Salt it to expel more water.</description></item><item><title>Beef Stroganoff</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stroganoff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stroganoff/</guid><description>This is American-style stroganoff.
Ingredients beef chicken stock onions flour butter Worchestershire sauce or something similar dijon or honey dijon mustard egg noodles Directions Dice an onion. Cut beef into bite-size strips. Ground beef can also be used (although not traditional), if beef is compacted into strips of similar size. Season the beef with kosher salt, freshly-ground pepper, or any other desired seasoning. Heat a skillet on high with butter or olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Bitoque - Portuguese Steak with Beer Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</guid><description>Bitoque (pronounced bee-tok) is a traditional quintessential Portuguese dish, its name comes from being cooked in wood burning ovens in the oil mills. Good in combination with red wine, beer sauce that I am going to also provide the ingredients and directions on how to do, rice, french fries and a salad.
Ingredients sirloin steaks garlic olive oil q.b. (quanto basta – ‘enough’) medium fat milk beer mustard flour eggs Directions Season the steaks with sliced garlic and salt.</description></item><item><title>Carbonade Flamande (Traditional Flemish beef stew)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</guid><description>This one is a delicious slow cooked beef stewed in beer. The smoked bacon is not in the traditional recipe but it&amp;rsquo;s good. Don&amp;rsquo;t add it if you want the real deal.
🍳 Cook time: 4-8 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients beef (chuck, brisket, oxtail&amp;hellip;): 1kg | 2 1/4lb gingerbread: 5 slices brown sugar: 1tbsp brown beer (try to get a strong, tasty one): 1L | 4 cups onions: 400g | 1lb diced smoked bacon: 250g | 1/2lb (optional) mustard butter olive oil thyme cloves (not garlic cloves, just cloves): 5 juniper berries: 5 bay leaves: 2 Directions Cut meat into big chunks Dice onions Sear the meat on high heat in a large stainless or cast iron pot until golden brown, using olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Traditional beef or lamb stew</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a typical Irish stew. This is traditionally made with lamb since it&amp;rsquo;s cheaper however, beef tastes a lot better and is more readily available in North America I&amp;rsquo;ve been told. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 2 or 3 days. Besides browning the meat this is really just throwing stuff into a pot in a certain order.</description></item></channel></rss>