<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beef on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/beef/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beef on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/beef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Meatballs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste  Directions  Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Goulash</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</guid>
      <description>Although it takes some time to make, it is actually quite easy to make, and it is a really hearty and delicious recipe, if I do say so myself.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 2/3  Ingredients  500g beef 300-400g potatoes 1 carrot 1 medium onion 12 tablespoons tomato paste 500ml water 3-4 garlic cloves 3-4 bay leaves Curcuma Paprika Oregano Parsley Caraway Basil (optional) Cilantro (optional) 2-3 champignon mushrooms (optional)  Directions  Heat up the frying pan and add some oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Jerky</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</guid>
      <description>Beef Jerky is ideal for road trips and camping, as it will not perish as readily as fresh meat. It is suitable not only as a snack but also as a meal. This recipe for jerky is not heavily brined and flavored as commercial jerky is.
Ingredients  ¾ tsp. salt ¼ tsp. pepper 1 tbl. brown sugar ¼ tsp. garlic 2 tbl. Worcestershire sauce or Teriyaki sauce ¼ tsp. Liquid Smoke 1 Lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Kidney</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</guid>
      <description>My wife&amp;rsquo;s beef kidney recipe
 ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  1 beef kidney 60g butter 2 onions 2 shallots 1 sprig of fresh parsley 3 bay leaves 400g croutons or toasted bread in pieces  Directions  clean the kidney and remove the fat cut the kidney into small chunks (2cm or 3/4&amp;quot;) put butter in a casserole dish add kidney, parsley, bay leaf, salt, pepper brown in the casserole for 10 minutes while stirring (don&amp;rsquo;t burn) add 2 glasses of dry white wine add half a glass of water so that the mixture is well-bathed simmer for 35 minutes add about 400g of toasted bread in pieces simmer for another 10 minutes  Contribution Philip Wittamore - Website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</guid>
      <description>Tender chunks of meat in a rich brown gravy poured over sour cream mashed potatoes, made in a pressure cooker. This recipe is a modification of the Texas Cafe Classics Sirloin Tips Recipe by Mark Rippetoe.
Ingredients  Any lean, tough cut of meat (ex. round steak) Unprocessed animal fat of some kind (ex. beef suet, mutton fat) Potatoes Sour cream Butter Milk Shredded cheese of your choice Small amount of flour Beef bouillon (optional) Red wine (optional)  Directions Beef Tips in Gravy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Meatballs with Tomato Sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Nothing beats meat, cheese and tomato combined together to create the best combination of flavors that man has created.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about two adult portions. That is, if you are also making some side dish, like in the photo.
For the meatballs:
 300-400g of ground beef meat 1/4 of an onion ~70g of cheese; I have made with different cheese types, but usually I use Gouda Parsley 1-2 garlic cloves 1 egg ~1/5 metric cups (~50ml) of bread crumbs  For the sauce:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili Con Carne</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Canned Whole Peeled Tomatoes Red Peppers White Onions Chili Pepper Garlic Ground Beef Kidney Beans Dark Chocolate Chili Powder Tomato Paste Beef Stock (optional) Neutral Oil Cilantro Sugar seasoning  cumin paprika chili flakes    Directions  Brown the beef by adding it to a pot with neutral oil. Start breaking it into small pieces. Allow water to leave the meat. Salt it to expel more water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimichanga</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</guid>
      <description>Essentially, just a fried burrito. Use whatever your favorite filling is.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 120min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Servings: 4  Ingredients  taco-meat 1 Onion Diced Tomatoes 1 Bell Pepper Burrito sized tortilla Plain Greek Yogurt or Sour Cream Any other vegetables you want Shredded cheese of choice (Optional)  Directions  Dice peppers, tomatoes, and onions and saute Add in meat. Season and cook until browned or fully cooked through Warm your tortilla and place small layer of yogurt, cheese, and filling on the bottom half of the tortilla Wrap by folding bottom over filling, folding sides in, and then rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburger Patties</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid>
      <description>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties
Ingredients  1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio Onion, chopped or powder (optional) Garlic, chopped or powder (optional)  Directions  Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil. Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature. Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings. Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.  Contribution  James Hendrie  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamburger Patties</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</guid>
      <description>🍽️ Servings: 6 patties
Ingredients  1 cup soft bread crumb 1/2 cup milk 1 1/2 pound ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1/2 teaspoon salt dash pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 2 tablespoons of fat or salad oil  Directions  Combine all ingredients except fat: mix well; shape into 6 patties. Heat fat in skillet. Brown patties on all sides; lower heat; cook to desired degree of doneness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellfire Steak</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</guid>
      <description>I first learned this recipe from a Bishop I had growing up. It produces quite a good steak despite the unconventional ingredients.
Ingredients  Steak Kosher Salt Mustard Powder Tabasco Sauce  Directions  Rub a generous amount of salt all over the steak Coat the entire steak with mustard powder Pour Tabasco Sauce onto both sides of the steak, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to put more on than you think you might otherwise be comfortable with the salt will cancel out a lot of the spice while grilling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meatloaf</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</guid>
      <description>This recipe will result in two or three glass dishes of tasty, moist meatloaf. Great for family suppers.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 6+  Ingredients  4 1/2 pounds Ground beef 1 Onion 2 Slices of bread 4 Eggs 1/4 Cup of milk Garlic salt Onion powder Mustard Sugar free ketchup 3 Cubes of brown sugar 1 Can of Campbell&amp;rsquo;s tomato soup Franks RedHot sauce (Optional)  Directions  Once thawed, put all of your beef into a bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pâté Chinois (Quebec Style Shepherd’s Pie)</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</guid>
      <description>This is the most traditional dish that every household eats in Quebec. As a kid, you would eat Pâté Chinois at least once a week, either at home or at the school&amp;rsquo;s cafeteria,. It is very similar to a Shepherd’s Pie, as it is divided in 3 layers of ingredients: meat, legumes and mashed potatoes. The literal translation of the name is something like chinese pie. You can search for the origin of the name on the internet, I&amp;rsquo;m not an history teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6  Ingredients For the sauce  ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional)  For the meatballs  1 lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoofvlees</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</guid>
      <description>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions. Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 to 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  2 Large onions 1 tablespoon butter 1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces 2 33cl bottles of brown beer 2 bayleaves 2 twigs of thyme 1 clove (spice) 2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon) 2 teaspoons of vinegar 1 slice of bread mustard  Directions  Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&amp;rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</guid>
      <description>This is a based, easy and relatively quick to make meal. Great for making in large batches with a big pot and eating throughout the week.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6+  Ingredients  1kg Med ground beef 900g Elbow macaroni 4 Cans of tomato soup Diced half or full onion Diced half or full bell pepper Oregano leaves Paprika Basil Sage Savory Thyme Marjoram Rosemary leaves Garlic salt Pink salt Onion power Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot sauce (optional) Mozzarella Cheese (optional)  Directions  Drop ground beef into large pot on low-medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
