<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>easter on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/easter/</link><description>Recent content in easter on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/easter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mazurek</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mazurek/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mazurek/</guid><description>Mazurek is a traditional Polish flat cake made in many homes for Easter. Many different toppings are possible.
Ingredients 2 1/2 cups flour 1/4 cup powdered sugar 200g (7 oz) butter 1 tablespoon 18% sour cream 2 egg yolks topping: for example orange jam from 4 oranges optional additional toppings/decorations: walnuts pecans raisins sliced almonds Directions Put flour and butter in a bowl. Cut the butter with a sharp knife into tiny pieces, mixing with the flour.</description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter). It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min Ingredients Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf. Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.) Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.</description></item><item><title>Greek Easter Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid><description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies Ingredients 1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more) Directions Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description></item></channel></rss>