<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stock on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/stock/</link><description>Recent content in Stock on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/stock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chicken Stock or Bone Broth</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chicken stock, or &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; is not a final dish in itself, but is used in many soups and other dishes to add great taste to something otherwise very simple.
While it is easy to make, it sells for very expensive in the store, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to know to make by yourself since it can be done very cheaply.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a whole raw chicken with organs removed (Drumsticks or thighs alone might suffice if a whole chicken is unavailable.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>celery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>optional aromatic ingredients
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a bay leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>crushed peppercorns&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut onions, celery and carrots into large chunks (you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to remove the onion peels), add to a large empty pot (stock pot).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the chicken to the pot as well. It is fine to butcher the chicken to reduce its size, but include all bones and tendons as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add any aromatic seasonings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill the pot with water up slightly past all the ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring contents to a boil, then reduce heat and let simmer for at least 45 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You may want to remove with a spoon or other instrument the bubbles that form on the top. This will give you a clearer stock, but it is not necessary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strain the liquid, now stock, into another container for storage or use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You may also eat the remaining chicken, possibly for lunchmeat, but since it has imparted its flavor to the stock, it will be slightly more bland so some seasoning might be advised.
You may eat or compost the remaining vegetables.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>