<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>indian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/indian/</link><description>Recent content in indian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Red Lentil Dahl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 medium Yellow Onion 1 Tbsp Fresh Ginger, grated 4 Garlic Cloves, minced 2 Tbsp Yellow Curry (mild madras) 1 tsp Sea Salt 1 cup dried Red Lentils 4 - 5 cups Water 5 Plum Tomatoes, chopped juice of 1 Lemon 1 cup Fresh Cilantro, chopped and lightly packed Dried Red Chili&amp;rsquo;s or cayenne pepper, to taste 1/4 tsp Ground Cinnamon Directions Heat oil in a soup pot and saute onions for 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🍳 Cook time: 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 can (29 ounces) tomato puree 1-1/2 cups plain yogurt 1/2 large onion, finely chopped 2 tablespoons olive oil 4-1/2 teaspoons minced fresh gingerroot 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 tablespoon garam masala 2-1/2 teaspoons salt 1-1/2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 teaspoon paprika 3/4 teaspoon pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2-1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 1-1/2-inch cubes 1 jalapeno pepper, halved and seeded 1 bay leaf 1 tablespoon cornstarch 1 cup heavy whipping cream Hot cooked basmati rice Chopped fresh cilantro, optional Directions In a 5-qt.</description></item><item><title>Curry sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</guid><description>I like to make double this amount and freeze the rest.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 25g butter 1 onion, sliced 2 garlic cloves, sliced Thumb of ginger, sliced 2 tbsp curry powder 1/2 tsp turmeric 1 tbsp malt vinegar 1 star anise 250ml chicken stock 1 tbsp cornflour 2 tbsp water Lemon juice (optional) Directions Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Coriander Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Boneless chicken marinated in a gravy of yoghurt and coriander
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 500g boneless chicken breast 250g fat free yoghurt 250g coriander leaves Mustard oil / Sunflower oil Sugar Ginger Garlic 2 medium onions Green chillies Garam masala 2/3 Cardamom pods 1 Bayleaf 1 Cinnamom stick Directions Cut the boneless chicken into small bite sized pieces.</description></item><item><title>Garam Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</guid><description>A spice mixture for most Indian dishes
Ingredients 4 Green Cardamom 2 Black Cardamom 1 tbsp Coriander 2 Cloves 1 tbsp Cumin 1 tbsp Fennel seeds 5/6 Bayleaf 5/6 Black pepper pods 1 Star anise (Optional) Mace (Optional): Mace is a dried flower originating from the Nutmeg plant. Use no more than 3 strands of this flower. Directions Star anise and Mace are normally not added to Garam masala.</description></item><item><title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients 250g cubes paneer 1 onion 1 capsicum 200ml tomato puree 1 tsp red chilli powder 1 tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp coriander powder 1/2 tsp garam masala powder 100ml thick yogurt 1 tsp fenugreek powder dry fenugreek leaves cardamom cumin seeds shaved ginger 20ml garlic paste 1 bowl corn Directions Take a glass container, and mix the cubed paneers with half a tea spoon of red chilli powder, turmeric powder, coriander powder, garam masala powder, fenugreek powder, and 50g yogurt.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Biriyani</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</guid><description>This recipe makes an Southern Indian (Tamil) style Lamb biriyani that has been adapted to a more western audience (aka a bit less spicy) and can be made with either Lamb or Mutton. Best served with a sauce such as an onion raitha.
A plated rendering of the dish, made with Mutton. Makes a really hearty ,meaty and delicious dish. The dishes uses a rice to meat ratio of 2:3. PS: the biriyani tastes better the longer it&amp;rsquo;s allowed to soak in it&amp;rsquo;s flavour after cooking.</description></item><item><title>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</guid><description>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&amp;rsquo;s quite similar to a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&amp;rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it provides as a sweet and cooling effect.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500 gm of Greek Yogurt One Red onion 50 gm of Cucumber Sprigs of Mint Dash of Honey Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option) Directions Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken Masala Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</guid><description>Butter chicken Masala is one of India&amp;rsquo;s most popular chicken recipes, a mild curry with a tomato-onion-cream base and boneless chicken pieces cooked in it to perfection.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients Boneless Chicken 1/2lb, cubed Butter Melted 2 tbsp Onions 2 medium-sized, minced Tomato 2 medium-sized, pureed Oil 2 tbsp Lemon juice 1 tbsp Garlic cloves 3, minced/crushed Ginger 1tbsp, minced/paste Garam Masala/Chicken Masala 1 tbsp Cream 4tbsp (or cashew paste) Chilli Powder 1 tbsp Turmeric powder 1/4 tbsp Crushed fenugreek leaves 1/4 tbsp 1 small bunch of coriander leaves / cilantro, for ganish Directions In a bowl, mix chicken with salt, pepper, 1/2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1/2 tbsp chili powder, turmeric powder, and lemon juice for the chicken marinade; let marinate for an hour.</description></item><item><title>Naan Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</guid><description>A curry serves best with naan that is unleavened bread. Traditionally made in ‘Tandoor or clay oven' but at home, we will be making it in the oven and/or on the stovetop. Naan is not eaten solely but acts as assortments with meat, veggies, or egg items.
⏲️ Prep time: 90 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients All-purpose flour 3 cups Active dry yeast 1 tbsp Sugar 2 tbsp Warm Milk 1 cup Butter melted 2 tbsp Oil - little to grease Directions Put the yeast and sugar to warm milk in a large mixing bowl and stir well.</description></item><item><title>Potato and Eggplant (Aubergine) Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</guid><description>A simple and tasty curry that is easy to customise.
Ingredients 1 large eggplant (aubergine) 2 medium potatoes 3 tbsp olive oil 2 onions (finely sliced) 2 garlic cloves (crushed) 2 tsp garam masala 2 tsp turmeric 2 tsp ground coriander 400 ml can chopped tomatoes 400 ml can coconut milk rice Optional extras carrots red peppers (capsicums) paneer Directions Heat the oven to approximately 200 °C (392 °F).</description></item></channel></rss>