<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/</link><description>Recent content on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zurich-Style Meat Saute</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zurich-sytle-meat-saute/</guid><description>Originally called &amp;ldquo;Züri Gschnätzlets&amp;rdquo; (Zurich chopped) from the city of Zurich in Switzerland, this is a tasty and practical recipe from simple ingredients. You can use any kind of meat really, depending on your taste. Very traditionally, finely sliced liver and kidney is also mixed in with the meat and mushrooms.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 600g Beef, finely sliced 250g Mushrooms, finely sliced 1 Onion 1 tbsp Flour 200ml White whine 200ml Cream 1 tbsp chopped parsley Directions Fry the meat in butter at high heat until it starts loosing liquid.</description></item><item><title>Kombucha</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kombucha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kombucha/</guid><description>The simple yet comprehensive guide to making tasty kombucha. This is intended to give you an initial overview of the process. I strongly encourage you to experiment with brewing times, teas, flavors, etc. The scoby is extremely tolerant, so the worst that can happen is that your resulting kombucha won&amp;rsquo;t be that great.
Ingredients 5l (1 gallon) jar 3-5 tbsp black (or green) tea 2 cups sugar kombucha scoby optional additional teas optional juices, fruits, spices patience ;) Directions Primary brew:</description></item><item><title>Galinha Caipira</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/galinha-caipira/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/galinha-caipira/</guid><description>Chicken stew ubiquitous in rural Brazil. Perfect pair with rice and beans, polenta or boiled cassava root.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2h 30min 🍽️ Servings: Usually enough for a family of five. Ingredients A whole ckicken weighing close to 2,5kg (roughly 3 pounds). Avoid industrially grown birds, as those can make the stew very greasy and flavorless. A cup of diced onions of any kind.</description></item><item><title>Grilled Mackerel with Miso Soup and Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grilled-mackerel-with-miso-soup-and-squash/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 Norwegian Mackerel Fillets 1 tbsp Sake 2 tbsp Miso paste 1/2 Onion 1 Summer Squash 1 tbsp butter 1 cup Jasmine Rice (optional) Soy Sauce (optional) Directions Place the mackerel fillets in a small container at room temperature. Pour sake on both sides of the fillets and let rest in the container, covered, for 30 min.</description></item><item><title>Keto Coconut Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-flour-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-flour-bread/</guid><description>I created this recipe looking for a bread alternative not using any grains, processed sugar and processed oils. It is sitting between bread and cake feel and my wife loved it. I used pasture-raised eggs to my recipe, just because it is more nutritious. But regular eggs should be fine.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 6 Medium Eggs (or 5 Extra Large) 1 Tbsp Coconut Oil ¾ cup Coconut Flour 1 tsp Baking Powder Pinch of Salt ½ tsp or less of Xanthan Gum (optional, to have a more stick bread) Directions Mix all dry ingredients in a big bowl.</description></item><item><title>Risengrød</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/risengroed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/risengroed/</guid><description>Risengrød is part of the Nordic Christmas tradition as a dinner dish. Rice boiled with milk and a little sugar to form porridge. It is served warm with butter and cinnamon mixed with sugar.
⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time 🍳 Cook time: 40 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients Water 3 dl Pama porridge rice 180 g Whole milk 1 liter Salt 2 pinches Sugar 4 tablespoons Cinnamon 2 teaspoons Butter 50 g Directions Bring water and rice to a boil in a deep pot.</description></item><item><title>Spiced Apple Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spiced-apple-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spiced-apple-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 pancakes Ingredients 1 cup flour 1 large apple, peeled 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp cinnamon (or more to taste) 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp vanilla extract 2/3 cup milk 1 egg Directions In a medium bowl, combine flour, sugar, cinnamon, baking powder, and 1 pinch of salt. Separate the egg yolk and egg white.</description></item><item><title>Strawberry Compote</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/strawberry-compote/</guid><description>Strawberry Compote (клубничный компот) is a chilled sweet drink that is popular in many post-soviet countries. It is similar to strawberry jam or conserves in taste (less sweet/concentrated flavor), but resembles fruit punch in looks and consistency. It is very easy to adjust this recipe and scale it up/down.
FYI, I suggest using organic strawberries for this (may be on the expensive side), it makes a world of difference in flavor.</description></item><item><title>Tajine Maadnous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</guid><description>Similar to an Italian frittata or Spanish tortilla, Tunisian tajine maadnous is an easy &amp;amp; delicious egg omelette filled with chicken, parsley, and spices.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 1 lb chicken breasts diced 1 medium onion chopped 1 large potato peeled and diced 1 cup water 1 small bunch parsley (about 1.5 cups, chopped, loosely packed) 8 large eggs 6 oz cheese 2 tbsp olive oil Spice Blend 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp coriander 1 tsp turmeric 1 tsp salt 1/2 tsp paprika or cayenne pepper if you want some heat 1/2 tsp black pepper 1/4 tsp caraway 1/4 tsp thyme 1/4 tsp cinnamon Directions Mix the spices together (grinding any whole spices if necessary) and set them aside.</description></item><item><title>Granola</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/granola/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/granola/</guid><description>Granola ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 3 cups Oats 1/2 cup Olive Oil 1/2 cup Maple Syrup 1 cup Chopped Nuts (Almonds, Pumpkin Seeds, etc) 1 tsp Ground Cloves 1 tsp Ground Cardamom 1 cup Dried Fruit (Apricots, Unsweetened Cranberries, Dates, etc) Directions Preheat oven to 315° F In a large bowl, mix: Oats, Oil, Maple Syrup, Chopped Nuts and Spices Cover two large baking sheets with parchment paper Spread the mixture thinly and evenly on baking sheets, put in oven Bake 15 minutes, take out of oven, stir, put back in oven (swap oven locations for even cooking) Bake 15 minutes, take out of oven, stir, put back in oven (swap oven locations for even cooking) Bake 10 minutes, take out of oven, do not stir (helps form clumps), let it cool Coarsely chop Dried Fruit and mix in Serve with yogurt, milk, fresh fruit, etc</description></item><item><title>Zaatar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar/</guid><description>This is a traditional Palestinian-Lebanese way of making Zaatar. It can be then eaten by dipping bread in olive oil and in the Zaatar or as part of another recipe. Will hold for a long time in the pantry. This recipe scales for larger amounts so long you preserve the ratios.
Ingredients 1 Cup Zaatar leaves (without the stalks), cleaned and dried. 1 Cup sesame (optionally roasted). 1 Cup Sumac.</description></item><item><title>Grostoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grostoli/</guid><description>Very popular fritter in Italian colonies throughout South Brazil. Not to be mistaken with Venetian Crostoli or Chiacchiere, even though those are still made. My grandmother&amp;rsquo;s recipe is more like Castagnole with Crostoli shape, with some post-Italian adaptations.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: A batch like this will last for two days in a family of four. Ingredients A cup of sugar 800g of flour A tablespoon of baking powder A pinch of salt 4 eggs 3 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>Exotic Ginger Cumin Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/exotic-ginger-cumin-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/exotic-ginger-cumin-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 Tbsp Vegetable Oil, divided 2 lbs Boneless Skinless Chicken, cut bite-size 2 tsp Garlic, minced 1/2 cup Onion, chopped 1 Tbsp Ginger Root, minced 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Cumin 1 tsp Turmeric 1/2 cup Chicken Stock 1 can (19oz) Stewed Tomatoes 2 Tbsp Tomato Paste 1 tsp Sugar 3/4 cup Low Fat Plain Yogurt Directions In large saucepan heat 2 tsp oil over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Hakka-Style Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hakka-style-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1/2 lb Ground Beef 1/4 cup Panko Breadcrumbs 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce, divided 4 tsp Chili Garlic Sauce 1/2 oz Ginger, minced 2 medium Green Bell Peppers 1 small Onion, chopped 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 2 oz Green Peas 1/2 cup Cilantro, loosely packed 1 Tbsp Moroccan Spice Blend, divided 4 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F.</description></item><item><title>One-Pot Chicken Tetrazzini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/one-pot-chicken-tetrazzini/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Butter 8 oz Mushrooms, sliced 1 small Red Pepper, chopped 1 small Onion, finely chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 4 cups Milk 2 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 8 oz Extra Broad Egg Noodles 5 oz Boursin Garlic and Fine Herbs 3 cup Deli Chicken, cooked and cut into bite-size pieces 1/2 cup Frozen Peas 1/2 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped Small Fresh Basil Leaves (optional) Parmesan, grated Directions Melt butter in a large saucepan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Pasta Primavera</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-pasta-primavera/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 12 oz Linguine 1/2 lb Asparagus, cut into 2&amp;quot; pieces 1/4 lb Green Beans, halved 1 cup Sugar Snap Peas, trimmed 1/2 cup Frozen Edamame or Peas 1 Tbsp Butter 1 small Onion, minced 2 cloves Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 2 1/2 cup Milk 1/3 lb Smoked Salmon, cut into wide strips 1/2 cup Fresh Mint, coarsely chopped 1/2 Lemon Directions In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook linguine 10 min or until al dente, adding asparagus, beans, and sugar snap peas during the last 3 minutes of cooking and edamame during the last minute.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Kung Pao-Style Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-kung-pao-style-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 4 Chicken Thighs 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 4 Tbsp All-Purpose Flour 2 small Sweet Peppers, chopped 3 ribs Celery 2 cloves Garlic 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 2 whole Green Onions, thinly sliced 2 Tbsp Chili Garlic Sauce, divided 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Sweet Chili Sauce 1/4 cup Peanuts, chopped Oil Directions Heat a medium pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Three Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bean-salad/</guid><description>Easy recipe to expand - black turtle beans and chickpeas also work well here.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1/3 cup Salad Oil (olive oil, canola, or sunflower) 1/2 cup Cider Vinegar 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Pepper 1/4 cup Sugar 1/2 tsp Celery Seed 1 can Cut Green Beans 1 can Cut Waxed Beans 1 can Red Kidney Beans 1 Carrot, thinly sliced 1 small Onion, chopped 1 Bell Pepper Directions Put dressing ingredients in a large salad bowl an whisk until blended.</description></item><item><title>Za'atar Chicken Bulghur Bowls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zaatar-chicken-bulgur-bowls/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Chicken Breasts 1 cup Bulghur Wheat 1 oz Mixed Olives, drained 4 oz Baby Spinach, chopped 2 Tbsp Za&amp;rsquo;atar Spice Blend 2 Roma Tomatoes 1 Lemon 1/2 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 2 Garlic Cloves, minced/grated 2 Tbsp White Vinegar 1 tsp Sugar Oil Directions Preheat oven to 450F. Add 1 1/2 cup water and 1/4 tsp salt to a medium pot.</description></item><item><title>Beef and Broccoli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-and-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1/2 lb Beef, cut into strips 2 Tbsp Vegetable Oil 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 2 cloves Garlic, minced 1 cup Carrots, sliced Snow Peas Bean Sprouts 1 cup Broccoli Pieces 1/2 cup Beef Bouillon 1 Tbsp Corn starch 1 Tbsp Soy Sauce Directions Heat oil, add beef and stir-fry until meat is browned and push to sides of pan.</description></item><item><title>Egyptian Lentils</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/egyptian-lentils/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 1 cup Lentils 1 cup Elbow Macaroni 2 Fresh Chili or Bell Peppers 2 Tbsp Lime Juice 1 1/2 cup Regular Rice 3 Tbsp Oil 2 medium Tomatoes, chopped 1 large Onion, diced Directions Place lentils in a saucepan and cover by 1&amp;quot; or more of water. Turn heat to high and bring to a boil, then turn down heat to simmer, and cook covered for 35 minutes or until tender.</description></item><item><title>Fajitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajitas/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time:15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/4 cup + 1/2 tsp Lime Juice, divided 3 Tbsp Olive Oil, divided 4 cloves Garlic, crushed 3 tsp Soy Sauce, divided 1 tsp Salt 1/2 tsp Liquid Smoke 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1/4 tsp Black Pepper 1 lb Chicken Breasts or Skirt Steak, bones/skin removed 2 Tbsp Water 1 large Spanish Onion, thinly sliced 1/2 each Green, Red, and Yellow Bell Pepper, thinly sliced Directions Combine 1/4 cup lime juice, 2 Tbsp of the oil, garlic, 2 tsp soy sauce, the salt, liquid smoke, cayenne pepper, and black pepper in a resealable container, add chicken/steak, cover, and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or overnight.</description></item><item><title>Irish Potato Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-potato-casserole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-potato-casserole/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 2 cups Potatoes, peeled and shredded 1/2 cup Butter, melted 2 whole Eggs, beaten 1 tsp Onion, minced 1 tsp Salt 1/4 tsp Paprika 1/2 cup Milk 1/2 cup Sharp Cheddar Cheese, shredded Directions Preheat oven to 350F. Butter a 1.5 quart baking dish. In a medium bowl, combine the potatoes, butter, eggs, onion, salt, and paprika.</description></item><item><title>Mexican Meat Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mexican-meat-loaf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 lb Lean Ground Beef 1 cup Black Beans (canned), rinsed and drained 1 cup Salsa, divided 1/2 cup Corn (frozen) 1/2 cup Bread Crumbs Cooking Spray Directions In bowl, place all ingredients except spray and using 3/4 cup of the salsa - mix well. Spray a loaf pan (approx. 5&amp;quot;x9&amp;quot;), and add above mix.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Salmon Quiche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/smoked-salmon-quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 60 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 3/4 cups Flour 1 cup + 2 1/2 Tbsp Butter, divided Up to 1/3 cup Water, chilled 1/2 cup Onion, finely chopped 14 ounces Smoked Salmon, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Chives, chopped 1 clove Garlic, chopped 2 tsp Fresh Basil, chopped 5 whole Eggs 1 cup Milk 1 cup Whipping Cream Directions Combine all pastry ingredients in a food processor (mix flour and butter, then add water gradually while mixing).</description></item><item><title>Tabouleh</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tabouleh/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 2 cups Cracked Wheat (bulghur) 2 cups Very Hot Water (or as directed) 1 Cucumber, chopped 2 small Tomatoes, chopped 1 bunch Green Onions, sliced 1/2 cup Mint (fresh), chopped 2 cup Parsley (fresh), chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced 1/2 cup Lemon Juice (fresh) 3/4 cup Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Pepper 2 tsp Salt Directions Soak the cracked wheat in the hot water until the water is absorbed, about 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Tofu and Cashew Chow Mein</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-and-cashew-chow-mein/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-and-cashew-chow-mein/</guid><description>Precooked thick wheat noodles are typically found in the refrigerated section of the supermarket. Preparing soba noodles is a worthy substitute.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 10 oz Precooked Thick Wheat Noodles 3 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Oyster Sauce 2 tsp Sesame Oil 2 Tbsp Peanut Oil or other suitable frying oil 6 oz Firm Tofu, cut into cubes 1 Carrot, julienned 2 cups Small Broccoli Florets 2 cloves Garlic, minced 2 tsp Ginger, finely grated 1/2 cup Roasted Cashews Directions Loosen the precooked noodles by soaking in a bowl of hot water for 2-3 minutes, then drain and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Cuca "Italiana"</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cuca-italiana/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cuca-italiana/</guid><description>Sweet bread with a crumbly top. The name derives from German &amp;ldquo;Streußelkuchen&amp;rdquo;, but while German colonists in Southern Brazil kept it identical to the mainland version, North Italian colonists took it and turned it into a tall loaf.
⏲️ Prep time: 2h 30min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients For the dough:
3 cups of all-purpose flour 1 1/2 cups of sugar 3/4 of a cup of warm water 2 eggs 6 tablespoons of milk 2 tablespoons of lard or butter 1 tablespoon of instant dry yeast A pinch of nutmeg 1 teaspoon of vanilla essence (optional).</description></item><item><title>Teriyaki Beef Wok</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/teriyaki-beef/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/teriyaki-beef/</guid><description>If you have no wok, a regular pan will suffice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 dL water 2 tbsp cornstarch 1 tbsp honey 1/4 tsp ginger 3 tbsp soy sauce Sesame oil Beef slices or strips Carrot, sliced (optional) Broccoli, florets (optional) Baby corn (optional) Water chestnut, sliced (optional) Bean sprouts (optional) Chili pepper, diced (optional) Noodles or rice Directions Whisk water, cornstarch, honey, ginger and soy sauce.</description></item><item><title>Cheddar-Crusted Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheddar-crusted-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheddar-crusted-chicken/</guid><description>Suggested sides: Roasted green beans as well as sweet potatoes mashed with sour cream and butter
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 2 Chicken Breasts 2 Tbsp Mayonnaise 1/4 cup Panko Breadcrumbs 1/4 cup Cheddar Cheese, shredded 1 Tbsp Smoked Paprika-Garlic Blend Directions Combine panko, cheese, and smoked paprika-garlic blend in a shallow dish. Preheat oven to 425F.</description></item><item><title>Colcannon Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/colcannon-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 70 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Potatoes, peeled and quartered 7 Tbsp Butter, cut into small chunks 1/2 cup Sour Cream 1 Egg 1 Tbsp Milk 3 cup Cabbage, shredded 2 Leeks, chopped 1 small Onion, chopped 2 cubes Chicken Bouillon 1/2 cup Cheddar Cheese, shredded Directions Place the potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water.</description></item><item><title>Easy Chicken and Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-chicken-and-rice-casserole/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 cup Onion, chopped 1/2 cup Celery, chopped 2 Tbsp Butter or margarine 2 cups Chicken, cooked and chopped 1 3/4 cups Hot water 2/3 cup Long Grain White Rice 1 can (10 oz) Mushrooms with liquid 1 cup Frozen Peas and Carrots 1 tsp Dried Thyme and Rosemary Directions In large fry pan, cook onion and celery in butter until soft.</description></item><item><title>Fall Vegetable and Chickpea Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fall-vegetable-and-chickpea-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fall-vegetable-and-chickpea-curry/</guid><description>Can be served over rice or on its own with a dollop of yogurt.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 Tbsp Butter 1 Onion, chopped 2 Tbsp Thai Red Curry Paste 1 Tbsp Ginger, minced 1 large Sweet Potato, peeled and cut into half-inch chunks 1 small Zucchini, cut into half-inch chunks 1 Red Pepper, cut into half-inch pieces 28 oz can Chickpeas, rinsed and drained 1 Lime 3 Tbsp Wheat Flour 1 1/2 cup Milk 1/2 cup Fresh Coriander, chopped Directions In a large non-stick frying pan, heat butter over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Ham and Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ham-and-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ham-and-lentil-soup/</guid><description>For more flavour, boil down a soup bone and use the broth when filling the crock pot.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 2 cup Lentils 1/2 lb Ham, diced 1 Onion, chopped 1 Bay leaf 2 ribs Celery, chopped 1 clove Garlic, minced Directions Combine all ingredients with 2 quarts water in the Crock Pot. Cook on low, covered, 8 to 10 hours.</description></item><item><title>Newfoundland Cod Chowder</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 4 Slices Bacon 2 Onions, sliced 1 tsp Savoury 6 Potatoes, peeled and cubed 3 Carrots, sliced 1 1/2 lbs Cod Fillets 1 can Evaporated Milk 2 Tbsp Fresh Parsley or Chives, chopped Directions In a large, heavy saucepan, cook bacon over medium-high heat for about 10 minutes or until crisp. Chop coarsely and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Panang-Style Beef Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/panang-style-beef-curry/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 315 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 lb Ground Beef 1 can (400mL) Coconut Milk 1 Red Chili Pepper 1/2 cup Red Curry Paste 4 tsp Peanut Butter 3/4 cup Jasmine Rice 2 Tbsp Cilantro 1 Sweet Bell Pepper 1/2 Onion (2 oz), chopped 1 Tbsp Garlic Puree 1 oz Peanuts, chopped 1/2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Mild Curry Paste Directions Start rice.</description></item><item><title>Perfect Potato Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/perfect-potato-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 5 Potatoes, peeled and cut into bite-size chunks (about 2 lbs) 1 cup Plain Yogurt 1/2 cup Mayonnaise 1 Tbsp Prepared Horseradish 4 Radishes, thinly sliced 2 stalks Celery, diced 2 large Green Onions, thinly sliced 1/4 cup Fresh Parsley, chopped 1/4 cup Fresh Dill, chopped Directions Place potatoes in a pot and just cover with water.</description></item><item><title>Turkish Red Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-red-lentil-soup/</guid><description>Serve with a squeeze of lemon and alongside turmeric flatbread.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 cup Red Lentils 5 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Paprika 1/2 Tbsp Red Paper Flakes 1 large Onion, finely diced 1 large Carrot, diced 4 tsp Tomato Paste 2 tsp Cumin 1/2 tsp Dried Mint 1/2 tsp Thyme or Oregano 4 cup Vegetable Broth 4 cup Water Directions Reserve half the paprika and red pepper flakes, set aside.</description></item><item><title>Turkish-Style Spiced Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-style-spiced-chicken/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Chicken Breasts 1 Tbsp Turkish Spice Blend 1 oz Almonds, sliced 3/4 cup Basmati Rice 12 oz Sweet Potato 2 oz Onion, chopped 100 mL Greek Yogurt 2 Tbsp Parsley 1 Lemon 1/2 tsp Garlic Salt 1 1/2 cup Chicken Broth 1 tsp Sugar Directions Cut sweet potatoes into 1/2 inch pieces.</description></item><item><title>Turmeric Flatbread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turmeric-flatbread/</guid><description>A great companion to Turkish Red Lentil Soup.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 cup Wheat Flour (white or whole) 1/2 Tbsp Ground Turmeric 1/2 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Baking Powder 2 Tbsp Olive Oil Directions Combine flour, turmeric, salt and baking powder. Stir in 1/3 cup water and the olive oil. Knead until smooth (1-2 min).</description></item><item><title>Winter Risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/winter-risotto/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3/4 cup Arborio Rice 1 cup Baby Spinach 2 Garlic Cloves 4 1/2 cup Vegetable Broth 1/4 cup Parmesan Cheese, shredded 1/2 lb Baby Tomatoes 1 Tbsp White Wine Vinegar 1/4 cup Walnuts, chopped 1/2 cup Leek, sliced 1 cup Mushrooms 3 Tbsp Unsalted Butter Directions Combine vegetable broth in a medium pot.</description></item><item><title>Autumn Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/autumn-soup/</guid><description>You can cook the veggies on the stove instead of baking them, just pay more attention to avoid burning. You can also use pumpkin instead of squash.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 Medium Squash 3 Potatoes 4 Carrots 1 Small Onion 1 Chicken Bullion Cube 1 cup Water 2 cups Milk Salt Pepper Directions Peel and chop squash, potatoes, carrots, and onion, add to oven-safe pot.</description></item><item><title>Greek Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2 cup assorted Lettuce, chopped or torn 4 whole Tomatoes, wedged or sliced 1 whole Cucumber, seeded and sliced 1 Bell Pepper, seeded and sliced 1 small Onion, sliced 1/2 cup pitted Black Olives (preferably brine-cured), coarsely chopped 3/5 cup Feta Cheese, crumbled 6 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 tsp Red Wine Vinegar 1/2 tsp Fresh Garlic, chopped 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp dill weed 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped Salt and freshly ground Black Pepper 2 Tbsp Lemon juice, fresh Directions Combine the lettuce, tomatoes, cucumber, onion, bell pepper, olives in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Gypsy Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gypsy-soup/</guid><description>The vegetables used in this soup are flexible. Any orange vegetable can be combined with green. Such as peas or green beans to replace peppers, or carrots and/or squash to replace the sweet potato.
⏲️ Prep time: 40 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 2 cup Chopped Onion 2 cloves Chopped Garlic 2 cup Sweet Potatoes, chopped and peeled 1/2 cup Chopped Celery 1 cup Chopped Fresh Tomatoes 3/4 cup Chopped Sweet Peppers 1-1/2 cup Cooked Chickpeas 3 cup Stock or Water 2 tsp Paprika 1 tsp Turmeric 1 tsp Basil 1 tsp Salt dash Cinnamon dash Cayenne 1 Bay Leaf 1 Tbsp Tamari Soy Sauce Directions In a soup kettle or large saucepan, saute onions garlic, celery, and sweet potatoes in olive oil for about five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ratatouille/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 12 min 🍳 Cook time: 75 min 🍽️ Servings: 12 Ingredients 3 1/2 lbs Tomatoes 1 1/2 lbs Eggplant 1 lb Zucchini 3 Bell Peppers 2 lbs Onions 6 cloves Garlic Herbes de Provence (Basil, Thyme, Parsley) Olive Oil Salt Pepper 140g Tomato Paste (optional if tomatoes aren&amp;rsquo;t yummy) Directions Peel and drain the tomatoes (don&amp;rsquo;t mind the seeds): cut out the stem cores; drop the whole tomatoes into boiling water for 2 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Red Lentil Dahl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-lentil-dahl/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 medium Yellow Onion 1 Tbsp Fresh Ginger, grated 4 Garlic Cloves, minced 2 Tbsp Yellow Curry (mild madras) 1 tsp Sea Salt 1 cup dried Red Lentils 4 - 5 cups Water 5 Plum Tomatoes, chopped juice of 1 Lemon 1 cup Fresh Cilantro, chopped and lightly packed Dried Red Chili&amp;rsquo;s or cayenne pepper, to taste 1/4 tsp Ground Cinnamon Directions Heat oil in a soup pot and saute onions for 5 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp and Chicken Jambalaya</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-chicken-jambalaya/</guid><description>Warm up your stock with raw shrimp shells to infuse additional flavour, if desired. Serve dish with french bread and your favourite beer.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min Ingredients 1/4 tsp Cayenne 3/4 tsp White Pepper 1 tsp Kosher Salt 1/4 tsp Thyme 1/2 tsp Rubbed Sage 1/4 tsp Dried Basil 1/2 tsp Black Pepper 1 Tbsp Unsalted Butter 1/2 cup Diced Andouille (or Chirozo sausage) 1/2 cup Diced Onion 1/2 cup Diced Bell Pepper 1/2 cup Diced Celery 1/2 cup Diced Fresh Tomatoes 1/2 cup Tomato Sauce 3/4 cup Enriched Long Grain Rice 1-1/4 cup Chicken Stock 1 Tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 2 Tbsp Minced Fresh Garlic 1/2 cup Diced Chicken (cooked or raw) 1-1/2 cup Medium Shrimp 1 Tbsp Finely Chopped Italian Parsley 3 Tbsp Finely Sliced Green Onions Directions Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.</description></item><item><title>Spinach-Rice Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spinach-rice-casserole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spinach-rice-casserole/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 4 cups Brown Rice, cooked 2 lbs raw Spinach, chopped 1 cup Onion, chopped 2 cloves Garlic, minced 3 Tbsp Butter 4 Eggs, beaten 1 cup Milk 1 1/2 cups Cheddar, grated 1/4 cup Parsley, chopped 2 Tbsp Tamari 1/2 tsp Salt (or more, to taste) 1/4 cup Sunflower Seeds A few dashes each - Nutmeg; Cayenne; Paprika Directions Saute onions and garlic with salt in butter.</description></item><item><title>Chipolata Sausage in Balsamic Vinegar</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chipolata-in-balsamic-vinegar/</guid><description>Easy to prepare Italian dish with lots of flavour great for a relaxing evening dipping bread and sipping wine.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 12 chipolata sausages 4 red onions 500g of cherry tomatoes (preferably mixed species) 4 garlic cloves Fresh basil leaves Black balsamic vinegar 1 loaf of ciabatta bread Directions Pre-heat the oven to 200c (400f) Put the chipolata sausages in an oven dish Cut 4 red onions into quarters spread them out in the oven dish.</description></item><item><title>Tunisian Couscous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/couscous/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/couscous/</guid><description>Credits to creator of recipe, Mike Benayoun , (original recipe). I decided to post it on here to be more available.
Couscous is a staple in most Maghreb cuisines. It is known as the national dish in Tunisia, but also in Algeria and Morocco, as well as Mauritania and Libya. Tunisian couscous is one of the countless variations of this delicious and versatile dish.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 2 lb lamb stew meat , cut into large pieces 6 cups couscous fine semolina (or medium) 2 onions , finely chopped 2 cloves garlic , pressed 4 tablespoons tomato paste 2 tablespoons harissa 2 tablespoons ground caraway 1 tablespoon ground coriander 1 teaspoon chili powder 4 turnips , cut in half 6 medium carrots , peeled 4 zucchini , peeled lengthwise, alternately leaving a layer of skin 6 small potatoes , peeled 10 oz.</description></item><item><title>Russian Okroshka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okroshka/</guid><description>A hearty and healthy cold soup, which is especially good to eat in the hot season. Author&amp;rsquo;s recipe.
Ingredients 2-3 medium potatoes 4 eggs 2 long or 4 short cucumbers 3 strands of spring onions 10-12 radishes bunch of dill 2 Kefir or 1 kvass 500g boiled sausage or boiled chicken meat 1 mineral water (optional) Directions Prepare a saucepan where you will put the ingredients (5 liters) and a saucepan for boiling eggs and potatoes Boil potatoes and eggs (hard boiled) Finely chop cucumbers, radishes, onions, dill and sausage (or meat) Peel eggs and potatoes and chop finely Pour kefir (or kvass) and mix all the ingredients If necessary, add boiled water or mineral water.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter sauce.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min Ingredients spaghetti or fettucine butter heavy cream garlic oregano white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended) lemon/lemon juice (optional) red pepper flakes (optional) seafood, choose from: mussels squid shrimp clams lobster Directions Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow these instructions.</description></item><item><title>Scouse</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/scouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scouse/</guid><description>A hearty and cheap stew, that&amp;rsquo;s easy to make and is my go to dish to make and freeze on weeknights. This dish is really flexible and goes with virtually any vegetables you&amp;rsquo;ve got in your cupboard. Originated around Stoke and Liverpool as Lobscouse and later split into the dishes Lobby and Scouse.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients beef mince a white onion garlic bayleaf potatoes carrots beef stock ~1 pint beef gravy granules parsnips(optional) swede(optional) cabbage(optional) Directions Finely dice the onions and garlic.</description></item><item><title>Korv Stroganoff</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/korv-stroganoff/</guid><description>This easy Swedish dish makes for a great weeknight dinner.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1/2 kg Swedish falukorv 1 yellow onion 1 tbsp olive oil 4 tbsp tomato purée 2 1/2 dl cream 1 dl milk 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp Dijon mustard Directions Cut the sausage into sticks and dice the onion. Fry the sausage and onion in oil for about ten minutes.</description></item><item><title>Easy Pizza Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/easy-pizza-sauce/</guid><description>One serving should be enough to cover a pizza. The sauce can be stored in the refrigerator for ~16 days if put into a conserving jar.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 2 onions 3 garlic cloves olive oil 700g tomato sauce 6 spoon tomato concentrate 0.5 spoon sugar 1 spoon salt 1 spoon pepper 1 spoon thyme/rosemary (finely chopped) 1 spoon oregano (finely chopped) 2 spoon basil (finely chopped) Directions Finely chop onions and garlic into a pot.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-pizza/</guid><description>This is a recipe combining two others and adding stuff on top. This is more of an example of possible ingredients, you can replace any of them with others.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 serving Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough 1 serving Easy Pizza Sauce ~80g mozzarella cheese ~40g Edam cheese ~40g Tilsitter cheese salami (optional) ham (optional) salsiccia (optional) aubergine (optional) zucchini (optional) mushrooms (optional) olives (optional) arugula salad (add after pizza is done) (optional) fresh basil leaves (add after pizza is done) (optional) Directions Cover a baking tray fully with a thin layer of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Dulce de Leche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dulce-de-leche/</guid><description>Delicious milk toffee used on desserts or as a spread. Substitute for Nootella or similar &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;. It is very demanding, so i only recommend you make it if you either can&amp;rsquo;t buy industrial dulce de leche (It will be way more natural than other sweets anyway), or have the time and interest to go through the process. It can be made more easily with sweetened condensed milk, but if you have access to it, you can get DDL anyways.</description></item><item><title>Pulpo a la gallega</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pulpo-gallega/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 to 40 min 🍽️ Servings: Ingredients 1 octopus (1.7 to 2kg) Potatoes 2 bay leaves Sweet and spicy red pepper Salt oil Directions Boil water along with salt and the bay leaves Once the water is boiling, introduce the octopus 3 times by putting it on and taking it out, then let it cook for 35 to 40 minutes by puncturing it to see whether it is already soft or we need to leave it a little longer turn off the fire and let it rest for 20 minutes more with the same water.</description></item><item><title>Wholemeal Wheat Flour Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/wholemeal-wheat-flour-pizza-dough/</guid><description>One serving(~200g dough) should be enough to make a pizza. The dough can be stored in the refrigerator for ~2 days. For it to last longer, it should be stored in the freezer.
⏲️ Prep time: 70 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g flour (Wholemeal Wheat Flour) 280ml lukewarm water 8g dry yeast 3.5 spoon olive oil 1.5 teaspoon salt Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough.</description></item><item><title>Banana and oatmeal cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-oatmeal-cookies/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Serving : 3 Ingredients 2 ripe bananas (250 g/9 oz peeled) 100g (3.5 oz) of oatmeal 1 table spoon of cinnamon powder (optional) 1 table spoon of honey (optional) Directions Pre-heat the oven to 180°C (350°F) Peel the bananas and squash them not too finely in a bowl. Incorporate the oatmeal. Incorporate cinnamon powder and/or honey (optional).</description></item><item><title>Apple Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</guid><description>Baked chicken with apples and onions. Suprinsingly good and simple combination.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Chicken breast or similar. Onions. Nuez moscada. Apples. Potatoes. Cream or creme fraiche. Salt. Pepper. One glass (33c) of wine or cognac. Directions Heat the oven to 200C and prepare an oven tray. Mix the chicken with nuez moscada, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Ardei umpluti with meat</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ardei-umpluti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ardei-umpluti/</guid><description>Farcies tomates with rice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 yellow peppers per person Around 120g of ground beef meat per person. 1 or 2 onions. Condiments of your choice: Parsley, origan or cumin. Olive oil Salt and pepper. Optional: Bechamel. Directions Heat the oven to 200C. Empty the peppers and remove the seeds. Slice the top to the peppers and place them in the oven tray, you may need to slice the bottom a litte bit to make them stand together.</description></item><item><title>Farcies tomatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/farci-tomatoes/</guid><description>Farcies tomates with rice.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 tomatoes per person. 300g of ground beef meat. 1 or 2 onions. Condiments of your choice: Parsley, origan or cumin. Olive oil Gruyere cheese. Salt and pepper. Optional: Butter. Directions Heat the oven to 200C. Slice the top to the tomatoes and place them in the oven tray.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Satay with Peanut Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-satay/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 lbs boneless chicken breast or thigh 1.5 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tbsp ground tumeric 2 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp coconut milk 3 tbsp peanut butter (creamy) 1 tbsp massaman curry paste water to thin peanut sauce Directions Cut the chicken into 1/2 inch thick strips. Mix chicken with oyster sauce, tumeric, 1 tbsp sugar and coconut milk.</description></item><item><title>Tarta de Santiago</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tarta-de-santiago/</guid><description>Delicious Spanish almond cake or famously known as tarta de Santiago. This is a cake from Galicia and it is super easy to make, with only 3 main ingredients. I always feel this type of cake is just perfect for the holiday season.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 3 eggs ¾ cup sugar (150 gr) 1 ½ cup almond meal (150 gr) ½ teaspoon cinnamon powder ¼ teaspoon salt Zest of 1 lemon Zest of 1 clementine Icing sugar, for dusting on top Directions Add eggs and sugar into a bowl and whisk until the mixture turns pale.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Corn</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettlecorn/</guid><description>Recipe can be expanded or contracted to your needs. I personally divide the recipe in half to fit my 2 quart saucepan (recipe calls for a 3 quart). I recommend using Orville Redenbacher&amp;rsquo;s popcorn kernels, as they are specifically formulated to pop consistently. Follow these directions precisely, and I will guarantee you will have no burnt or unpopped kernels.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Serving 14 Ingredients 2 tablespoons vegetable oil, or oil of your choice 1/4 cup of popcorn kernels 2 tablespoons of sugar (brown sugar works too) salt to taste Directions Add oil into your saucepan and 3 popcorn kernels.</description></item><item><title>Fennel White Bean and Kale Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fennel-beans-and-kale-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup with lots of veggie and protein.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 bowls Ingredients ½ cup olive oil 2 small fennel bulbs, small-diced 2 small yellow onions, small-diced 4 teaspoons minced fresh rosemary or thyme 10 cloves of garlic, minced or pressed ½-1 teaspoon red-pepper flakes. 10-12 oz kale, (escarole, swiss chard, or spinach can also be used). 4 cans cannellini beans, rinsed 4 cups chicken broth.</description></item><item><title>Butter-based biscuit and cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-based-biscuit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-based-biscuit/</guid><description>This recipe is some basic recommandations for making butter based biscuits (aka shortbread, sablés, cookies &amp;hellip;). The complexity comes from the presence of butter mostly.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min ⏲️ Wait time: 1h 🍳 Cook time: 15 min Ingredients Butter Flour White sugar Eggs (optionnal) Directions Prepare the dough Mix the sugar and eggs until it gets white Add the &amp;ldquo;Pommade&amp;rdquo; butter and mix thoroughly until the preparation is airy.</description></item><item><title>Kettle Chips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kettle-chips/</guid><description>Credits to creator of recipe, Ethan Chlebowski, (original recipe). I decided to post it on here to be more available.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min 🍳 Cook time: 11 min 🍽️ Servings: 1~2, about 1 plate full Ingredients 1 Russet Potato, or other potato with high starch and low moisture. The amount of starch effects the crunchiness of the chip. Peanut Oil for frying (at least 1 to 2 inches in the pan) Salt or seasoning of your choice Directions Set a wok or pot over medium-low heat and add the peanut oil about 1 to 2 inches up the pot.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp Fettuccine Alfredo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-fettuccine-alfredo/</guid><description>Shrimp fettuccine alfredo is one of the best tasting and low effort dishes. The recipe i give below yields an alfredo sauce that is a bit on the thicker side. If you want a thinner sauce, adding a touch or two more milk will thin out the sauce. This is a great meal for 3-4 people or you can eat one serving and freeze the rest for 2-3 more dinners.</description></item><item><title>Tahini short bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tahini-short-bread/</guid><description>This short bread recipe uses sesame paste called Tahini, a minimal amount of white sugar is necessary in order to get a crunchy/caramelized short-bread. For better results, a food processor is welcome for this recipe. IMPORTANT Butter is what makes this recipe complicated when cooking the dough, make sure it is not liquid or that the room is not to warm and make sure that the shortbreads are cold before putting in the oven.</description></item><item><title>Grands-pères au sirop d'érable (Maple Dumplings)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/grands-peres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/grands-peres/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings:5-6 Ingredients 1 cup flour 2 TSP baking powder 1 pinch salt 2 TB butter, cut into pieces ½ cup milk 1 cup water 1 cup maple syrup Directions Stir together flour, baking powder and salt until aerated and no longer clumpy. Work in the butter with your fingertips and add milk. Form into 5-6 balls.</description></item><item><title>Croque-monsieur bites</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croque-monsieur/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients For the bechamel 50g Butter 50g Flour 1 Liter of milk Salt Ground Pepper Nutmeg For the bites 12 Slices of bread 2 Tbsp of Mustard 12 very thin slices of ham with Italian herbs 80g grated cheese (Emmental, Comté Gruyère Mimolette Directions Prepare the béchamel: melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan.</description></item><item><title>Puff Pastry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/puff-pastry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/puff-pastry/</guid><description>A basic puff pastry recipe that can replace any recipe that calls for puff pastry.
⏲️ Prep time: ~1.5 hrs 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 24 Ingredients 5 cups bread flour 2 1/2 teaspoons salt 2 cups water 2 cups unsalted butter, softened Directions Before starting on the dough, place the butter between two pieces of plastic wrap. Pound into a flat disc using a rolling pin or other heavy object.</description></item><item><title>Torta Frita Criolla (Argentinian frybread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torta-frita-criolla/</guid><description>A &amp;ldquo;merienda&amp;rdquo; (afternoon meal) that is intertwined with the history of colonization on the River Plate region. Never have it by yourself, instead with friends or family, and a cup/gourd of Mate.
⏲️ Prep time: 1h 10min or 2h 10min, (depending on how long you leave it to rest.) 🍳Cook time: 10 minutes. 🍽️ Servings : 10. Ingredients 1.1 pound (1/2 kilo) of all-purpose flour. 4 tablespoons of lard or butter.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Arrabbiata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-arrabbiata/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Pasta Olive oil Chilli flakes or diced chilli peppers Crushed garlic cloves Crushed tomatoes (about 800 gramms for 500 gramms of pasta) Chopped parsley Grated Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano Reggiano (optional, but highly recommended) Directions Start heating up water for the pasta. Heat up a few tablespoons of olive oil over low heat. Crush several cloves of garlic into the olive oil, add the chilli flakes or chilli peppers and fry them for a short time, while being careful not to burn the garlic.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Paprikash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-paprikash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-paprikash/</guid><description>Chicken Paprikash is a delicious meal from Hungary, and I hope you are also Hungary! I make it all the time when I have guests.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 8 bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs salt to taste pepper to taste 2 cups chicken or beef broth 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 medium sized onions 1 tablespoon powdered garlic 3 tablespoons tomato paste 1/4 cup Hungarian paprika or regular paprika 1 tablespoon cayenne pepper (optional) 1 cup sour cream (optional) Directions Pat raw chicken thighs with paper towels for crispier skin.</description></item><item><title>Pastítsio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pastitsio/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 Ingredients Pasta layer 600g penne rigate salted water Meat layer 1 large onion, finely diced 700g lean ground beef .5 TB ground allspice .5 TB ground cinnamon .25 TSP ground clove (optional) 340g tomato paste Béchamel layer 226g butter 226g flour 1L cold milk 237ml chicken stock freshly grated nutmeg (optional) grated cheese (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 190°C In a large pot of salted water, cook the pasta per package directions.</description></item><item><title>Ray Peat's Carrot Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peat-carrot-salad/</guid><description>A raw carrot salad to support digestive, hormone and thyroid health
&amp;ldquo;Endotoxin formed in the bowel can block respiration and cause hormone imbalances contributing to instability of the nerves, so it is helpful to optimize bowel flora, for example with a carrot salad; a dressing of vinegar, coconut oil and olive oil, carried into the intestine by the carrot fiber, suppresses bacterial growth while stimulating healing of the wall of the intestine.</description></item><item><title>Red Bean Buns (豆沙包)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dou-sha-bao/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dou-sha-bao/</guid><description>Soft and fluffy sweet buns filled-up with creamy Azuki red bean paste.
⏲️ Prep time: 2h 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 350g (~12 oz) wheat flour 1 sachet (~ 4g / 0.14 oz) baker&amp;rsquo;s yeast 1 teaspoon baking powder 200g (7 oz) sugar 20cl (~ 0,05 gal) water 1 teaspoon sunflower oil 250g (~ 9 oz)red beans Azuki (soak 24h before recipe) salt 6 baking paper square 7x7cm (~ 3x3inches) Directions 24h after soaking, boil the beans during 5 minutes and rince to clean up impurities.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Sausage Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-sausage-pasta/</guid><description>A delicious spicy pasta dish, super easy to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a student and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap for how much food you get. I found it in a newspaper a while back and thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it with you guys because it&amp;rsquo;s my favourite meal. I also like to drink the excess red wine while cooking which adds to the enjoyment of cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 red onions, chopped Olive oil 6 spicy Italian sausages 1 sprig rosemary, needles finely chopped 1 red chilli, deseeded and diced A large glass of red wine (approx.</description></item><item><title>Steak Tartare</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/steak-tartare/</guid><description>Steak Tartare is a dish prepared using raw ground / minced beef and egg yolk. A popular dish in Europe, this recipe is a good stepping stone into the world of raw meats, organs and pates.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Ground Beef (Lean as possible) Eggs Onion or Shallots Capers Gherkin / Cornichons Parsley (Optional) Ketchup (Optional) Mustard (Optional) Worcestershire Sauce (Optional) Directions Dice your onions or shallots.</description></item><item><title>Potato Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-soup/</guid><description>Serves many people or one person for many days.
Ingredients Potatoes (yellow or brown), I don&amp;rsquo;t count but 10+ Butter, a stick or two Whole Milk Garlic Cheese (optional) Onion Greens (optional) Sour Cream (optional) Directions Bake the potatoes at 450° for about an hour. Take them out and leave them to cool for a good 10 minutes. Begin heating up a big pot to about medium temperature, and put the butter in to melt.</description></item><item><title>Lavacake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lavacake/</guid><description>Easily made chocolate dessert with fluid chocolate content. The only requirement is a baking tin with cupcake pits.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 7 min 🍽️ Servings 4 Ingredients 1 Egg 25g Flour 25g Butter 75g Chocolate Directions Cover the baking tin with some butter. Heat the oven for 200°C. Mix all of the ingredients. Fill dough in the baking tins pits. Bake for 7 min.</description></item><item><title>Quiche Lorraine - Lothringer Käsetorte</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quiche/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 160 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 200g Flour (full sight) 100g Butter or Margarine 5 Tablespoons of Water 200g of Ham (alternatively cooked ham) 4 Eggs 1/4 Cream 125g grinded Edamer Cheese For the Baking Tin: More Butter and Flour Directions Spread some butter on a 26cm Ø or two smaller baking tins and cover it with flour Sieve the flour, mingle the butter/margarine in small flakes.</description></item><item><title>Ceviche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</guid><description>Ceviche is a South American dish which originated in Peru. The following recipe will only cover the bare minimum ingredients, so feel free to experiment by adding things like garlic, ginger, peppers tomatoes, cilantro, other citrus juices, and anything else you feel might taste good in there.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min Ingredients Seafood Red Onion Lime Juice Directions Slice your onion as thinly as you can then let them all sit in a bowl of cold water for a while.</description></item><item><title>Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheese/</guid><description>The success of this recipe depends entirely on the quality of the milk. The fresher the milk the better. Your regular UHT milk won&amp;rsquo;t work, because the necessary bacteria have been killed.
You do not necessary need cow milk, basically every animal milk will work, but the cheese will have vastly different (not necessarily worse) characteristics.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of milk 25g of table salt (optional with aging) 2g of rennet Some coarse salt Oil and vinegar (for aging) Directions Preparation Pour the milk and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 35°C.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tikka-masala/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🍳 Cook time: 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 can (29 ounces) tomato puree 1-1/2 cups plain yogurt 1/2 large onion, finely chopped 2 tablespoons olive oil 4-1/2 teaspoons minced fresh gingerroot 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 tablespoon garam masala 2-1/2 teaspoons salt 1-1/2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 teaspoon paprika 3/4 teaspoon pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 1/4 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2-1/2 pounds boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into 1-1/2-inch cubes 1 jalapeno pepper, halved and seeded 1 bay leaf 1 tablespoon cornstarch 1 cup heavy whipping cream Hot cooked basmati rice Chopped fresh cilantro, optional Directions In a 5-qt.</description></item><item><title>Cream Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cream-cheese/</guid><description>Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 250ml of fresh, non-UHT milk 250ml of yogurt 1lt of fresh cream 5g of table salt 6g of of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Mix the yogurt, the milk, the cream, the salt, and the sugar into a bowl. Heat the bowl to 80°C while stirring. Once the temperature has been reached, add the citric acid and mix well.</description></item><item><title>Frijol con puerco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frijol-con-puerco/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 ~ 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 kg of black beans, rinsed and drained. 2 kg of pork loin or ribs cut into 5 cm pieces, it can be mixture of the two. 1 white onion without skin cut, in half. 4 branches of fresh epazote, or 15 branches of coriander tied with kitchen twine. 8 to 10 radishes, julienned or striped.</description></item><item><title>Greek Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h pour the newly obtained yogurt into the cheesecloth.</description></item><item><title>Honey Sriracha Chicken Thighs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-sriracha-chicken-thighs/</guid><description>This recipe yields a batch of relatively spicy chicken thighs. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy foods, you can add more honey and less sriracha. Conversely, if you like spicy foods, consider a 1:1 ratio of sriracha and honey.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 40-45 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 5-6 bone-in, skin-on chicken thighs 1 tablespoon olive oil 1/3 cup honey 2 tablespoons sriracha hot sauce 1/2 teaspoon kosher salt 1/2 teaspoon black pepper Sesame seeds as a garnish (optional) Directions Preheat oven to 350°F Season the chicken.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta/</guid><description>The ricotta is an Italian cheese made by cooking the whey (liquid byproduct of the cheese production), by cooking it at an high temperature (80-90°C), hence the name &amp;ldquo;ricotta&amp;rdquo;, which means &amp;ldquo;cooked again&amp;rdquo;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s typically made from the whey, you can make it directly from the milk as well.
Ingredients thermometer 1 cheesecloth 1 cheese recipient 2l of whey 500ml of milk (or if not using whey, 2l of milk) 10g of table salt 6g of citric acid (contained in 130ml of lemon juice) Directions Preparation Pour the milk (and/or whey) and the salt into a pot, stir it well, and heat it up to 80°C.</description></item><item><title>Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 14 Ingredients 1 1/4 lbs (600 grams) tomatoes 1 14.5 oz (400 grams) canned tomatoes 1 green onion 1 red onion 1 jalapeño pepper 1 handfull fresh cilantro 1 clove garlic 1/2 lime, juice squeezed (optional) 1 chili pepper (optional) 1/4 tsp ground cumin (optional) Directions Add all ingredients to a food processor and burst shortly for desired degree of chunkyness.</description></item><item><title>Sardine Cakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</guid><description>Can be served with a Spicy Yogurt Sauce as Tapas or Hors D’Oeuvres.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🧊 Chill time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 15 Ingredients Sardine Fish Cakes 2 tins sardines (~4oz) ½ cup mayonnaise ½ cup Panko breadcrumbs 2 teaspoons Old Bay seasoning 1 egg lemon juice (optional) Spicy Yogurt Sauce ½ cup plain yogurt (whole milk) 1 tablespoon sriracha 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce minced garlic (optional) Directions Remove sardines from tin, reserving oil, and place fish in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Lamb with Lemon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/slow-cooked-lamb-with-lemon/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need a good-sized lidded pot that can go in the oven for this. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that then you can use a large roasting tray with sides and cover it with foil, sealing it as best you can. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent celebration or Sunday meal.
Ingredients Lamb shoulder, or something similar, like lamb shank, preferably on the bone. Get something that will fit in your pot, with room for vegetables around it.</description></item><item><title>Tzatziki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tzatziki/</guid><description>A traditional greek dip that goes well with crackers, celery and carrots or in a greek gyro. Great for parties and sharing with your family friends. Can be eaten immediately after preparation or after a few hours of being in the fridge for enhanced flavor.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Greek yogurt, 2 cups Cucumber, 3 inches Dill Garlic, 1 clove/teaspoon Olive oil, 1 teaspoon Lemon/lime or vinegar Salt and pepper Directions Finely grate the cucumber and chop the dill Strain the cucumber thoroughly with a clean kitchen towel Mash the garlic and the olive oil in a mortar and pestle Add all three to the Greek yogurt Squeeze in some lemon/lime or vinegar Add a generous pinch of salt and small pinch of pepper Optionally add some extra olive oil Stir and enjoy with your favorite snack</description></item><item><title>Baby Back Ribs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baby-back-ribs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baby-back-ribs/</guid><description>Some classic and delicious baby back ribs. Keep in mind that if you do not have a smoker, a grill with some tin-foil wrapped smoking wood with poked holes will suffice.
Ingredients Applewood (or other sweet cooking wood such as cherry or maple) 2 baby back rib racks 1 container of barbecue rub (Traeger Pork and Poultry Rub is recommended) Tin foil Bag of brown sugar Bottle of honey Barbecue Sauce (Oakland Dust, The One BBQ Sauce is recommended) (Optional) A stick of butter Directions Preheat your smoker to 180 degrees Fahrenheit using applewood.</description></item><item><title>Beef Wellington</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-wellington/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-wellington/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep Time: 10 min 🍳Cook Time: 2 hours 🍽️Servings: 4 Ingredients 1lb of Fillet Beef Extra Virgin Olive Oil 1lb of mushrooms 4 Thinly Cut Slices of Ham 2tbsp of Yellow Mustard 7oz of Puff Pastry 2 Egg Yolks Beaten Side note: Fillet beef is preferred. It gives the beef wellington a soft, tender and juicy flavour. Trust me, using fillet is worth it.
Directions Season the fillet with salt and black pepper.</description></item><item><title>Full English Breakfast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/full-english-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/full-english-breakfast/</guid><description>This is a hearty English breakfast, common in the UK. This recipe is made up largely of ingredients that someone would have in their fridge/cooler, although for an authentic experience, purchasing English back bacon and English sausages would be preferable.
🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 4 raw sausages (English sausages to be authentic) 4 slices of bacon (English back bacon to be authentic) 2 eggs half a tin (200g) of baked beans 2 slices of bread 1 large tomato half a cup (120g) of button mushrooms Directions Preheat your oven to 250°c or 480°F.</description></item><item><title>Medieval Beef Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/medieval-beef-soup/</guid><description>Medieval beef soup with turnips and turnip greens.
Ingredients One beef roast Around three to four large turnips with their greens attached Two cups of chicken stock 1/10 grams of Saffron 1/4 a stick of butter A slow cooker A bowl of warm water. Directions Cube the roast into bite sized pieces and place them in a large skillet with the butter. Heat the pan on medium-high heat and brown the meat with the melted butter until the outside is evenly cooked, sprinkle with pepper as it browns.</description></item><item><title>Aussie Snags (sausage sizzle)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aussie-snags/</guid><description>An Australian BBQ classic tradition that is simple and very easy to make. Great for parties and outdoor events especially national events. Sometimes served at hardware chains.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: Depends Ingredients Sausages (thin) Onions (4g per sausage) Tomato sauce Mustard (optional) White sliced bread Butter Oil Wood chips (optional, fuel for smokey flavour) Directions Chop up the onions into rings Bring the sausages to the grill, turning once every 5 mins Add oil of your choice to the hotplate then add the onions Use your tongs to toss the onions until they are golden brown When the onions are golden brown turn off the hotplate When the sausages are cooked, butter the bread, then the onions, and add a sausage (optionally split) Finally tomato sauce on top</description></item><item><title>Beef Kidney</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-kidney/</guid><description>My wife&amp;rsquo;s beef kidney recipe
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 beef kidney 60g butter 2 onions 2 shallots 1 sprig of fresh parsley 3 bay leaves 400g croutons or toasted bread in pieces Directions clean the kidney and remove the fat cut the kidney into small chunks (2cm or 3/4&amp;quot;) put butter in a casserole dish add kidney, parsley, bay leaf, salt, pepper brown in the casserole for 10 minutes while stirring (don&amp;rsquo;t burn) add 2 glasses of dry white wine add half a glass of water so that the mixture is well-bathed simmer for 35 minutes add about 400g of toasted bread in pieces simmer for another 10 minutes</description></item><item><title>Apple Pie</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients Filling 900 g (4-5) golden delicious apples 15 g (1 tbsp) lemon juice 50 g white sugar 65 g brown sugar 5 g (1 tsp) cinnamon 1-2 g nutmeg 15 g cornstarch 15 g ice water 226 g (2 sticks) cold butter, cut into slices Crust 350 g flour 5 g salt 30 g white sugar 225 g butter 50-100 ml ice water Egg Wash 1 egg (optional) 15 g water (optional) Directions Peel and cut the apples into 1-2 inch strips Put the apples in a bowl and mix in the lemon juice, sugar, cinnamon, nutmeg, and cornstarch and let it sit for 15 mins to release water Transfer the filling mixture to a sauce pan and reduce the liquid over medium to low heat for around 15 mins, stirring regularly, then turn off the gas While the filling is sitting / reducing, start the crust by putting the flour, salt, sugar, and pieces of butter in a food processor Run the food processor until it resembles a coarse sand (5-10 seconds) then start dripping in the ice water until the mixture starts to chunk together You&amp;rsquo;ll know when it&amp;rsquo;s done if you can pinch the dough with your hand and it sticks together Preheat oven to 350°F then start making the pie crust Cut the dough in half and roll both halves out with a rolling pin until they are big enough to cover your pie pan (around 9 inch diameter) Put the bottom half dough into the pie pan and cut off the excess dough with a knife Dump the sauce pan full of the filling into the pie pan and even it out Cover the pie filling with the top dough and fold over and tuck in the excess crust Use a fork or your fingers to pinch down the top crust to the bottom crust so you don&amp;rsquo;t have air gaps Optionally you can now brush on the egg wash to make the crust get a shiny golden brown color when it cooks Cut a few slits in the top crust with a knife to give it a nice design and allow for air to release Bake 45 minutes at 350°F or until the crust is brown to your liking and the apples are bubbling inside</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 230 g melted butter (2 sticks) 330 g bread flour 5 g salt 5 g baking soda 100-200 g white sugar 100-200 g brown sugar 1 egg 15 g milk 5 g vanilla 225 g 50-70% dark chocolate chips or semi-sweet milk chocolate chips Directions Preheat oven to 375°F Mix the flour, baking soda, and salt in a bowl Using a mixer or whisk, beat the butter, sugar, eggs, vanilla and milk in a separate bowl for a few mins Combine and stir in the dry ingredients, then the chocolate chips Use an ice cream scooper or spoon to make uniform balls of cookie dough to the size you like and evenly space them out on a parchment paper lined baking sheet (you may need more than one sheet depending on the size of the cookies) Bake in the oven one baking sheet at a time for around 8-10 minutes, taking them out when they start to brown Cool for a few minutes then put them on a cooling rack</description></item><item><title>Italian Mulled Wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-mulled-wine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-mulled-wine/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Crushed Ingredients 1 star anise 1 bay leaf 1 pinch rosemary 1 pinch peppercorn 1 pinch thyme 1 pinch red pepper 1 pinch fennel seeds 1 pinch cloves 1 pinch nutmeg Non-Crushed Ingredients 1 bottle Italian red wine 1 orange 1 lemon 1 tbsp honey 1 tsp vanilla 1 stick cinnamon 4 figs (optional) 100 ml limoncello (optional) 50 ml sweet vermouth (optional) 50 ml bourbon, brandy, or cognac (optional) Directions Pour the wine into a stock pot and turn the gas on medium high Crush all the &amp;ldquo;Crushed Ingredients&amp;rdquo; in a mortar and pestle Peel and juice the orange and lemon (toss the peels and juice into the wine but not the white pith) When the wine is up to a simmer, immediately bring the gas down to low and pour in all the rest of the ingredients Cook on low for at least 15 minutes to infuse the flavors Keep the flame on low so the wine stays warm and continues to infuse, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t bubble / burn off the alcohol Feel free to double the recipe or scale any of these ingredients up or down to suite your taste</description></item><item><title>Limoncello</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/limoncello/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/limoncello/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Wait time: 20 days 🍽️ Servings: 22 Ingredients 5-7 organic lemons (regular lemons are covered in wax) 300ml 95% ABV grain alcohol 700ml water 500ml sugar Directions Pour the alcohol into a 1 liter mason jar Peel the lemons avoiding the white pith (it will make your limoncello bitter) and submerse them in the alcohol Cover the jar and let the lemons infuse the alcohol for 20 days After the infusion is completed, create a simple syrup by boiling the water and dissolving the sugar in the water Allow the water to cool completely, then strain the alcohol into the sugar water and stir Bottle or put it back into the mason jar Feel free to scale the recipe up or down, and adjust the sugar to the sweetness you like, but the ABV should remain somewhere around 28-30%</description></item><item><title>Mapo Tofu (麻婆豆腐)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mapo-tofu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mapo-tofu/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Marinated Pork 450 g (1 lb) ground pork 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp Shaoxing cooking wine 1 tsp cornstarch 1 tsp white pepper powder Braise 2 tbsp spicy doubanjiang (la doubanjiang) 1 tsp dou-chi 2-3 chopped scallions white and green separated) 2-4 minced garlic cloves 2 inch minced ginger (similar amount as garlic) 400 ml chicken broth or water 340 g (1 package) soft tofu cut into 1.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom Stroganov</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-stragonov/</guid><description>Prep time: 10 Minutes Cook time: 20 Minutes Servings: 2
Ingredients 8 oz uncooked pasta (spaghetti or any other long noodle will work. Stroganov can also be served over rice.) 12 oz mushrooms (I reccommend shitake, but white, portabello, or maitake will also work.) 2 cloves of garlic, minced 1 small yellow onion, minced 2 Tbsp butter 1 Tbsp general purpose flour 1 Cup vegetable broth 1 Tsp dijon mustard 1 Tsp Smoked paprika 4 Tbsp creme fraiche (can be made by mixing equal parts heavy and sour cream) 2 Tbsp parsely Directions Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil and cook pasta al dente In a cup, combine flour, mustard, smoked paprika, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Ragu Napoletano</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu-napoletano/</guid><description>This recipe is known by Italian-Americans as &amp;ldquo;Sunday Gravy&amp;rdquo;, which originated from the Southern Italian dish Ragu Napoletano. This is my variation of my family&amp;rsquo;s version which was passed down 3 generations to me.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-60 min 🍳Cook time: 4-5 hrs 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 Ingredients Tomato Sauce 6-10 lbs San Marzano plum tomatoes (fresh or canned peeled) Tomato paste (optional) Aromatics and Herbs 8 cloves garlic 1.</description></item><item><title>Ravioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ravioli/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Dough 4 eggs 400 g 00 flour Drizzle of olive oil Cheese Filling 1 lemon 50 g grated Pecorino Romano cheese 250 g ricotta 1 egg Seafood Fillings Chopped leftover lobster legs, lobster tail, or minced crab (optional) Directions The basic rule of thumb I use for pasta is 100g, 1 egg per person For this recipe you can go two ways, the old school &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo; method or a kitchen aid mixer (skip to step 7) For the well method, pile the flour onto the counter and with your hand carve a hole or a well in the center Crack the eggs into the center of the well, and drizzle a bit of olive oil into the center With a fork, begin slowly breaking up, mixing, and incorporating the egg into the flour until there is no longer any loose egg that can escape the outer well border At this point use your hands to bring the sandy mixture together and knead the dough for about 5-10 minutes or until the dough is smooth For the stand mixer method just throw all the ingredients into the mixer with a dough hook and set it to level 4 for about 3-5 minutes and it will be done You might need to scrape the sides down and maybe hand knead the dough a bit longer after it&amp;rsquo;s done to make it into a nice smooth ball Cover the dough with plastic wrap and let it rest in the fridge a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s easier to roll out (15-30 mins) While the dough is resting, make the filling by first mixing the ricotta and egg into a bowl Zest and juice a lemon peel into the bowl Optionally add seafood ingredients at this point Grate the Pecorino into the bowl, add salt and pepper to taste, and mix to distribute the ingredients evenly Take out the dough and cut it into 4 pieces, keeping the ones not currently being worked on covered so they don&amp;rsquo;t dry out Roll the dough out with a pasta machine down to the point where you can just barely see your hand through it (setting 2-3 out of 7) or roll it out with a rolling pin into a long sheet, maybe like 16 x 8 inches or so At this point you can either cut the sheet in half and make two sheets, a top and bottom, or one sheet, where you will fold the dough over and use the folded seam as one side of the ravioli Using a teaspoon, evenly space out the ricotta filling onto the sheets, leaving a few inches on each side for the seams As stated in step 16, either take the 2nd sheet and place it over top or fold over the dough and press down firmly, forcing out any air and making sure the two pieces of dough stick You may need to brush some water onto the dough if it is too heavily floured and not sticking Using a fancy pasta cutter, a knife, or even a pizza cutter, cut evenly between the seams of the raviolis to separate them If you used a pasta cutter, you are now done, store the raviolis on a floured wax paper sheet or freeze them for later If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a pasta cutter, use a fork to press down the dough around the edges of the cut raviolis to ensure they are firmly closed and no leaks or air bubbles are visible, or else they will explode when cooked To cook, throw them in salted boiling water and they will let you know when they&amp;rsquo;re done when they float to the top (1-2 minutes) Serve the seafood version with a simple fresh red sauce and basil, or spice it up a bit and go with a base of red sauce with some added heavy cream, and a pinch of red pepper flakes to make a pink sauce for the seafood version</description></item><item><title>Soleier (pickled eggs)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/soleier/</guid><description>Soleier are a german pub dish. They are typically enjoyed between two beers.
⏲️ Preparation time: 10min 🍳 Cook time: 10min 🍽️ Servings: 10 Ingredients peels of five onions 10 eggs 2 loorber leaves 3 cloves 4 allspice 1Tbsp peppercorns 1Tbsp caraway seeds 1Tbsp mustard seeds 1tsp of Szechuan pepper (optional) 1tsp lovage (optional) 1tsp nutmeg (optional) 100mL vinegar 3 cloves of garlic Directions Put 750mL of water and the peels of five onions in a pot and let them cook for five minutes.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tenders Airfried</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tenders-airfried/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min Ingredients Raw chicken strips Flour Egg wash Bread crumbs Olive oil Seasoning: salt and pepper with cayenne or paprika (optional) Directions In a plate, mix a little over a table spoon of spices into your flour. Dip the chicken into the flour one strip at a time coating the entire surface. Dip the floured chicken into the eggwash.</description></item><item><title>Chorizo &amp; Chickpea Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chorizo-and-chickpea-soup/</guid><description>Recommend serving with corn bread.
🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Chorizo Sausage(s) 2 Garlic cloves Ginger Paprika, 2 Tsp Cumin, Parsley Juice from whole Lemon Chickpeas, 400g ( drained ) Butter and sunflower oil, for frying Directions Fry the sliced Chorizo in butter, along-with diced Ginger and Garlic. Add oil after a couple mins. Pour in Lemon-juice, Chickpeas, and Cumin &amp;amp; Paprika. Then 100ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Coleslaw</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coleslaw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coleslaw/</guid><description>This is a coleslaw recipe that I got from a chili restaurant in my neighborhood that closed down a few years ago. This recipe makes more dressing than needed for the coleslaw, so you can save it or use it as a vegetable dip.
⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🥶 Fridge time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 8 - 10 Ingredients 3/4 cup mayonnaise 1/2 cup buttermilk 3 tbsp lemon juice 3 tbsp apple cider vinegar 4 tbsp distilled vinegar 1/3 cup olive oil 1/4 cup granulated sugar 1 1/2 tsp kosher salt 1 tsp ground black pepper 1 tsp celery seeds 1/2 tsp onion powder 1/4 tsp granulated garlic 1/4 tsp mustard powder One large head of green cabbage One large carrot Directions Finely shred, rinse, and drain the carrot Finely shred the cabbage (use a food processor if possible) Whisk together the mayonnaise, buttermilk, lemon juice, cider vinegar, distilled vinegar, olive oil, and sugar Add the salt, pepper, celery seeds, onion powder, and granulated garlic, and combine well Combine the shredded cabbage and carrot in a separate bowl Slowly add the dressing until it lightly coats the vegetables, and toss well.</description></item><item><title>Curry sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</guid><description>I like to make double this amount and freeze the rest.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 25g butter 1 onion, sliced 2 garlic cloves, sliced Thumb of ginger, sliced 2 tbsp curry powder 1/2 tsp turmeric 1 tbsp malt vinegar 1 star anise 250ml chicken stock 1 tbsp cornflour 2 tbsp water Lemon juice (optional) Directions Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Honey Garlic Chicken with Broccoli and Brown Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/honey-garlic-chicken/</guid><description>Very easy, high protein.
Servings: 2 Ingredients 1/2 cup ( 100g ) brown rice 1/2 cup ( 70g ) frozen peas 1 head broccoli (you can use really any amount of broccoli) 2 chicken breasts 1 tbsp honey 1 tbsp low-sodium soy sauce 1 tbsp minced garlic Directions Cook rice in a pot. Instructions are on the bag it comes in. While rice is cooking, cut chicken breasts into cube.</description></item><item><title>Dianne's Southwestern Cornbread Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/diannes-southwest-salad/</guid><description>Dianne&amp;rsquo;s Southwestern Cornbread Salad is as colorful as it is delicious.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-12 🥶 Chill: 2 hrs Ingredients 1 (6-ounce) package Mexican cornbread mix 1 (1-ounce) envelope buttermilk Ranch salad dressing mix 1 small head romaine lettuce, shredded 2 large tomatoes, chopped 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained 1 (8-ounce) package shredded Mexican four-cheese blend 6 bacon slices, cooked and crumbled 5 green onions, chopped Directions Prepare cornbread according to package directions, cool, and crumble.</description></item><item><title>Tanzanian Tea w/ Milk</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tanzania-tea-with-milk/</guid><description>This is a very traditional simple beverage from Tanzania, a country in East Africa. While I stayed there in Mwanza and Dar es Salaam, they would always have this option for breakfast (or in general).
⏲️ Prep time: 5-10 min 🍳 Cook time: 3-8 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Black Ceylon Tea (Preferably, you want a dark, herbal flavor from your tea. I have some from Dar es Salaam, but when I tried researching, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find out what kind of tea it is.</description></item><item><title>Yorkshire Puddings</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yorkshire-puddings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yorkshire-puddings/</guid><description>Basically the northern England equivalent of the french pancake ( a means to make use of extra flour when you didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough for bread ). They go well with Sunday Roasts. Puddings may be preserved in freezer for up to a month.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 140g flour 4 eggs 200ml milk sunflower oil Directions Preheat oven to 230°C / gas mark 8.</description></item><item><title>Baked pasta with broccoli, boiled eggs and scamorza cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-pasta-with-broccoli/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 20~30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g pasta 500g broccoli 4 eggs 200g scamorza cheese 400g béchamel sage (optional) parmesan cheese (optional) Directions Boil water and add salt (a handful for every liter), put pasta inside. Boil broccoli and eggs for 10 minutes. While everything is boiling dice scamorza cheese, prepare a pan. Put a layer of béchamel.</description></item><item><title>Challah Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/challah-bread/</guid><description>A kind of braided bread preparation.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 2-4 NOTE: Prep time does not account for the 3-4 hours the dough must be left to rise and cool (see directions 5, 10, &amp;amp; 12).
Ingredients 600ml ( 1 Pint ) warm water 1 tablespoon dry active baking yeast 7 tablespoons honey 1.5kg flour 3 eggs 1 tablespoon salt 1 tablespoon poppy seeds 4 tablespoons olive oil Directions Fill a large bowl with the water, and sprinkle with the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Oatmeal Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oatmeal-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 2 eggs 40g sugar (3 tbsp) 20g honey (1 tbsp) 60ml milk (4 tbsp) (you can use water instead) 120g oat flour (1 cup) 1 tsp baking powder (or baking soda + some acid to activate it) Raspberry jam (optional) Directions Mix eggs, sugar, honey and milk. In another bowl mix oat flour and baking powder.</description></item><item><title>Quarkbällchen – Fried curd balls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quarkbaellchen/</guid><description>“Quark” is a type of fresh dairy product. It&amp;rsquo;s usually translated as curd cheese or cottage cheese.
Ingredients 420ml quark (plain yoghurt can be used as a replacement) 2 eggs 6 or 7 tbsp of sugar 2 packets of vanilla sugar 400g flour (500g if using yoghurt) 2 packets of baking powder 1L sunflower oil for frying (Optional) icing sugar (Optional) Alcohol by eye so that they do not soak up so much oil Directions Mix ingredients (quark, eggs, sugar, flour, baking powder) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Yibin Burning Noodles</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yibin-burning-noodles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yibin-burning-noodles/</guid><description>This is a dry noodle dish from the town of Yibin in Sichuan, China.
Ingredients Yibin Chili Oil Sichuan ground chilies, 1/3 cup Roasted rapeseed oil (caizi you) or Chinese peanut oil, 2/3 cup Peeled and smashed ginger, 2 inches Cassia bark (or cinnamon stick), 2 inches Star anise, 2 Chinese black cardamom (optional), 1 Sichuan peppercorn, 1 tsp Roughly chopped walnut pieces, 2 tbsp High-quality melted pork lard, 1/3 cup Noodles Fresh alkaline noodles, 150g Yibin Chili Oil, 2 tbsp Light soy sauce, 1 tbsp White sesame oil, 1 tbsp Toasted yacai, 2 tbsp Mixed toasted crushed peanuts/sesame, 2 tbsp Sliced scallion greens, 2 tbsp MSG, 1/4 tbsp Directions Yibin Chili Oil Add ground chilies to a heat-proof jar or bowl.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/burger-dressing/</guid><description>A delicious home made hamburger dressing 🍔
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min Ingredients 3 tbsp mayonnese or aioli 2 tbsp ketchup 1 tbsp sriracha 1 clove garlic, if using mayonnese and not aioli (optional) Directions Mix ingredients in a bowl</description></item><item><title>Italian Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/italian-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2.5 - 3.25 hr 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients 600g or 5 cups bread flour (or all-purpose if not available) 1 packet (appr. 2 1/4 tsp or 7g) active dry yeast olive oil for greasing Directions Follow directions on the packet to activate yeast in a bowl large enough for mixing the dough Add enough water for a total of 400g or 1 3/4 cups (i.</description></item><item><title>Lenten Lentil Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-lentil-curry/</guid><description>Simple green lentil recipe. Suitable for Lent.
Prep time: 5 min Cook time: 30-35 min Servings : 2 Ingredients 200 g (7 oz) green lentils 50 g (1¾ oz) vermicelli 1 tsp curry powder ½ tsp paprika powder ½ tsp cinnamon powder ½ tsp ground sumac Directions Thoroughly rinse the lentils and drain the water. Put the lentils in the pot, and add 1 L (0.</description></item><item><title>Mayonnaise or aioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mayonnaise-or-aioli/</guid><description>Aioli is pretty much just mayonnaise with garlic, although traditional aioli only includes olive oil and garlic, and no eggs or acid. This recipe uses raw eggs, so if that is sketchy in your region use pasteurized eggs 🥚.
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 min Ingredients 1 whole egg or 2 egg yolks, preferably at room temperature 2.5 dl/ 1 cup neutral oil 1-2 tbsp vinegar or lemon juice 1 tbsp pickle juice (optional) 2-4 cloves of garlic for aioli, don&amp;rsquo;t include for mayonnaise 1 tsp dijon mustard (optional) Directions Place egg, vinegar, mustard a pinch of salt and pepper in a beaker or narrow and tall container.</description></item><item><title>Mazurek</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mazurek/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mazurek/</guid><description>Mazurek is a traditional Polish flat cake made in many homes for Easter. Many different toppings are possible.
Ingredients 2 1/2 cups flour 1/4 cup powdered sugar 200g (7 oz) butter 1 tablespoon 18% sour cream 2 egg yolks topping: for example orange jam from 4 oranges optional additional toppings/decorations: walnuts pecans raisins sliced almonds Directions Put flour and butter in a bowl. Cut the butter with a sharp knife into tiny pieces, mixing with the flour.</description></item><item><title>Okonomiyaki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/okonomiyaki/</guid><description>Okonomiyaki is a Japanese savory pancake. Instead of using air bubbles to lighten the pancake, thin strips of cabbage provide levity to the cake. This is a very popular street food in Japan, and can be topped with all sorts of different ingredients, as &amp;ldquo;Okonomiyaki&amp;rdquo; roughly translates to &amp;ldquo;Grilled how you like&amp;rdquo;.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 125g flour</description></item><item><title>Orange jam</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-jam/</guid><description>This jam is a traditional topping for the Polish mazurek, but can be used as a generic sweet spread.
Ingredients 4 medium sized oranges 1 lemon 1 1/2 cup sugar Directions Zest all fruit. Peel off the albedo (the white part under the skin). Blend the fruit (not too much, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to become an even mush, just cut up into small pieces). Combine the blended fruit, zest, and sugar in a pot.</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian Vareniki</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-vareniki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-vareniki/</guid><description>(Vareniki/Dumplings) Vareniki are popular all over the world, but abroad they have different names.
⏲️ Prep: 30 mins 🍳 Cook time: 25 mins 🍽️ Servings: 45 Ingredients 18 ounces potatoes 3 cups all-purpose flour ¼ cup sour cream ½ teaspoon baking soda ½ cup water ¼ cup butter 2 onions, finely diced 3 ½ cups finely chopped button mushrooms Directions Place potatoes into a large pot and cover with salted water; bring to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Coriander Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Boneless chicken marinated in a gravy of yoghurt and coriander
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 500g boneless chicken breast 250g fat free yoghurt 250g coriander leaves Mustard oil / Sunflower oil Sugar Ginger Garlic 2 medium onions Green chillies Garam masala 2/3 Cardamom pods 1 Bayleaf 1 Cinnamom stick Directions Cut the boneless chicken into small bite sized pieces.</description></item><item><title>Garam Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</guid><description>A spice mixture for most Indian dishes
Ingredients 4 Green Cardamom 2 Black Cardamom 1 tbsp Coriander 2 Cloves 1 tbsp Cumin 1 tbsp Fennel seeds 5/6 Bayleaf 5/6 Black pepper pods 1 Star anise (Optional) Mace (Optional): Mace is a dried flower originating from the Nutmeg plant. Use no more than 3 strands of this flower. Directions Star anise and Mace are normally not added to Garam masala.</description></item><item><title>Hoisin Pork Belly</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hoisin-pork-belly/</guid><description>Melt-in-mouth fatty pork in a sweet and spicy glaze.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 15 mins 🍽 Servings: 2 Ingredients 400g high fat pork belly (no skin) large thumb of ginger 4 cloves of garlic 1 scotch bonnet chili 2 tbsp ketchup 2 tbsp hoisin sauce 2 tbsp honey 2 tsp sesame oil 1 spring onion Directions Cut pork belly into 1 inch cubes.</description></item><item><title>Ukrainian Borscht</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ukrainian-borscht/</guid><description>Borscht is a beet soup that originates from Ukraine and is common in Eastern Europe and North Asia. Depending on the recipe, borscht may be purely vegetarian; it may be served either hot or cold; and it may range from a hearty one-pot meal to a clear broth or a smooth drink.
⏲️ Prep time: 25 mins 🍳 Cook time: 40 mins 🍽️ Servings: 10 Ingredients 3 red beetroots 4 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil 8 cups chicken broth + 2 cups water 3 yukon potatoes 2 carrots 2 celery ribs 1 onion 4 Tbsp ketchup or 3 Tbsp tomato sauce 1 red bell pepper (optional) 1 can white cannelini beans with their juice (optional) 2 bay leaves (optional) 1 pressed garlic clove (optional) 1 cup sour cream (optional) fresh dill to taste (optional) Directions Peel, grate and/or slice all vegetables (keeping sliced potatoes in cold water to prevent browning until ready to use then drain).</description></item><item><title>Lebanese Lentil Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lebanese-lentil-soup/</guid><description>author: skipper-davies Lebanese-Style Lentil Soup with Swiss Chard and Lemon
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 3 cups red lentils 12 cups water 1 large red onion, diced 2 small Yukon gold potatoes, diced 1 medium zucchini, diced 4 cups Swiss chard, chopped 1 bunch of cilantro, chopped ¼ cup of lemon juice, more to taste 1 teaspoon cumin Directions In a large pot, add lentils and water and place on medium heat to boil.</description></item><item><title>Shepherd's Pie</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shepherds-pie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shepherds-pie/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 50 - 60 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 - 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 600 grams (g) of mealy/floury potatoes 2 onions 2 carrots 4 tablespoons (tbsp.) of oil 800 g of minced lamb 100 g of frozen peas 2 tbsp. of tomato paste/puree 300 milliliters (ml) beef stock 1 tbsp. of sweet or smoked paprika 30 g of butter 200 ml of milk 1 pinch of nutmeg Directions Peel potatoes, cut into cubes and boil in saltwater for 20 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Smoked Turkey</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkey-smoked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkey-smoked/</guid><description>Turkey, smoked on a charcoal grill
⏲️ Prep time: 120 min 🍳 Cook time: 90-180 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 4-15 Ingredients 1 turkey, 5-15 lb. (thawed) 1-2 cups whipped butter (room temperature) 2 cup chicken broth 1-4 tbsp garlic powder (optional) 1 lb mixed vegetables (carrots, potatoes, broccoli, etc.) (optional) Directions Mix garlic powder into the whipped butter. Remove giblets and other materials from the turkey cavity.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Mayo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spicy-mayo/</guid><description>A simple sauce that is at almost every sushi bar in the United States.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 min Ingredients chili sauce (e.g Sriracha) mayonnaise sesame oil Directions Add 2 parts mayonnaise to 1 part chili sauce in a bowl. Add 1 tbsp of sesame oil for every cup of mayonnaise you use. Mix all of the ingredients together, and taste test it for more chili sauce or mayonnaise.</description></item><item><title>Torrijas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/torrijas/</guid><description>Torrijas are a spanish dessert traditionally eaten during the Holy Week (Easter). It is said they were first cooked using the leftovers from the Lent.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min Ingredients Dried bread (or Torrijas bread). Must be bread from a regular loaf, not from a tin loaf. Milk (to soak the bread, 2 cups per 16 torrijas approx.) Eggs (to coat the bread, 2 eggs per 16 torrijas approx.</description></item><item><title>Collard Greens with Smoked Duck and Parsnips</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/collard-greens-with-smoked-duck-and-parnips/</guid><description>This dish was a pandemic leftover invention loosely inspired by Ethiopian gomen. It can be served as a side dish, but we eat it an an entree. If you intend it as a side dish, then this serves 4. The smoked duck adds a bit of saltiness, so it&amp;rsquo;s better to season to taste after cooking. Serve with good quality, crusty bread.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1/2 smoked duck breast (skin on) chopped 1 large onion sliced 1 small parsnip julienned 1 large bunch collard greens chopped into ribbons 1/2 green cabbage cut into ribbons (optional) 1–2 tablespoons olive oil and/or butter 1 teaspoon ground coriander 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon 1/2 teaspoon garam masala Directions In a large dutch oven (or a big pot with a lid) on low heat, add the chopped duck breast and olive oil and/or butter to the pot for a couple of minutes.</description></item><item><title>Demi-glace</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/demi-glace/</guid><description>This is a take on a traditional demi-glace without needing to buy an astronomically large amount of veal bones. Use this as your main base for pan sauces, an extra flavor bomb, or a replacement for recipes that call for broth or stock.
These are the basic proportions &amp;ndash; multiply as needed. I typically multiply by six to give me several weeks worth of demi-glace ice cubes.
Ingredients 1 qt (32 oz, 946mL) low-sodium broth or stock (I prefer Pacific Foods) 1 1/4 oz (7g) packet unflavored, unsweetened gelatin 1 teaspoon (5mL) tomato paste 1 teaspoon (5mL) low-sodium soy sauce 1/2 teaspoon onion powder (very optional) Directions Put the tomato paste in a large pot, then turn the heat on medium Spread the paste around the bottom of the pot and stir until it just barely starts to brown Deglaze with the broth Stir in all other ingredients and boil over high heat until reduced to about 1/6th of its original volume Freeze in ice cub trays</description></item><item><title>Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hearty-breakfast-oatmeal/</guid><description>If your Oatmeal isn&amp;rsquo;t Hearty Breakfast Oatmeal&amp;hellip; Is it even Oatmeal?
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Serving: 1 hearty serving Ingredients 1/2 cup Large Flake Oats (no partially cooked quick-oats allowed!) Almonds Pecans 1 Tbsp Roasted Flax Seed 1 Tbsp Hemp Hearts Cranberries (adjust amount to preference) 1/2 Banana (mashed) 1 cup Milk (3.25% if possible) Cinnamon (adjust amount to preference) 1 Egg ON Vanilla Ice Cream Protein Powder (optional) Directions Chop or mash nuts and fruit.</description></item><item><title>Shakshouka</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shakshouka/</guid><description>Shakshouka is a dish of eggs poached in a sauce of tomatoes, olive oil, peppers, onion and garlic, and commonly spiced with cumin, paprika, cayenne pepper, and nutmeg. This recipe is a quick and simple version for a delicious breakfast.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 5 small tomatoes 5 eggs 1 peeled white onion some chives cumin powdered sweet pepper Directions Scald the tomatoes so they are easier to peel.</description></item><item><title>Basic Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/basic-meatballs/</guid><description>Hybrid beef/pork meatballs perfect for spaghetti and meatballs or a meatball sub.
🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound ground beef (preferably 90/10 or 93/7) 1 pound ground pork 1/2 cup italian breadcrumbs 1/3 cup milk (I use 2% but doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much) 1/4 cup yellow onion diced (about 1/2 small yellow onion) 1 egg 1/2 cup shredded parmesan 1/4-1/2 cup chopped parsley 2 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp dried oregano 1 tbsp rosemary 1 tbsp basil 1 tbsp garlic powder Salt and pepper to taste Directions Preheat oven to 200°C/400F In a bowl, combine all ingredients Hand form into balls by packing with your hands and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Fondue</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fondue/</guid><description>A swiss classic for cold winter dinners. Traditionally cooked in a &amp;ldquo;Caquelon&amp;rdquo; pot and served on a candle heated stove, to keep the cheese from going solid again.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 garlic clove 4 dl (1.5 cups) white wine 800 g (1.7 lbs) swiss cheese (50/50 mix of Gruyère and Emmentaler recommended) 1 shot of kirsch (cherry brandy) 1 tsp lemon juice 1-2 tbsp starch flour 1 loaf (~800g/~1.</description></item><item><title>Ricotta lasagna filling</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ricotta-lasagna-filling/</guid><description>A quick and easy filling for lasagna based on ricotta
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0 min 🍽️ Servings: 5-6 Ingredients Ricotta cheese One large egg Parmesan cheese Oregano (Optional) Directions Mix the ricotta cheese together with a handful of finely grated parmesan. Add the oregano and the egg and mix. Add salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti all'amatriciana</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-all-amatriciana/</guid><description>Ignore the fact that those in the photo are pennette and not spaghetti, that&amp;rsquo;s all I had that day.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Pecorino romano cheese preferably or Parmesan 1.5oz (40g) Fresh chili pepper (as many as you&amp;rsquo;d like) Extra virgin olive oil 1/4 cup (40g) Guanciale preferably or Bacon 3.5oz (100g) White wine 1/4 cup (60g) Tomato passata 10oz (300g) Spaghetti or similar long pasta 12oz (350g) (optional) Extra pecorino romano or parmesan Directions Grate the pecorino and keep it aside.</description></item><item><title>Turkish Yogurt Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/turkish-yogurt-soup/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients yogurt 1/3 cup rice 2 tablespoon flour 1 egg yolk butter Directions wash the rice put water in the pot and wait for water to boil add some salt and rice wait for 15 minutes mix yogurt, egg and flour and salt in a different bowl add water from the soup and mix by warming when the rice is soft, add the yogurt mixture to the soup and mix quickly cut down the heat, wait for 15 minutes for the sauce, simply melt the butter in a separate small pan and stir in the dried mint add sauteed dried mint to the soup and stir well serve warm</description></item><item><title>Asian Style Chicken with Sticky Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/asian-style-chicken-sticky-sauce/</guid><description>Asian style crispy coated chicken with sweetish sauce recipe. Served with boiled rice.
Ingredients Chicken with crispy coating Around 14 ounces or 400 grams of chicken breast 1 Egg 3 tbsp of cornflour 10 tbsp all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp garlic powder 2 tsp paprika powder Around 5 tbsp of sesame oil for frying the chicken Sauce 1 tbsp sesame oil 2 garlic cloves, mashed to paste. 1 tbsp Chinese rice vinegar or alternatively white wine vinegar 3 tbsp honey 2 tbsp ketchup 2 tbsp brown sugar 4 tbsp soy sauce Directions Prepare the sauce by mixing the ingredients together in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Bolo do Caco (Caco Bread)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolo-do-caco/</guid><description>A traditional Madeiran-Portuguese Bread
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 💤 Rest time: 3 days 🍽️ Servings: 10 breads Ingredients Imperial
1¾ lb sweet potato 8 cups all-purpose flour ⅔ cup water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry - yeast 3 teaspoons salt Metric
750 g sweet potato 1 kg all-purpose flour 150 ml water (warm at 75F / 35C) 3 tablespoons active dry yeast 3 teaspoons salt Directions Peel the sweet potatoes.</description></item><item><title>Bolognese Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolognese-sauce/</guid><description>Basic bolognese sauce for lasagne or pasta dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 45 min 🍳 Cook time: at least 4 hours Ingredients extra virgin olive oil 2 carrots 2 celery sticks 1 large onion 2 garlic cloves (optional, but not traditional) 200 grams pancetta (optional) 300 grams beef mince 350 grams pork mince 350 grams veal mince (if you cant find veal replace with pork) 140 grams concentrated tomato paste 690 grams diced tomatoes water 1 can peeled tomatoes 1-2 glasses wine (whatever you have open) 1 glass of milk (optional) 1 glass of beef/vegetable stock (optional) Directions Finely dice the carrots, celery, onion and pancetta, if your blender can handle it you can optionally blend all this to speed it up.</description></item><item><title>Brown Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/brown-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brown-sauce/</guid><description>A very basic sauce that can be used for various dishes.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 1 onion 75g butter 1dl flour 1l bouillon Black pepper freshly grounded Directions Chop and sauté the onions and put the aside for a while Melt the butter on a pan and add the flour to it Brown the flour on medium heat until the mixture is dark brown Add the bouillon in small batches while stirring with a whisker Let the sauce boil and thicken for few minutes Add the onions and ground some pepper in the sauce (optional) Add preferred meat to the sauce or use as is</description></item><item><title>Corn Salsa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/corn-salsa/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 Minutes 🍳 Cook time: 1 Hour+ in fridge Ingredients 2 pounds frozen corn, defrosted 1/2 Red onion, finely chopped 4 Radishes, sliced thin and chopped Few pinches of Cilantro, finely chopped 1-2 Jalepenos, finely chopped (optional) Juice of 2-3 Limes Salt and pepper, to taste Directions Chop everything to pieces smaller than the corn kernels. Mix well and let sit covered in the fridge for at least an hour, even better overnight.</description></item><item><title>Country Crisp Cereals</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/country-crisp-cereals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/country-crisp-cereals/</guid><description>This is a recipe for making Jordan&amp;rsquo;s Country Crisp-like cereals.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳Cook time: 2 h 🍽️ Servings: 7 Ingredients Oat Flakes (270 g - 800 mL) Rice Flour (or any other flour) (20 g - 55mL) Sugar (100 g) Crushed Hazelnuts (20 g) Oil (any type) (60 g - 75 mL) Water (50 g) Chocolate (70 g) (optional) Vanilla Extract (1/2 tsp) (optional) Directions Preheat the oven at 120°C.</description></item><item><title>Egg Roll in a Bowl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggroll-in-a-bowl/</guid><description>Egg rolls, but, you know, in a bowl.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 pound ground turkey 1 bag coleslaw mix 1 small onion 2-3 cloves of garlic 1 tbsp fresh ginger 1/4 cup Hoisin sauce soy sauce sesame oil Directions Grate or mince ginger finely. Process with the garlic cloves by grinding with salt under the edge of a knife.</description></item><item><title>Erwtensoep (Dutch pea soup)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/erwtensoep/</guid><description>Erwtensoep, also called snert, is the Dutch version of pea soup. Slices of rookworst (smoked sausage) are added before serving. The soup, which is traditionally eaten during the winter, is emblematic of Dutch cuisine. It is customarily served with Frisian rye bread (roggebrood) and bacon, cheese or butter. Pancakes are sometimes served with pea soup; this dish is called snert met struif, struif referring to the pancakes.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 7 1/2 cups / 1.</description></item><item><title>French Onion Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-onion-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 6-7 Onions, cut into quarter moons 1 stick of butter 1/2 cup Olive oil Salt, to taste 1 Baguette Loaf, sliced 1 Can of Chicken Broth 3 Garlic cloves, finely chopped 1/4 cup brown sugar Balsamic vinegar, to taste Worcestershire Sauce, to taste Soy Sauce, to taste 64oz Beef Broth 2-3 Bay Leaves Melty cheese, preferably guereye or swiss Directions Sweat the onions in a covered Dutch oven over med-low heat, salt them, with 1 whole stick of butter and some olive oil for about 2 hours stirring occasionally but increasing in frequency as the heat gets raised over time.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garlic-toast/</guid><description>Garlic toast, perfect as a substitute for crackers in a cheese platter.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min Ingredients Any kind of firm, thin, sliced bread (Sourdough, Baguette) Garlic-infused olive oil (Optionally substitute butter or regular olive oil) Garlic salt Directions Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F). Place sliced bread on a baking tray lined with aluminium foil. Generously coat bread slices with garlic-infused olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Lemon and oregano chicken traybake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-and-oregano-chicken-traybake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (in 10 minute intervals) 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 8 chicken thighs (skin on) 500g new potato 100g bacon lardon 8 shallots 5 oregano sprigs / heavy sprinkle of oregano leaves 2 tbsp olive oil 2 lemons 200ml chicken stock 100ml white wine Directions Heat oven to 220C/200C with fan/gas 7. While oven is heating up cut the new potatoes into 0.</description></item><item><title>Lobster bisque</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid><description>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 🍳Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 litres Ingredients 1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams 2 onions 2 carrots 1 shallot 2 garlic cloves cognac 3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree 4 tomatoes 3 tbsp flour 1 glass dry white wine 2 litres fish stock 1 bayleaf 2 twigs of thyme fresh parsley heavy cream olive oil 2 tbsp butter Directions Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.</description></item><item><title>Meatloaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/meatloaf/</guid><description>This recipe will result in two or three glass dishes of tasty, moist meatloaf. Great for family suppers.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 6+ Ingredients 4 1/2 pounds Ground beef 1 Onion 2 Slices of bread 4 Eggs 1/4 Cup of milk Garlic salt Onion powder Mustard Sugar free ketchup 3 Cubes of brown sugar 1 Can of Campbell&amp;rsquo;s tomato soup Franks RedHot sauce (Optional) Directions Once thawed, put all of your beef into a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Miso-soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-soup/</guid><description>Miso-soup is Japanese traditional home cooking.
Ingredients dashi stock miso paste tofu(optional) seaweed(optional) green onion(optional) Directions put about half of the water in the pot and bring the water to a boil. put the dashi stock in the pot. if you use tofu or seaweed, cut the ingredients into bite-sized pieces, place the ingredients in the pot and bring to a boil. Melt the miso in the water and bring the water to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid><description>Ingredients 250g cubes paneer 1 onion 1 capsicum 200ml tomato puree 1 tsp red chilli powder 1 tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp coriander powder 1/2 tsp garam masala powder 100ml thick yogurt 1 tsp fenugreek powder dry fenugreek leaves cardamom cumin seeds shaved ginger 20ml garlic paste 1 bowl corn Directions Take a glass container, and mix the cubed paneers with half a tea spoon of red chilli powder, turmeric powder, coriander powder, garam masala powder, fenugreek powder, and 50g yogurt.</description></item><item><title>Pepper Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pepper-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pepper-sauce/</guid><description>A very basic pepper sauce that is great for steaks and other dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 tablespoon freshy ground rose pepper, green pepper and black pepper 1 teaspoon dijon mustard 1dl bouillon 2dl cream Salt if needed Directions Ground the peppers and put them on the pan and roast them for about one minute while moving the peppers with your spatula Mix in the mustard and bouillon and bring to a boil Add in the cream and let the sauce thicken on medium heat for about 10-20 minutes Taste the sauce and add salt if needed</description></item><item><title>Pho Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pho-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pho-soup/</guid><description>Vietnamese Pho Soup is a tea-like, beef based soup with a flavor profile that differentiates it from the traditional Western palette. This recipe is designed to be as easy to make as possible, while simultaneously being as based as possible.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings:4 Ingredients Garlic (4-8 large cloves) Spring Onions Cardamom Seeds (10 or so) Star Anise (4-5) Ginger Cinnamon Sticks (3-5 sticks) Diced Beef (300g) Beef Bones with marrow (3x) Beef bouillon cubes (1-3) Coriander (to taste) 1 Lime (to taste) Fish/Oyster Sauce Honey or Brown Sugar Rice noodles Directions Heat your oven and place the spices (garlic, cardamom seeds, cinnamon sticks, star anise and ginger) on a tray and bake them until browned or decently toasted.</description></item><item><title>Potato sourdough bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-potato-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min Ingredients 150g boiled potatoes in there skin 350g wheat flour 50g whole rye flour 11g salt 150g water 250g sourdough Directions Boil the potatoes Peel of the skin of the potatoes (let them cool down a bit) Stir all ingredients and knead them well. Let the dough rest for 5 hours in warm (25-30°C) conditions. Preheat the oven to 250°C.</description></item><item><title>Simple Creamy Pasta Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-pasta-cream-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 2 min 🍳 Cook time: 3 mins 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients Dairy liquid cream (10%+ fat recommended) Flour (Wheat flour recommended) Directions Add 1 teaspoon of flour into a saucepan. Pour ~60ml(2fl oz|1/4 cup) of cream into a saucepan. Stir and turn on maximum heat. Keep stirring until it becomes thick. If the sauce is too liquid, add more flour, if the sauce is too solid (like a uncooked pancake), add more cream.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough bread with seeds and grains</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-bread-with-seeds-and-grains/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-bread-with-seeds-and-grains/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 120 min Ingredients For the preparation 100g grain of choice (e.g. rye, spelt and wheat) 40g linseed 30g sesame 30g sunflower seeds 600g water For the bread 400g sourdough 200g water (25-35°C) 200g rye flour 300g wheat flour 20g sea salt 2tsp bread spice soaked seeds and grains Directions Preparations (the day before) Feed your sourdough starter for the next day.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough starter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-starter/</guid><description>This recipe contains instructions for sourdough starter needed for all sourdough breads. The starter can be done with either wheat flour or rye flour for rye breads. Prefer organic flours as they contain most wild yeasts.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min/day ⏲️ Wait time: 4 days Ingredients Wheat or rye flour Water Directions Day 1: mix 80g of water to 50g of flour and put a cover on the container loosely.</description></item><item><title>Southern Biscuits</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/southern-biscuits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/southern-biscuits/</guid><description>This is Southern (American) Style Biscuits.
Ingredients 2 cups AP flour 1 tsp white sugar 1 tbsp baking powder 1 tsp kosher salt 8 tbsp sweet butter 3/4 cup whole milk Directions Preheat oven to 425°F In a bowl combine dry ingredients Cube butter and add to dry ingredients Mix butter with hands or fork until a cornmeal consistency is achieved Add milk and mix until homogeneous Roll biscuits out to approx.</description></item><item><title>Tofu Stir Fry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-stir-fry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tofu-stir-fry/</guid><description>A vegetarian dish that is easy to make and very flavorful. Goes well with rice or noodles
Serves 3 to 5.
Cooking time: ~10 to 20 minutes
Ingredients One block of extra firm tofu Three eggs Vegetables per your choice, recommendations include: Sugar snap peas Chopped cabbage Sliced carrots Broccoli Cauliflower Soy or teriyaki sauce 2 tbsp minced garlic Coconut oil Directions (Optional) Deep freeze tofu at least 24 hours prior and then thaw.</description></item><item><title>Tuh'u</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuhu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuhu/</guid><description>Tuh&amp;rsquo;u (Akkadian for possibly &amp;ldquo;beetroot&amp;rdquo;) is an ancient Mesopotamian spring festival dish, a lamb stew of sorts, extracted by historians at Yale Babylonian Collection from tablets from Babylonia, ca. 1740 BC.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 60-90 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 450 g of lamb leg meat, diced 4 tbsp of sesame oil, olive oil, or rendered fat 350 mL of prepared water 350 mL of sour-tasting beer (e.</description></item><item><title>Apple strudel</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-strudel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-strudel/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients Puff pastry Apricot jam (about 300 g | 10 oz) 3 apples Ground cinnamon Breadcrumbs / crushed cookies Butter (optional) Powdered sugar (optional) Directions Peel and cut the apples in thin slices. Roll out the puff pastry with a rolling pin. Spread the jam over the puff pastry with a spoon. Arrange the apple slices over the jam.</description></item><item><title>Crab salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/crab-salad/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients Сrab meat (300 grams) Egg (3) Rice (50 grams) Corn (1 can) Cucumber (1) Carrot (1) Onion (1) Mayonnaise (100 grams) Directions Boil rice, eggs and carrot Chop crab meat and all other ingredients Combine and mix all ingredients Add mayonnaise Chill before serving</description></item><item><title>Pasta Alla Norma</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-alla-norma/</guid><description>A delicious Sicilian pasta dish, with Aubergines in a tomato sauce topped with fresh basil.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 aubergines (900g) 300g spaghetti 100ml olive oil 5 garlic cloves, minced 1 chilli (or 1 tsp of dried chilli flakes) 2 x 400g tinned chopped tomatoes 1 teaspoon dried oregano 1 teaspoon caster sugar Fresh basil Directions Preheat oven to 220c (fan), or gas mark 7.</description></item><item><title>Pâté Chinois (Quebec Style Shepherd’s Pie)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pate-chinois/</guid><description>This is the most traditional dish that every household eats in Quebec. As a kid, you would eat Pâté Chinois at least once a week, either at home or at the school&amp;rsquo;s cafeteria,. It is very similar to a Shepherd’s Pie, as it is divided in 3 layers of ingredients: meat, legumes and mashed potatoes. The literal translation of the name is something like chinese pie. You can search for the origin of the name on the internet, I&amp;rsquo;m not an history teacher.</description></item><item><title>Sausage Rolls</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sausage-rolls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sausage-rolls/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30-60 min Ingredients Eggs Puff pastry Pork meat / sausage meat Directions Place baking paper onto a tray Whisk eggs Lay out pastry, brush or pour egg whisk so it lightly covers the pastry Prepare sausage meat onto pastry Fold pastry around the meat, apply extra egg whisk to the &amp;lsquo;seal&amp;rsquo; where the pastry is folded together Bake until golden brown.</description></item><item><title>Zarangollo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zarangollo/</guid><description>Simple veggie starter/side dish from Murcia (Southeastern Spain)
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10-15 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 White onion 1 Eggplant Olive oil Egg (optional) Directions Cut onion in julienne (a third or half of an onion ring) Cut the eggplant in slices or chunks that can fit in a teaspoon Add oil to a pan (not a shallow one, wide and a bit deep is ideal if you have one) until it barely covers the vegetables Cook and stir in medium heat until they are tender, caramelized and translucent Kick up the heat to give them a crispy touch, but not for long (Optional) Turn off the heat and crack open an egg on top (Optional) Let the residual heat cook the egg.</description></item><item><title>Assam Tea</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/assam-tea/</guid><description>This is a simple Assam tea recipe.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 2 teaspoons of Assam Tea 150 ml of fresh water Sugar (Optional) Milk (Optional) Directions Add 150 ml of water to a small pan and bring it to boil. Then add 2 teaspoons of tea into it and reduce the heat to low. Strain the tea using a tea filter into a cup.</description></item><item><title>Baba's Feta Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/babas-feta-pasta/</guid><description>Greek Pasta Recipe with sauce made out of feta, stock, cream cheese and other ingredients. Uses mixed spice for special flavour, and is a great dinner or mid-day meal.
⏲️ Prep time: 15-30 min 🍳 Cook time: 25-30 min Ingredients Serves Around 3 People. You can scale up to 4 If you increase most quantities by +1/4.
Medium Sweet Onion (Finely Chopped) Virgin olive oil (not extra-virgin) White Sugar 3 Fresh Medium Garlic Cloves (Chopped Fine) 15-20 Kalamon/Kalamata Olives (Cut into thirds) Whole small courgette (Cut to small pieces) 6 Medium Mushrooms (Cut smallish and small stalk) 1/2 Broccli (Chopped small) 8-10 Finely sliced cherry tomatoes 1/2 Block of feta (Washed) 1 Chicken stock (Added to 3/4 Mug boiling water) Overfilled Teaspoon Mixed Spice 3/4 Bowls fusilli pasta Overfilled tablespoon Creme Cheese 1/3 Mug whole milk Directions Make sure to prepare &amp;amp; chop most ingredients before you start.</description></item><item><title>Baked Mostaccioli</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-mostaccioli/</guid><description>Pasta baked in dish with spicy sauce
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 bowls Ingredients 24 oz or 1 jar of Fradiavolo Sauce (Victoria) 1 box Mostaccioli Rigati or Penne Rigati (Ronzoni) ~8 oz shredded Mozzarella Cheese (Poly-O) I&amp;rsquo;ve found that pre-shredded cheese doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good as shredding it right before cooking. 2x 2 quart (8&amp;quot;) baking dishes or 1 large baking dish (see picture below) Directions Bring a pot to a boil and cook pasta for 6 minutes (very al dente).</description></item><item><title>Belgian pear syrup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/belgian-pear-syrup/</guid><description>A delicious syrup that can be eaten on bread and used in a multitude of recipes.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 hours Ingredients 7 pears (Quality doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter; you can argue that overripe pears are better because they have more sugar content.) 3 apples a small handful of dates, raisins, dried apricots or prunes (optional &amp;ndash; you can experiment with these; they can bring out some nice flavors.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast Wrap</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breakfast-wrap/</guid><description>The basic parts of a full English in a wrap. Inspired by McDonald&amp;rsquo;s breakfast wraps.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 (2 wraps) Ingredients 2 sausages 2 bacon rashers 1 egg 2 wraps milk ketchup (optional) Directions Begin by cutting the sausages in half and frying them ensuring that they&amp;rsquo;re cooked the whole way through. Next, fry the bacon.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Pasta Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-pasta-bake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 300-400g Pasta (Fusilli recommended but not essential) 50g Butter 100g Flour 200ml Milk 400g Cheddar Cheese 6 Rashers of bacon (optional) Directions Grate the cheese. Chop up the bacon into roughly 2cm x 2cm squares. Start cooking the pasta. Start melting the butter in another saucepan. Once melted, add flour and mix until the mixture forms a paste that does not stick to the sides.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Potato Bake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-potatoe-bake/</guid><description>Potatoes baked in a dish smothered with cheese, what&amp;rsquo;s not to love?
You will need a deep dish that is oven safe
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 30g+ Butter 250g Cheddar Cheese 275ml Milk 16g Flour 600g Potatoes As much bacon as you want to garnish Directions Preparation: Preheat to 180C Butter deep baking dish Peal and thinly slice potatoes Grate Cheese Sauce: Melt Butter in Pot Slowly add flour and stir constantly After 2 min or bubbly remove from heat Add milk slowly, stirring constantly Add 3/4 of the cheese Salt and Pepper to taste Assembly: Add a thin layer of potatoes to the dish Add a layer of cheese sauce Add bacon Repeat steps 1-3 of assembly until there are no more potatoes/sauce Add the remaining 1/4 cheese to the top Put in oven for 45 min.</description></item><item><title>Classic béchamel sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/classic-bechamel-sauce/</guid><description>Classic French sauce, base for a lot of dishes
⏲️ Prep time: 0m 🍳 Cook time: 15-20 min Ingredients 5 Teaspoons unsalted butter 5 Teaspoons flour 1 litre whole milk Salt to taste Pepper to taste Pinch of nutmeg Directions Put your butter in your pot and let is slowly melt on medium to low heat. Once the butter is fully melted add the flour and stir it in to make a roux.</description></item><item><title>Francesinha</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/francesinha/</guid><description>Francesinha is a traditional dish from the city of Porto. The francesinha in its special sandwich variation consists of linguiça, ham, cold meat and beef steak, covered with melted cheese.
Ingredients Based Ingredients bread linguiça (type of Portuguese sausage) ham Portuguese cheese beef meat Sauce Ingredients blonde beer fried tomato sauce port wine beef broth salted butter onion minced garlic cornstarch olive oil piripiri (Portuguese chili) Directions Directions for the sauce In a big saucepan, heat the olive oil and add the garlic and the onions.</description></item><item><title>French Toast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-toast/</guid><description>This recipe results in five slices of easy to make french toast.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 2 Eggs 1/2 Cup of milk (1/4 for a more solid consistency) 5 Slices of bread Maple Syrup (Optional) Butter Directions Butter up a frying pan and set it on the burner with low-medium heat.(May need to add more butter in-between slices) Take your two eggs and crack them into a bowl together.</description></item><item><title>Greek Easter Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/greek-easter-cookies/</guid><description>A very simple, delicious, and traditional greek recipe for easter cookies.
⏲️ Prep time: 30-45 min 🍳 Cook time: 18-22 min 🍽️ Servings: Five-dozen individual cookies Ingredients 1 lb of unsalted butter 3 cups of sugar 10 eggs 6 tsps baking powder 2 tsps baker’s ammonium 1 pinch of baking soda 2 tsp powder vanilla Zest of 3 oranges Zest of 2 lemons 1/2 cup orange juice 1 cup warmed milk 1 egg yolk whisked to brush cookies Enough flour to make a soft pliable dough (about 9 cups or a bit more) Directions Cream butter and sugar together until fluffy.</description></item><item><title>Kalderetang Manok</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kalderetang-manok/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kalderetang-manok/</guid><description>Classic Filipino dish, great paired with freshly cooked rice and a bottle of Coca Cola.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min. 🍳 Cook time: 1 hr. 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 1 lb of chicken 2 chopped potatoes 2 chopped carrots 1 chopped onion 2 chopped cloves of garlic 1 chopped tomato (optional) 3 cups of water Tomato sauce Chopped bell pepper Dried peas Liver spread Fish sauce Grated cheese Directions Sauté onions, garlic and (optional) tomato, in a pan of olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Kvass</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/kvass/</guid><description>Kvass is a Slavic fermented beverage which is both simple to make and rich in flavour.
⏲️ Prep time: ~30 min ⌛ Fermentation time: ~1 week Ingredients 100 g of raisins 100 g of sugar 3 slices of black bread (e.g. pumpernickel bread, rye bread) 1-2 lemons 1 pkg (7 g) of active dry yeast Optional: A handful of coffee beans Non-citrus fruits (e.g. plums, apples, kiwi) Directions Bring 1 L of water in a pot to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Biriyani</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lamb-biriyani/</guid><description>This recipe makes an Southern Indian (Tamil) style Lamb biriyani that has been adapted to a more western audience (aka a bit less spicy) and can be made with either Lamb or Mutton. Best served with a sauce such as an onion raitha.
A plated rendering of the dish, made with Mutton. Makes a really hearty ,meaty and delicious dish. The dishes uses a rice to meat ratio of 2:3. PS: the biriyani tastes better the longer it&amp;rsquo;s allowed to soak in it&amp;rsquo;s flavour after cooking.</description></item><item><title>Lasagna</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lasagna/</guid><description>A nice recipe for amazing fully home-made lasagna.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 hour 🍳 Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients Parmesan cheese Emental cheese (optional) Dry mozzarella cheese Fresh Bolognese sauce or about 1 litre worth of store-bought sauce Béchamel sauce or ricotta lasagna filling Lasagna pasta sheets Directions Prepare the bolognese or jared pasta sauce. When the sauce is almost done cooking prepare your béchamel or ricotta filling.</description></item><item><title>Loaded Mexican Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/loaded-mexican-rice/</guid><description>A tex-mex style mexican rice with beans and meat. Adding the beans and meat take it from a side dish to good good burrito filling. :x
Ingredients 5 serving
1 Cup uncooked long grain white rice 1/2 Cup frozen peas 1/2 Cup frozen corn 2 Caned adobo chilies chopped 5 Tbsp tomato paste 1 Can of black or pinto beans 1/2 Cup ground meat (optional) 1/4 Onion diced (optional) Directions Cook rice per manufactures instructions.</description></item><item><title>Mushroom risotto</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/mushroom-risotto/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20-30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Olive oil 1 shallot 4 cloves of garlic 300g button or crimini mushrooms 400g risotto rice (Arborio, Carnaroli or Vialone Nano) 1/2 cup white wine (optional) Mushroom or chicken stock Butter Grated Pecorino or Parmesan cheese Directions Finely mince the shallot and garlic and slice the mushrooms into large pieces. Heat a pan with some olive oil on medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Nashville Chicken Sandwich</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/nashville-chicken/</guid><description>If you love spicy foods and chicken then this Nashville Hot Chicken sandwich recipe is just for you. It takes some time with prepping and process but when you take that first bite all the effort will be worth it. It’s unlike any other fried chicken recipe that includes double frying your chicken and using the same cooking oil from your fry as a sauce for the Nashville Hot Chicken spice.</description></item><item><title>No-knead Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-bread/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 13 h 🍳 Cook time: 50 m 🍽️ Servings: 8-12 slices Ingredients 3 c flour 1 tsp salt 1/4 tsp instant yeast or 1.25/4 tsp active dry yeast 1 1/2 cups warm water Oven-safe pan Directions Mix the dry ingredients then add the hot water. It should come out as a firm dough. Leave the dough at room temperature for 12 hours. You can then keep the dough in the fridge for up to 48 hours before cooking.</description></item><item><title>No-knead pizza dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/no-knead-pizza-dough/</guid><description>Perfect for pan pizza in an 11 inch iron skillet.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 7-24 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 pizza Ingredients 200g flour 2g instant yeast (dry) 5g salt 5g olive oil 140g luke warm water Directions Mix dry ingredients in a bowl. Mix in olive oil and water. No need for hands or kneading! Cover bowl air tight, and let it sit in room temperature for at least 7 hours, and up to 24 hours.</description></item><item><title>Onion Raitha (Indian Tzatziki)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/onion-raitha/</guid><description>Raitha is an yogurt-based Indian style sauce that goes great with rice dishes such as Pilau and Biriyani. It&amp;rsquo;s quite similar to a greek Tzatziki and is quick and quite easy to make. It&amp;rsquo;s great especially with super spicy indian dishes as it provides as a sweet and cooling effect.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500 gm of Greek Yogurt One Red onion 50 gm of Cucumber Sprigs of Mint Dash of Honey Hint of Chilli Powder (Spicy option)/ Hint of sugar (Sweet option) Directions Chop the onion into tiny cubes (0.</description></item><item><title>Pan pizza</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-pizza/</guid><description>Pan pizza gives a thick and crispy crust 🍕. For this recipe, start early with the dough, preferably the night before. It takes a lot of time, but little effort and gives a fantastic result.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hours Ingredients no-knead pizza dough pizza sauce cheese olive oil pepperoni (optional) mushrooms (optional) pineapple (optional) &amp;hellip;really whatever you like (optional) Directions Preheat oven to max temp.</description></item><item><title>Pizza sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 0.5-2 hours Ingredients 400g canned tomatoes, preferebly skinned and whole 150g tomato puré 1 medium sized onion olive oil garlic oregano chili pepper (optional) Directions Dice onion and fry in olive oil on medium heat. Add chopped garlic and chili pepper (optional) for some minutes. Mix in tomato puré, salt, pepper, and oregano. Cook until puré gets oily.</description></item><item><title>Savory Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/savory-squash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/savory-squash/</guid><description>Prep Time: 5 mins Cook Time: 1 Hour Ingredients 1 Butternut Squash 1/2 Stick of butter Salt, to taste St. Augur Blue Cheese Chives Directions Peel Butternut squash and discard both ends. Cut in half lengthwise, scoop and discard seeds. Cut in half lengthwise again. Place face down on greased baking sheet. Rotate to roast the other face after 20 minutes, Check at 45 mins with a toothpick for softness.</description></item><item><title>Schinkenfleckerl überbacken, Viennese Mac'n'Cheese</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/schinkenfleckerl-gratinated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/schinkenfleckerl-gratinated/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 25 min 🍳 Cook time: 120 min 🍽️ Servings: 8-12 This is a recipe for a typical Austrian carb and protein bomber. This is traditionally made with ham or smoked rolled roast. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 3 or 4 days.
Serve topped with cheese on top of salad (with Mustard, Jam, Salt, 1 Vinegar, 4 Oil-Vinegrette)</description></item><item><title>Simple Chicken Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-chicken-curry/</guid><description>An easy chicken curry recipe which scales very well (double it, triple it, etc.). Best served with rice.
Servings: 3-4
Ingredients Spices
1 ½ tsp Coriander 1 tsp Cumin ½ tsp Turmeric ½ tsp Ground Fennel Seeds ½ tsp Cinnamon ½ tsp Black Pepper ½ tsp Ginger ¼ tsp Mustard ¼ tsp Ground Cloves Sriracha Sauce (optional) Main Ingredients
¼ cup (½ stick) Butter 1 large Onion 4 cloves Garlic 2-3 cups Chicken Broth 2-3 cups Crushed or Pureed Tomatoes 1 ½ lbs Boneless Skinless Chicken Breasts Directions Mince the garlic and dice the onion.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Pork Carnitas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-carnitas/</guid><description>This recipe makes a lot and is super easy. A whole roast usually makes enough for a few meals (depending on how many people will be eating it). Leftovers can be refrigerated for 4-5 days.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 8 hr 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 10-11 Ingredients 2 ½ lbs. boneless pork shoulder 6 cloves of garlic, cut into slivers 1 ½ teaspoons cumin ½ teaspoon sazon ¼ teaspoon dry oregano ¾ cup low sodium chicken broth 2-3 chipotle peppers in adobo sauce 2 bay leaves ¼ teaspoon dry adobo seasoning Directions Season pork with kosher salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Sopa de Lentejas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lentejas/</guid><description>Traditional-spanish dish. Typical spanish!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 1 carrot, chopped 1 green bell pepper, chopped 4 garlic cloves, minced 1 large onion, chopped 1 cup dry brown lentils, soaked overnight and drained 2 plum tomatoes, chopped 2 cups water, or as needed 1 bay leaf 1 tbsp extra-virgin olive oil 1/2 tsp of paprika 1/4 spicy chorizo (optional) Directions Heat olive oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough Table Loaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-loaf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sourdough-loaf/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve never made your own sourdough bread, it can be intimidating! But I believe it is absolutely worth the time and effort. You can look up videos to explain some of the methods listed, such as the stretch and fold, or different ways to shape your loaf. Fermenting grains has been a tradition of home cooking for millennia, and an art only lost in recent years. Fermenting grains has numerous health benefits, is much easier to digest, and even contains natural preservatives.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti aglio e olio</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aglio-e-olio/</guid><description>Aglio e olio, pasta with garlic and olive oil, is one of the simplest yet greatest pasta dishes of all time. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, easy, and uses a lot of basic pantry ingredients which makes this a convenient weeknight meal.
🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 pound (500g) spaghetti (or similarly shaped pasta) 1/2 cup (110g) extra virgin olive oil 5-6 cloves of garlic 1/4 tsp red pepper flakes A bunch of fresh parsley Directions Heat a large skillet on medium-high heat, start cooking the pasta.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti alla puttanesca</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-alla-puttanesca/</guid><description>author: postbellum Easy and delicious italian dish. Spaghetti alla puttanesca entice you for the savory sauce that surrounds them: peeled tomatoes, capers, &amp;ldquo;Gaeta&amp;rdquo; olives, and anchovy fillets give these spaghetti a unique taste.
⏲️Prep time: ~18 min 🍳 Cook time: 6-7 min 🍽️Servings: 4 Ingredients Pot of water 320g italian spaghetti 2 garlic cloves 10g salted capers 25g anchovies in oil 800g peeled tomatoes &amp;ldquo;sugo&amp;rdquo; 1 bunch of parsley 100g Gaeta olives 2 chopped chillies A pinch of salt Directions Wash capers from salt, then cut them Pit and crush Gaeta olives Wash and chop the bunch of parsley Start cooking the pasta until al dente.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Tortilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spanish-tortilla/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 8 free-range eggs 1 kg of potatoes 1 white onion Extra virgin olive oil Directions Peel, rinse and dry the potatoes. Cut the potatoes into thin slices. Put in a bowl, add salt to taste and stir. Put a nonstick frying pan on the fire and add enough olive oil to fry all the potato slices.</description></item><item><title>Stoemp</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoemp/</guid><description>Mashed potatoes in Belgian style
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 500g potatoes 300g carrots 100g bacon 50g butter 100ml heavy cream 1/2 teaspoon ground nutmeg Directions Cut bacon into bits. Sauté bacon until well colored. Peel and dice into small chunks potatoes, peel and slice carrots. Boil for 20-25 minutes potatoes and carrots in salted water. Drain vegetables and mash with a fork, so that the texture remains slightly chunky.</description></item><item><title>Stoofvlees</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stoofvlees/</guid><description>This is a traditional belgian stew made with cheap, though beef cuts, beer and onions. Traditionally eaten with fries and chicory salad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 to 4 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Large onions 1 tablespoon butter 1kg chuck roast, cut in bite-sized pieces 2 33cl bottles of brown beer 2 bayleaves 2 twigs of thyme 1 clove (spice) 2 tablespoons of belgian apple/pear syrup (optional, ill write up a recipe for this soon) 2 teaspoons of vinegar 1 slice of bread mustard Directions Peel the onions and cut them into medium sized pieces, don&amp;rsquo;t cut the onion too small.</description></item><item><title>Swedish Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/swedish-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/swedish-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3 Eggs, beaten 1 tsp Salt 1 tbsp Sugar 1 cup Flour 1 - 2/3 cups Milk 6-8 tbsp Butter Directions At medium/low heat begin melting the butter, and continue with beating eggs in large bowl, add salt, sugar, milk, flour and mix. Add melted butter while stirring batter. Use about 1/2 cup batter on griddle and tilt until spread evenly over griddle surface.</description></item><item><title>Chicharrones</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicharrones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicharrones/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork Butt with fat Adobo Goya all purpose Cumin Goya Naranja juice Corn oil (preferred) Directions Cut pork butt to around bite sized pieces with fat attached for frying and flavor. Add Adobo Goya and spread evenly throughout the pork Add Black pepper 1 ml Add Cumin 1 ml Add Salt 5 ml Add Goya Naranja 15 ml Rub all of it to spread the spices along the meat Have a colander to put the Chicharonnes in after having fried it and have another pot on the bottom that has some paper inside for oil Put it in deep dish skillet around Medium (3-4) heat cover with lid for around 30-35 mins till you see it&amp;rsquo;s cooked, turning to make sure everything is cooking evenly After it dries up at around 30-35 mins put the temperature to High (6-7) without the lid Put some oil to make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stick too much Use spoon to spin/stir and fry until a golden brown Take out the Chicharonnes and put into the colander.</description></item><item><title>Bloody Mary Mix</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bloody-mary-mix/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 1 (46 fluid ounce) bottle tomato-vegetable juice cocktail 1 fruit, without seeds lemons, juiced 1 teaspoon brown sugar 1 tablespoon steak sauce 1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce 1 teaspoon prepared horseradish 1 teaspoon hot pepper sauce 1/2 teaspoon celery salt Directions In a large pitcher, combine juice cocktail, lemon juice and brown sugar.</description></item><item><title>Chimichanga</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chimichanga/</guid><description>Essentially, just a fried burrito. Use whatever your favorite filling is.
⏲️ Prep time: 120min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Servings: 4 Ingredients taco-meat 1 Onion Diced Tomatoes 1 Bell Pepper Burrito sized tortilla Plain Greek Yogurt or Sour Cream Any other vegetables you want Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers, tomatoes, and onions and saute Add in meat. Season and cook until browned or fully cooked through Warm your tortilla and place small layer of yogurt, cheese, and filling on the bottom half of the tortilla Wrap by folding bottom over filling, folding sides in, and then rolling.</description></item><item><title>Cinque Pi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cinque-pi/</guid><description>This is a nice simple dish made up of five ingredients: panna, pomodori, parmigiano, pepe, e prezzemolo
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients pasta: 800g | 1 1/2 lb Cream: 4dl | 1 1/2 cups Tomato paste 2 TS Parmigiano (grated) Parsley Directions Start cooking the pasta. Mix the cream with the tomato paste and bring to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Glühwein - mulled wine</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gluehwein/</guid><description>A recipe for Glühwein/mulled wine a beverage you can find at almost every European christmas market. This recipe is my favorite one - optimized for flavor rather than alcohol content (it still kicks in).
🍽️ Servings:1-4 Ingredients for 1 liter of Glühwein
300 ml Cassis-Juice (Johannesbeer), if you can&amp;rsquo;t find it you can replace it with another juice, I did it e.g. with cranberry pomegranate juice 1 bottle 700ml red wine (I prefer Primitivo/Zinfandel), don&amp;rsquo;t buy a cheap cooking wine, you want to drink it :) 50 g Sugar 25 g Raisins 1 orange 1 cinamon bark 1 spoon ginger powder (or a bit of fresh ginger) 1 spoon cloves 5 star anise if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the spices you can also just throw in sweet cinamon tea bags instead (or similar), they contain most spices - I took 6 teabags for 1 litre Directions cut the orange in nice looking pieces (since they are mainly decoration) throw everything in a pot warm up (don&amp;rsquo;t boil) enjoy</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties-all-beef/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 4 patties
Ingredients 1 lb ground beef, 20% or more fat ratio Onion, chopped or powder (optional) Garlic, chopped or powder (optional) Directions Form patties with the beef. Use high-fat ground beef, you won&amp;rsquo;t need oil. Place into a pan, pre-heated or otherwise, at medium/med-high temperature. Add salt, pepper, and optional seasonings. Cook until done, flipping occasionally to prevent burning.</description></item><item><title>Irish Coffee</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/irish-coffee/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish cream liqueur 1 (1.5 fluid ounce) jigger Irish whiskey 1 cup hot brewed coffee 1 tablespoon whipped cream 1 dash ground nutmeg Directions In a coffee mug, combine Irish cream and Irish whiskey. Fill mug with coffee. Top with a dab of whipped cream and a dash of nutmeg.</description></item><item><title>Orange Glorious</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/orange-glorious/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate 1 cup milk 1 cup water 1/2 cup white sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 12 cubes ice Directions In a blender, combine orange juice concentrate, milk, water, sugar and vanilla. Add ice cubes and blend until smooth. Pour into glasses and serve.</description></item><item><title>Pozharskiye Cutlets</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pozharskiye-cutlets/</guid><description>Famous Russian cutlet recipe, favoured by Nicholas I. Despite what seems to be a massive amount of butter required, they&amp;rsquo;re rather light, yet creamy.
Ingredients Chicken mince Butter (originally, 1 part butter per 2 parts chicken; 1/4 works perfectly fine) Eggs (~1 egg per 500g chicken, plus 3-5 for the breading) A couple white bread loaves (store-bought breadcrumbs also suffice, but require more eggs) Spices/salt (optional, recommended) Non-lard based, non-chunky sauce (optional) Onions (optional) Directions Prepare 2 medium-sized and 1 extra large bowl, a few plates and a regular frying pan.</description></item><item><title>Russian 1000 Islands Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/russian-1000-islands-sauce/</guid><description>A tasty sauce that goes well with salads or rice. Recipe taken from a Russian monastery.
Ingredients Ketchup (Sir Kensington&amp;rsquo;s recommended) Mayonnaise Horseradish Worchestershire sauce Paprika Dijon mustard Onion powder Pickle relish (optional) Directions Put ingredients into bowl or cup. Mix together thoroughly.</description></item><item><title>Salsa Verde</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa-verde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/salsa-verde/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound (450g) tomatillos, husks removed 1 clove garlic 2 jalapeño or serrano chilies 1/2 cup (26g) chopped onion 3 Tbsp (40ml) oil cilantro Directions Place tomatillos, garlic, and chilies in a medium saucepan and cover with water. Simmer until tomatillos turn pale green, about 10 minutes. Transfer tomatillos, garlic, and chilies into a blender or food processor. Add the onion and cilantro. Puree until smooth, then salt to taste, usually a teaspoon (6g) will suffice.</description></item><item><title>Danish Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/danish-pancake/</guid><description>Danish Pancake recipe
Ingredients 375g wheat flour a little bit of salt (1/3 of a teaspoon) 1 ½ tablespoon sugar 9 dl milk 4 eggs Directions Put all the ingredients in a bowl and stir until it&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up. Preheat a pan with butter or margarine. Turn when one side starts turning brown. They are done when both sides start turning brown. Add Butter or Margarine when needed.</description></item><item><title>Lenten Chili</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-chili/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lenten-chili/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 large onion, chopped 3 cloves garlic, minced 4 15oz cans of kidney beans (or 6 cups cooked beans) 1 29oz large can tomato sauce (or 4 cups fresh tomato sauce) 1 15oz can diced tomatoes (or 1 large diced tomato with skin removed) 1/2 can of sweet corn 1 cup cooked white or brown rice 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp smoked paprika 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp onion powder 1 tbsp chili powder 1 tbsp crushed red pepper 2-3 tbsp olive oil Directions Chop the large onion and mince the garlic cloves.</description></item><item><title>Potato Leek Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-leek-soup/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 3 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 large leeks 1 quart chicken or veggie stock 11 ounces peeled and sliced waxy potatoes 1 bay leaf ¾ cup heavy cream white pepper (optional) ½ teaspoon ground nutmeg (optional) ½ tablespoon dill weed Directions Chop the white to light-green part of the leek into moderately sized pieces and discard the dark-green ends.</description></item><item><title>Schnitzel</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/schnitzel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/schnitzel/</guid><description>Original Austrian breaded meat, pan-fried in butter.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 6 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 veal cutlets (1 ~ 150g) 2 eggs 1 lemon 100g flour 150g bread crumbs 100g butter (or even better clarified butter) Directions Prepare 3 bowls. (One with flour, one with beaten eggs, one with bread crumbs seasoned with salt and paprika) Wash the veal and gently dry it with kitchen roll.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp and Grits</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-grits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/shrimp-and-grits/</guid><description>This recipe is derived from Smokin' &amp;amp; Grillin' wit AB &amp;ndash; youtube
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 2-3 Ingredients 2 lbs Large/Jumbo Shrimp 6 Slices of Bacon 1 cup Un-Cooked Grits 3 cups Chicken Broth 2 cups Shredded Cheddar Cheese 3 tbsp Butter 3 tbsp Chopped Fresh Parsley 1 tbsp Creole / Cajun seasoning 2 Cloves of Garlic, minced 2 tsp Worcestershire Sauce 1 tbsp Lemon Juice Directions Add bacon to hot pan.</description></item><item><title>Baked Salmon</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-salmon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/baked-salmon/</guid><description>Simple method for making a good serving of salmon. Goes well with just about anything.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 19 min Ingredients Salmon Steaks Red Pepper Flakes Lemon Juice Butter Cooking oil / spray Aluminum Foil Directions Season salmon with salt, black pepper, and red pepper to taste. Spray or rub in cooking oil on aluminum foil and place on cookie sheet or in baking pan.</description></item><item><title>Cannellini Bean Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cannellini-bean-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1 can Cannellini beans, drained and rinsed 2 tbsp minced garlic 1/2 onion 1 tsp smoked paprika 1/2 tsp ground cumin 1 15 oz can diced tomatoes 1 tbsp parsley flakes Prosciutto Arugula Directions Sauté garlic and onions in olive oil until onions are translucent. Add diced tomatoes, seasonings, and salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Cooked Chickpeas</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cooked-chickpeas/</guid><description>Easy recipe for cooked chickpeas. Can be add to salads, rice, or almost anything else.
⏲️ Prep time: 1 min 🍳 Cook time: 15 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 can chickpeas / garbanzo beans, drained 1 tbsp olive oil 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp cumin 1 tsp paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper Directions Heat oil in pan. Add chickpeas and seasonings. Cook over medium-high heat for 10-15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Dominican Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dominican-spaghetti/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 1 box Spaghetti 1 Onion minced 1 Green Pepper minced 2 Garlic cloves minced 1 tbsp Chicken Bouillon Cube or Adobo 1 tbsp sazón 1 tbsp Tomato Paste 1 cup Tomato Sauce 1 tbsp Butter ¼ cup Evaporated Milk 2 tbsp Green Olives 1 tsp Sugar 1 cup Starchy Pasta Water Directions Boil spaghetti.</description></item><item><title>Fajita Seasoning</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fajita-seasoning/</guid><description>Simple seasoning mix similar to Old El Paso. Can be used for any Mexican dishes or plain meats.
Ingredients 1/2 tsp Garlic Powder 1/2 tsp Onion Powder 1/2 tsp Paprika 1/2 tsp Smoked Paprika 1/2 tsp Ground Cumin 1/2 tsp Ground Coriander 1/2 tsp Oregano 1/2 tsp Cayenne Pepper 1 tsp Salt 1 tsp Brown Sugar 1.5 tsp Chili Powder Directions Mix seasonings in a bowl. Adjust amounts depending on how much is needed.</description></item><item><title>Pilaf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pilaf/</guid><description>Popular central asian and middle eastern dish. High in nutrition, designed to be prepared and eaten communally.
Ingredients 150ml cooking oil 1kg long grain rice 1.5kg meat (lamb or any other kind of meat) 500g onions 500g carrots 2 tbsp salt 5 cloves of garlic raisins, cardamom, paprika, coriander, cinnamon, cumin, turmeric (all optional) Directions Put the cooking oil in a cauldron and heat it until the oil is boiling, add a head of onion until it is black, then throw it out.</description></item><item><title>Aljotta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aljotta/</guid><description>Aljotta (&amp;ldquo;jo&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;Yo!&amp;quot;) is a traditional Maltese light fish soup with roots in french bouillabaisse and similarly refers to the method of serving the fish that are cooked in it. The most appropriate fish to use for both the stock and the accompanying meal are &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; white fish that don&amp;rsquo;t turn the broth cloudy, ideally stargazers, monkfish, red gurnard, and moray eels but also hake, mullets, cod and haddock.</description></item><item><title>Arroz Chaufa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/arroz-chaufa/</guid><description>Peruvian-chinese dish. Easy to cook just add and mix everything.
⏲️ Prep time: 40 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Rice Salt Bell Pepper Chicken Eggs Soy Sauce Welsh Onion Directions Cut the chicken into pieces and fry it. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt. Cook scrambled eggs. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the salt. Cook the rice. If it is yesterday&amp;rsquo;s rice better, preferably without salt.</description></item><item><title>Bolinhos de Coco</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bolinhos-de-coco/</guid><description>This is a Portuguese dish that translates to &amp;ldquo;coconut cupcakes,&amp;rdquo; though there are probably lots of equivalent dishes from other cultures. Its simplicity and short preparation time make it perfect for a snack or dessert.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min Ingredients 300 g coconut 150 g sugar 3 egg yolks 1 whole egg Powdered sugar (optional) Directions Mix the non-optional ingredients in a medium bowl.</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiro</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/brigadeiro/</guid><description>A very traditional Brazilian dessert that is present in every Brazilian birthday party! Delicious and super easy to make.
Ingredients One can of condensed milk. Three or four spoons of chocolate powder or cocoa powder. One spoon of butter (Actual butter and preferably unsalted. No margarine!) Sprinkles (Optional) Directions Add all ingredients into a pan. Put it under low heat and stir it (preferably with a wooden spoon) until it stops sticking to the bottom of the pan.</description></item><item><title>Chicken in Red Wine Vinegar Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-in-red-wine-vinegar-sauce/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 6 Ingredients 3 tablespoons/~44 milliliters extra-virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon/~14 grams unsalted butter 1 whole chicken, cut into 10 pieces (alternatively, use breasts or legs) 4 shallots, finely chopped 1 cup/720 milliliters red wine vinegar 1 cup/240 milliliters crème fraîche or heavy cream Finely chopped parsley (optional) Directions Rub each piece of chicken in salt and pepper mixture.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-soup/</guid><description>Hearty soup that is adaptable to customizing to your desired vegetables or other additions
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: Ingredients 2 chicken breasts 1 Onion 2 carrots 2 celery stalks 32 oz / 950ml Chicken Stock or Broth Pasta (Optional) Directions Cook chicken breasts, shred, and set aside in a bowl. Cut up carrots and celery, place in pot and saute.</description></item><item><title>Coconut Oil Coffee</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coconut-oil-coffee/</guid><description> 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 1 cup hot coffee 1 tbsp coconut oil 1 tbsp unsalted butter Directions Blend coffee, coconut oil, and butter together in a blender until oil and butter are melted and coffee is frothy.</description></item><item><title>Lemon juice salad dressing</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lemon-juice-salad-dressing/</guid><description>A dressing that goes well on lettuce or any other mixed greens.
Ingredients Lemon juice from half a lemon Tablespoon of olive oil Clove of garlic Directions Combine lemon juice and oil in small bowl. Add salt and pepper to taste. Add the garlic, pressed or finely minced. Mix well before adding to salad.</description></item><item><title>Party Mimosa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/party-mimosa/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 (12 ounce) can apricot-mango nectar 1 (12 ounce) can pineapple juice 1 (6 ounce) can frozen orange juice concentrate, thawed and undiluted 1 (750 milliliter) bottle cold champagne 3/4 cup cold water Directions Stir together apricot nectar, pineapple juice, water, and orange juice concentrate in a large pitcher until combined. Pour in bottle of sparkling wine just before serving.</description></item><item><title>Pickled Red Onions</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pickled-onions/</guid><description>A good way to use up older red onions and goes great with just about anything.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings Varies Ingredients Red Onions Vinegar Water Directions Cut onion in half and slice root to stem and place in a jar Mix equal parts of water and vinegar in a pot and bring to a boil. Add salt to taste As soon as it begins to boil, turn off and pour the mix into the jar and allow to cool.</description></item><item><title>Red Sauce (Ragu all'Italiana)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/red-sauce/</guid><description>My great-grandma&amp;rsquo;s red sauce. All purpose: good for pastas, lasagnas, subs, etc.
⏲️ Prep time: 12 mins 🍳 Cook time: Simmer all day 🍽️ Servings: 7 Ingredients 1/3 lb salt pork 2 lb chuck roast 3 Cloves of garlic Crushed hot red pepper Sweet onion Large carrot 2 Bay leaves 2 tbsp. Olive oil (she used mazola oil) 12 oz. Can tomato paste 29 oz. Diced tomatoes 29 oz.</description></item><item><title>Stir Fried Chicken with an Orange Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stir-fried-chicken-with-an-orange-sauce/</guid><description>I could have called this Orange Chicken but I feel like some people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t classify my recipe that way.
Ingredients Chicken (a pound or two) Oranges An Onion Two Red Bell Peppers Soy Sauce Honey Butter Flour Directions Chop your onion and red bell peppers into small bits and throw them in a large frying pan to cook with a pat of butter, stirring occasionally. Chop your chicken into small bite sized pieces, add them to your pan once your onions begin to become translucent.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli with Ginger and Garlic Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ginger-garlic-broccoli/</guid><description>Asian inspired broccoli dish with tasty sauce. Sauce can be used for all kinds of Asian inspired sauted vegetables.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients 1-2 Broccoli (fresh best, frozen works too) Minced garlic (1 tablespoon) Minced ginger (1 tablespoon) Sherry or regular white wine (you cook with what you drink with!) (1 tablespoon) Soy sauce (1-2 tablespoon) Directions Cut broccoli into little flourettes (hold the broccoli upside down and cut around the stem with a pairing knife) Fill your pan (or wok) around half inch (1.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken Masala Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</guid><description>Butter chicken Masala is one of India&amp;rsquo;s most popular chicken recipes, a mild curry with a tomato-onion-cream base and boneless chicken pieces cooked in it to perfection.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 Ingredients Boneless Chicken 1/2lb, cubed Butter Melted 2 tbsp Onions 2 medium-sized, minced Tomato 2 medium-sized, pureed Oil 2 tbsp Lemon juice 1 tbsp Garlic cloves 3, minced/crushed Ginger 1tbsp, minced/paste Garam Masala/Chicken Masala 1 tbsp Cream 4tbsp (or cashew paste) Chilli Powder 1 tbsp Turmeric powder 1/4 tbsp Crushed fenugreek leaves 1/4 tbsp 1 small bunch of coriander leaves / cilantro, for ganish Directions In a bowl, mix chicken with salt, pepper, 1/2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1/2 tbsp chili powder, turmeric powder, and lemon juice for the chicken marinade; let marinate for an hour.</description></item><item><title>Fish Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fish-curry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fish-curry/</guid><description>Best served with white rice
🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:5 Ingredients 3T neutral oil 1 onion 1 red onion 2 cloves of garlic 4cm ginger 1 red pepper 1t curry powder 250g green beans 4 tomatoes 200ml fish broth 200ml coconut milk 400g fish fillet (white fish) Directions Boil green beans for 10 minutes Cut onions, tomato, garlic and fish. Heat oil on a wok and sauté the onion and garlic Add beans, tomato, broth and spices and boil for 6 minutes Add coconut milk, fish and pepper (whole) and boil for an additional 6 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Frittata</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/frittata/</guid><description>Very filling egg dish that&amp;rsquo;s easy, fast, and can be eaten at any meal. Any other types of vegetables can be added, this is just what I use the most
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings:4-6 Ingredients 4-6 Eggs 1/2 Onion 1 Bell Pepper 2 Tbsp Heavy Cream Thinly sliced meat (prosciutto, shaved chicken, sandwich steak, etc.) (Optional) Shredded cheese of choice (Optional) Directions Dice peppers and onions and saute in an oven safe pan at medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Naan Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</guid><description>A curry serves best with naan that is unleavened bread. Traditionally made in ‘Tandoor or clay oven' but at home, we will be making it in the oven and/or on the stovetop. Naan is not eaten solely but acts as assortments with meat, veggies, or egg items.
⏲️ Prep time: 90 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients All-purpose flour 3 cups Active dry yeast 1 tbsp Sugar 2 tbsp Warm Milk 1 cup Butter melted 2 tbsp Oil - little to grease Directions Put the yeast and sugar to warm milk in a large mixing bowl and stir well.</description></item><item><title>Shrimp and Sausage Gumbo</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gumbo-shrimp-and-sausage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gumbo-shrimp-and-sausage/</guid><description>This recipe is a simplified version of AB&amp;rsquo;s Seafood Gumbo &amp;ndash; youtube
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 130 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 2-3 lbs Shrimp 2 lbs Andouille Sausage 2 (32 oz) Chicken Broth 1 cup olive oil 1 cup All Purpose Flour 1 cup finely chopped Yellow Onion 1 cup finely chopped Green Pepper 1 cup finely chopped Celery 2 tbsp minced Garlic 1 tbsp Worcestershire Sauce 1 tbsp Cajun or Creole Seasoning (Creole Kick) 1 12 oz.</description></item><item><title>Simple Tuna Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-salad/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍽️ Servings: 3 Ingredients 1 (7 oz) can white tuna, drained 6 tablespoons mayonnaise 1 tablespoons sweet pickle relish A pinch of garlic powder (optional) 2 tablespoons white vinegar or lemon juice (optional) 1 cup shredded cheese (optional) 1 chopped hard-boiled egg (optional) Directions In a medium bowl, stir together tuna, mayonnaise, and relish. Add optional ingredients like vinegar, cheese or hard-boiled eggs if wanted.</description></item><item><title>Spatchcock Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spatchcock-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 (3 1/2) pound whole chickens, wingtips removed 2 teaspoons salt 1 teaspoon dried tarragon 1 teaspoon paprika 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 4 teaspoons olive oil 2 lemons, thinly sliced and seeded Directions Preheat oven to 450 degrees F (230 degrees C). Line a large rimmed baking sheet with foil. Place chicken, breast side down, on a work surface. Starting at the tail end, cut along both sides of backbone with kitchen shears.</description></item><item><title>Tomato and Grilled Bell Pepper soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-and-grilled-paprika-soup/</guid><description>🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️Servings:12 Can be prepared the night before and kept frozen for a week or two.
Ingredients 10 tomatoes 2 red bell peppers 2 onions 1 clove of garlic 1L stock or broth ¾t Cayenne pepper 1t paprika powder 3t bruschetta herbs 1t oregano 1t giner syrup 2T olive oil 2T heavy cream Directions Halve, deseed and grill the bell peppers in an oven or on a grill.</description></item><item><title>Zopf</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/zopf/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 30 min (plus one hour rising) 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 1kg white wheat flour ½L milk 125g butter 14g dry yeast 1½T salt 1 egg Directions Cut or tear up butter and put in skillet with milk on low heat (This is so the ingredients are not too clod, temperature should not exceed 31 C). Put the flour in a large bow with the yeast, salt, milk and butter.</description></item><item><title>Breton Crêpes (Breton Galettes)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/breton-crepes/</guid><description>Buckwheat crêpes eaten as dishes, traditionally garnished with ham, eggs and cheese (galette complète).
~15/20 galettes.
Ingredients 500g buckwheat flour 1 egg 70cl water Directions Mix flour, salt, egg and water. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Let it rest one hour at room temperature. Cook the galette on a crepe-maker or a big flat pan. When garnishing, heat the galette again with a bit of salted butter.</description></item><item><title>French Crêpes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-crepes/</guid><description>Like pancakes, but very thin.
15 crêpes.
Ingredients 300g white flour 3 eggs 60cl milk 20cl beer 30g butter or 3 tablespoons of oil Directions Mix flour, salt, eggs and melted butter or oil. (In this order to avoid dry flour) Slowly add milk and beer until the dough becomes fluid enough. (Pouring it from the ladle has to be fluid) Let it rest one hour. (optional) Cook the crêpe in a flat pan, one ladle at a time.</description></item><item><title>Tomato Flavored Hamburger and Macaroni</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tomato-flavored-hamburger-macaroni/</guid><description>This is a based, easy and relatively quick to make meal. Great for making in large batches with a big pot and eating throughout the week.
⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 1 hour 🍽️ Servings: 6+ Ingredients 1/4 lb. Pork Sausage 1 lb. Med ground beef 1 3/4 Cups Elbow macaroni 1 Can of tomato sauce Diced half onion Diced half bell pepper Oregano leaves Paprika Sage Thyme Marjoram Rosemary leaves 2 Large grated garlic cloves Onion powder Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot sauce (optional) Mozzarella Cheese (optional) Better than Bulion 1 3/4 cups of Macaroni Elbows Directions Season the meat with the paprika, sage, thyme, marjoram, rosmary leaves, oregano leaves, and black pepper Saute the onion and the bell pepper until they become soft.</description></item><item><title>Banana Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 people Ingredients 1 cup flour (2.5 dl) 1 tablespoon sugar 2 teaspoon baking powder 1 cup milk (2.5 dl) 1 egg 2 very ripe bananas Directions Combine flour, sugar, baking powder and a little bit of salt in a large mixing bowl. Whisk milk and egg into the flour mixture until no clumps remain in the resulting batter.</description></item><item><title>Ginataang Kalabasa</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ginataang-kalabasa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ginataang-kalabasa/</guid><description>Or &amp;ldquo;Squash in Coconut Milk&amp;rdquo;. This is a common Filipino dish.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients One medium sized squash that is easy to peel (butternut squash is usually best) Two cans of coconut milk One onion A few cloves of garlic Directions Remove the seeds from your squash, then peel it and chop it up into large cubes, then set aside.</description></item><item><title>Hamburger Patties</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hamburger-patties/</guid><description>🍽️ Servings: 6 patties
Ingredients 1 cup soft bread crumb 1/2 cup milk 1 1/2 pound ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1/2 teaspoon salt dash pepper 1/2 teaspoon cayenne 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce 2 tablespoons of fat or salad oil Directions Combine all ingredients except fat: mix well; shape into 6 patties. Heat fat in skillet. Brown patties on all sides; lower heat; cook to desired degree of doneness.</description></item><item><title>Hellfire Steak</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hellfire-steak/</guid><description>I first learned this recipe from a Bishop I had growing up. It produces quite a good steak despite the unconventional ingredients.
Ingredients Steak Kosher Salt Mustard Powder Tabasco Sauce Directions Rub a generous amount of salt all over the steak Coat the entire steak with mustard powder Pour Tabasco Sauce onto both sides of the steak, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to put more on than you think you might otherwise be comfortable with the salt will cancel out a lot of the spice while grilling.</description></item><item><title>Hummus</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hummus/</guid><description>Ingredients One can of garbanzo beans (chickpeas) 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 cup of tahini (also known as tehina) 1/4 cup (or more, to taste) of lemon juice, fresh preferred - this is about 1 1/2 to 2 lemons' worth 1 (or 2) clove(s) of garlic, roughly chopped (fresh or frozen pre-chopped is fine, but not dry) 1/4 teaspoon cumin, ground (if you have whole, toast in a dry pan until fragrant before grinding) 1/4 teaspoon za&amp;rsquo;atar (optional, if you can find it) 1 Tablespoon of olive oil, plus more for serving Fresh parsley (optional for serving) Directions Drain and rinse the garbanzo beans.</description></item><item><title>Oaty Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oaty-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 3⁄4 cup milk 3⁄4 rolled oats 1 egg 1⁄2 teaspoon salt 2-3 tablespoon sugar 1⁄2 cup flour 2 teaspoon baking powder 2 teaspoon baking soda 25g butter (melted) Directions Pour milk over rolled oats. Add remaining ingredients. Mix with fork (or in a food processor) just enough to combine ingredients. Put spoonfuls of mixture onto preheated, greased or sprayed griddle or fry pan.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/peanut-butter/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb. of raw pre-shelled peanuts Directions Spread peanuts on a large baking sheet and roast in the oven at 350°F (175°C) for ten to twelve minutes While the peanuts are still hot remove any skins from them. This is best done by wrapping a few handfuls at a time in a dish towel and rolling them against each other for several seconds. Put all your roasted and skinned peanuts in a food processor, add salt if desired, and chop until you have reached your desired thickness of peanut butter.</description></item><item><title>Quick Breakfast Spaghetti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quickbreakfastspaghetti/</guid><description>A quick breakfast spaghetti recipe that covers a healthy amount of carbs, fat, and spices. Eggs and/or bacon can be added to cover some protein, you should cook those while the boiler is cooking the spaghetti for time efficiency.
Ingredients Spaghetti (any kind you prefer) Ground spices (I like to use cumin, turmeric, paprika, and garlic) Tomato Paste/Sauce (preferably one with basil and without preservative) Extra Virgin Olive Oil Directions Boil some water fully and prepare a pot.</description></item><item><title>Simple sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/simple-sauce/</guid><description>This is a simple and well known recipe. It goes by many names and this recipe is a starting point for many sauces, eg &amp;lsquo;1000 island sauce&amp;rsquo;.
Ingredients Tomato sauce. Mayonaise Directions Mix one part tomato sauce with two parts mayonnaise. What &amp;lsquo;part&amp;rsquo; means is up to you, because that will determine how much sauce you will have. You can also adjust this to your liking. More tomato sauce, more acidity.</description></item><item><title>Spaghetti and Meatballs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spaghetti-and-meatballs/</guid><description>⏲️Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️Servings: 6 Ingredients For the sauce ½ chopped sweet yellow onion 3 cloves chopped garlic 1 cup finely chopped carrots 1 cup chopped cremini brown mushrooms 2 cans (28 oz.) Italian plum tomatoes ¼ cup chopped fresh Italian parsley ¼ cup chopped fresh basil 3 tbsp. tomato paste ¼ cup grated Parmesan-Romano cheese blend ¼ cup red wine (optional) For the meatballs 1 lb.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed Round Squash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stuffed-round-squash/</guid><description>Round Squash, Zucchini, or Courguettes can be served as main dish (2 servings per person) or as accompaniment. The amount of squash should be adjusted according to their size. This recipe uses ones the size of a fist.
⏲️ Prep time: 50 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 2 Onions 1 Carrot 4 Round squash 1 Cup of rice 100gr of Cheese (optional) Directions Cook the rice.</description></item><item><title>Banana Muffins with Chocolate</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-muffins-with-chocolate/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min Ingredients 3 bananas 100 g / ½ cups butter 150 g / ¾ cups sugar 2 eggs 1½ tsp. cooking powder 260 g / 2⅛ cups wheat flour 50 g / 1¾ oz dark chocolate 50 g / 1¾ oz milk chocolate some vanilla sugar (optional) Directions Peel the bananas and mush them together. Whip the two eggs and mix them with the sugar.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sweet Potato Fries Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sweet-potato-fries/</guid><description>A simple, tasty, and healthy carb based snack.
Ingredients 1-2 Sweet Pototoes (try different types) Olive Oil Cinnamon Rosemary (optional) Directions Set oven heat to 425°F (220°C). Grab a pan and put a layer of parchment paper (or aluminum foil) on it. Chop the potato(es) on your cutting board with a sharp knife throwing them onto the pan. Drizzle the fries with olive oil. Toss the fries with clean hands to coat the fries in olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Beef Goulash</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-goulash/</guid><description>Although it takes some time to make, it is actually quite easy to make, and it is a really hearty and delicious recipe, if I do say so myself.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 90 min 🍽️ Servings: 2/3 Ingredients 500g beef 300-400g potatoes 1 carrot 1 medium onion 12 tablespoons tomato paste 500ml water 3-4 garlic cloves 3-4 bay leaves Curcuma Paprika Oregano Parsley Caraway Basil (optional) Cilantro (optional) 2-3 champignon mushrooms (optional) Directions Heat up the frying pan and add some oil.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Meatballs with Tomato Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cheesy-meatballs/</guid><description>Nothing beats meat, cheese and tomato combined together to create the best combination of flavors that man has created.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about two adult portions. That is, if you are also making some side dish, like in the photo.
For the meatballs:
300-400g of ground beef meat 1/4 of an onion ~70g of cheese; I have made with different cheese types, but usually I use Gouda Parsley 1-2 garlic cloves 1 egg ~1/5 metric cups (~50ml) of bread crumbs For the sauce:</description></item><item><title>Chicken Pasta Casserole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-pasta-casserole/</guid><description>Easy to throw together and transport for the working fellow. High in protein!
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 35 min 🍽️ Servings: 4-6 Ingredients 16oz (450g) macaroni (elbow, penne) 24oz (700g) raw chicken breast, diced 9oz (250g) mozzarella cheese, shredded 1.5oz (40g) parmesan cheese, grated 1.5oz (40g) bread crumbs 16oz (450g) diced tomatoes Some oil and butter (Optional) More mozzarella and parmesan for fans of cheese.</description></item><item><title>Chilli con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pork-based-chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Thinly minced and non-lean mince is preferred. Spices shall be left to the choice of the cook, if at all desired. Mince should be broken up well before cooking.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 1-2 hours Ingredients Chorizo pork sausage Pork mince Bacon strips Tomato sauce Chilis Kidney beans Olive oil Wine Butter (spices) Directions As pan heats: Slice chilies and chorizo as desired Olive oil in pan heat on high Pork mince in.</description></item><item><title>Country Breakfast Skillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/country-skillet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/country-skillet/</guid><description>If you are feeling quite hungry after just waking up and want to have a breakfast to fill your HP and stamina bars for the day, I&amp;rsquo;ve got just the perfect recipe for you.
To be honest, this is more of a build-your-own dish. What I am providing here, I would say, is more of a starting point and you&amp;rsquo;re more than welcome to add (or remove) anything you&amp;rsquo;d like. I also have to say that this is not exclusively a breakfast dish, I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for breakfast, for lunch, for supper, for dinner, etc.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/creamy-mashed-potatoes/</guid><description>Mashed potatoes is a really great recipe that is often relegated to the position of side dish. This recipe is a spin of the classical mashed potatoes recipe that&amp;rsquo;s got itself more going on. You can serve this dish for a relatively light meal, or you can also serve it as a side dish if you want to have a really hearty meal.
Ingredients The quantities here are for about four adult portions.</description></item><item><title>Fresh Guacamole</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/guacamole/</guid><description>A nice recipe that functions as a delicious and fresh appetizer, best eaten with some totopos corn chips, especially in a hot summer day.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two adult portions:
2 Hass avocados 1/4 medium onion 1 small tomato Cilantro 1 lime And of course, some totopos to eat with.
Directions Cut the avocados in half, open them and place the pulp in a bowl.</description></item><item><title>Fried Anglerfish fillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-anglerfish-fillet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-anglerfish-fillet/</guid><description>This is a simple light-flavoured recipe. Anglerfish (I&amp;rsquo;m referring specifically to the &amp;lsquo;monfish/sea-devil&amp;rsquo; variant) meat is mild, absorbing the butter and subtle flavours of the herbs. Preparing the anglerfish is an involved process that I&amp;rsquo;ll try and explain to the best of my abilities but watching someone do it would be more then helpful.
Ingredients 1 Anglerfish Butter, enough to fry with Chives or green onions Marjoram, fresh herbs are preferable Directions Preparing the fish Turn the creature on its back.</description></item><item><title>Fried Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-potatoes/</guid><description>Ingredients Potatoes Oil or Crème Fraîche Onions Directions Peel and cut the potatoes to desired size. Cut the onions. Put a bit of Oil or Crème Fraîche in your pan. Put both the potatoes and the onions into the pan. Cook them until they&amp;rsquo;re golden-brown. Enjoy</description></item><item><title>Hangover Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/hangover-eggs/</guid><description>Whenever my friends back home would drink to excess, they&amp;rsquo;d wake up wanting something tasty. I made them what I call &amp;ldquo;Hangover Eggs&amp;rdquo;. Whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re hungover, they&amp;rsquo;re very delicious! I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been making them to gain weight, though you can alter the recipe to whatever suits your lifestyle.
Ingredients Tony Chachere&amp;rsquo;s Green onions Olive oil Loaf of French Bread Eggs Tabasco Beer Directions Bring a cast iron pan to medium-high heat and add a second or two of olive oil when things start to warm up.</description></item><item><title>Japanese Noodle Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/japanese-noodle-soup/</guid><description>This is a very easy and simple Japanese style ramen noodle soup. This is very cheap to make, and you can really customise this however you wish with the garnish. This is my own spin inspired by other recipes that I found.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 20 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 750ml Chicken stock 4 Pork chops OR 4 Chicken Breasts Set honey 3 Garlic cloves Soy sauce Worcestershire sauce Ginger, sliced Chinese 5 Spice 1 Red Chilli, sliced and deseeded (Optional, but recommended) 375g Ramen Noodles (Medium Egg Noodles work well too) 100g Spinach (Optional) 4 Tbsp Sweetcorn (Optional) Sesame seeds (Optional) 4 Boiled Eggs (Optional) 1 Sheet of Dried Nori (Optional) Spring Onion, chopped (Optional) Directions For the broth, add 700ml of chicken stock to a large boiling pot with the garlic, ginger, soy sauce, chinese five spice, chili, and 300ml of water.</description></item><item><title>Ketchup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ketchup/</guid><description>Ketchup/Catsup Ingredients 2 1/2 quart (15 to 17 medium-sized) sliced tomatoes 1 large garlic clove, chopped 1 cup vinegar 1/4 cup chopped onion 1/2 cup sugar 3 - inch piece stick cinnamon 1 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon paprika 1 teaspoon whole cloves a dash cayenne pepper Directions Simmer together tomatoes and onion for 20 to 30 minutes; press through a sieve. Put the cinnamon, cloves, and garlic loosely in a clean, thin, white cloth; tie top tightly; add to vinegar and simmer 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Maque Choux</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/maque-choux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/maque-choux/</guid><description>An old cajun recipe for stewed corn &amp;amp; tomatoes. Enjoyable at any time of year, but I love to make it on hot summer afternoons as a side to a sausage dish. Pairs well with brown ales.
Ingredients A little sugar A good bit of grease (about a handful) Handful of chopped onion Handful of chopped bell pepper Eight ears of corn Handful of chopped tomatoes Salt &amp;amp; Pepper (to taste) Directions Clean the corn and cut lengthwise about a thumbnail (1/4 in) from the top and scrape down using the soft end of a knife (to keep the juices).</description></item><item><title>Merchant's Buckwheat</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/merchants-buckwheat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/merchants-buckwheat/</guid><description>Buckwheat is not very popular outside Russia, the former USSR, and some Asian countries; but it is a nice grain full of nutrients which can be used to prepare delicious and nutritious dishes.
Ingredients The ingredients below are for 2 hearty portions.
400g pork meat 1/2 metric cup (~125ml) buckwheat 1 1/5 metric cup (~300ml) water 1 medium-sized carrot 1 small onion 6-8 tablespoons tomato paste Wheat flour Curcuma Chili powder (optional) 3-4 garlic cloves Parsley 3-4 bay leaves Directions Chop the onion and cut the pork into small pieces.</description></item><item><title>Omelet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/omelet/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Omelets Ingredients 2 tablespoon quick-cooking tapioca 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/8 teaspoon pepper 3/4 cup milk, scalded 1 tablespoon butter, or margarine 4 egg yolks, beaten until thick 4 egg whites, beaten stiff Cheddar Cheese (optional for Cheese Omelet) Directions Add tapioca, salt and pepper to milk; cook in double boiler 15 minutes or until tapioca is clear and mixture thickened, stirring frequently.</description></item><item><title>Pan-seared Chicken Fillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pan-seared-chicken/</guid><description>This is a quick and easy recipe to prepare delicious chicken fillets that are juicy on the inside, and crisp on the outside.
Ingredients For this recipe I don&amp;rsquo;t use any exact proportions, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of cooking it one time to get a sense of what the ideal proportions for you are.
Chicken fillet(s); I normally use chicken breasts Wheat flour Paprika Garlic powder Herbes de Provence Directions Rinse the chicken fillets.</description></item><item><title>Parmesan potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/parmesan-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/parmesan-potatoes/</guid><description>You can have this as a side dish, or for breakfast. Well, you can have it whenever and wherever you want if you are cooking it! We are grown ups here after all.
Ingredients As you can already probably imagine, this dish doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of ingredients. The quantities are for one average hungry student. If you want to have it as a side dish this should be enough for two persons.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Navy Style</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-navy-style/</guid><description>This is one of the three pasta dishes that I usually cook. It&amp;rsquo;s a Russian pasta recipe that is fast and easy to make and is quite tasty.
Ingredients Here are the ingredients for about two hearty adult portions:
250g pasta. Usually I prefer to use fusilli or penne, but any short-cut pasta should do. 300-400g ground beef 3-4 tomatoes 1 carrot 1/2 onion 2-3 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika Directions Add olive oil to your frying pan, heat it to medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Quesadilla</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/quesadilla/</guid><description>A quick and easy low-prep meal, able to be taken anywhere.
⏲️ Prep time: ~5 minutes + ingredients prep time 🍽️ Serves: 1 Ingredients 1-2 tortillas. Any brand works, but you can decide if you want the tortilla folded in half, or 2 tortillas together. ~4 small pinches of (Mozzarella, Oaxaca, or Montery Jack cheese). Most cheeses are fine, but the taste of oaxaca cheese is more authentic.</description></item><item><title>Refried Beans</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/refried-beans/</guid><description>One of my favorite dishes that works either as an appetizer or side dish is refried beans. A classic from Mexican cuisine, that is best eaten with some totopos, or tortilla chips.
Ingredients As usual, the ingredients here are for about two adult portions:
400-500g can of pre-cooked beans 1/4 onion 3-4 garlic cloves Cumin Paprika 2-4 spoonfuls butter Cooking oil (can be olive oil) Directions Add the oil and the butter to the frying pan and heat to medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Roasted chicken breast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roasted-chicken-breast/</guid><description>How to roast chicken breast with a &amp;ldquo;leave-in&amp;rdquo; probe thermometer. The thermometer ensures the chicken comes out juicy and delicious.
Ingredients Boneless skinless chicken breast(s) 1/4 stick of butter per chicken breast Seasoning (optional) Directions Fill a large bowl with enough water to submerge the chicken. Add salt to the water until it&amp;rsquo;s fully saturated. Put the chicken under the water and let it sit for 20-40 minutes at room temperature.</description></item><item><title>Rösti</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/roesti/</guid><description>Used two serving sizes for this Rösti
This swiss classic works great together with fried eggs and steamed peas or spinach. Can be useful to get rid of leftover potatoes from the day before.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients ~800g (~1.5lb) potatoes (firm/waxy) 2 carrots 500g (~1lb) peas or spinach 4 eggs 2 onions (medium size) butter Directions Shred raw or cooked (but cool) potatoes with a grater.</description></item><item><title>Scandinavian Coffee Cake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/scandinavian-coffee-cake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: ≈ 3 hours 🍽️ Servings: 1 cake Ingredients 1/2 cup milk 1/2 cup shortening 1/2 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 package active dry yeast 1/4 cup warm (not hot) water 3 cup sifted enriched Flour 2 eggs, beaten melted butter, or margarine 2/3 cup firmly packed brown sugar 2 teaspoon cinnamon chopped walnuts Directions Scald milk. Add shortening, sugar, and salt.</description></item><item><title>Sticky Porkchops</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sticky-porkchops/</guid><description>Simple chinese inspired sticky porkchops.
⏲️ Prep time: 3 hours 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients 4 Pork chops 2 heaped tbsp Set honey 3 Garlic cloves, crushed Soy sauce Ginger (thumb sized piece), sliced 1 tbsp Chinese Five Spice Directions Fill a shallow dish with soy sauce to about half the thickness of your porkchops. The level shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to fully submerge them.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Morning Milkshake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sunday-milkshake/</guid><description>A sweet and refreshing milkshake that barely requires any effort to make. You&amp;rsquo;re not required to make it and drink it on Sunday, it was just almost a tradition in my family to make it on the weekends, and it somehow does taste better on a Saturday or Sunday morning.
Ingredients These are for about 4 glasses or 1 liter:
1 banana (or 2 if they are small) ~120 grams of berries.</description></item><item><title>Taco Meat</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/taco-meat/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound (about 500 g) ground beef or turkey 1 medium onion, finely chopped (or 1 1/2 teaspoon onion powder) 1 medium tomato, chopped (or 1 small can of tomato sauce) 1 teaspoon chili powder (or 1/3 teaspoon each oregano, cumin, garlic powder) 1 teaspoon oregano (ground or leaf) 1/4 teaspoon cumin dash of pepper (1/8 teaspoon or less) Directions Brown beef and onion together. Drain grease.</description></item><item><title>Tortellini</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tortellini/</guid><description>Ingredients Tortellini 1-2 eggs Cooking cream Cheese (optional) Directions Buy tortellini (prefer meat or spinach). Bring water to a boil. Add salt to water only after boiling. Add tortellini in. Cook for 3 minutes. Drain water from the pot while keeping tortellini in. Add cooking cream and mix at medium heat until reduced a bit so it&amp;rsquo;s more creamy. Turn off the heat and add 1 or 2 eggs.</description></item><item><title>Tuna Sub</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuna-sub/</guid><description>Use the best tuna you can find. I like oil-packed but water is OK. Someone you know has a tuna salad recipe.
Ingredients 1 recipe of your favorite tuna salad Sandwich bun or bread (a good one) Thinly sliced cheese (your favorite) Sliced tomatoes Baby spinach leaves Pickles Mayo and mustard Other sandwich toppings (very little out of bounds here). Directions Lightly toast one side of the bun Add cheese to bottom of bun Spread a layer of tuna salad Place several spinach leaves on top bun Add sliced tomatoes Add pickle slices Season with salt and pepper to taste Combine halves and enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Yogurt</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/yogurt/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 thermos, ½l capacity each thermometer 1l milk 100ml yogurt Directions bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) pour the yogurt into the milk wisk well bring the milk to 45°C (113°F) again (don&amp;rsquo;t go higher than that, please) boil some water (about 100ml) and use it to wash the thermos from inside let the water out and pour the milk into the thermos leave the thermos in the oven(or in any other place whithout air flow) for 12h store in the fridge</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/banana-bread/</guid><description>Not too sweet. Great for when you have friends over for tea.
Ingredients 2 cups all purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoon baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda Spices: 1 teaspoon cinnamon 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg 1/4 teaspoon ginger 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 cups mashed bananas (this is around 4-5 bananas) 2 eggs 1 cup sugar (brown or white is fine) 1/2 cup butter 1/4 cup crushed walnuts Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (175°C) Mix the wet ingredients (eggs, bananas, butter, sugar) in one bowl.</description></item><item><title>Beef Jerky</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-jerky/</guid><description>Beef Jerky is ideal for road trips and camping, as it will not perish as readily as fresh meat. It is suitable not only as a snack but also as a meal. This recipe for jerky is not heavily brined and flavored as commercial jerky is.
Ingredients ¾ tsp. salt ¼ tsp. pepper 1 tbsp. brown sugar ¼ tsp. garlic 2 tbsp. Worcestershire sauce or Teriyaki sauce ¼ tsp. Liquid Smoke 1 Lb.</description></item><item><title>Beef Tips in Gravy on Sour Cream Mashed Potatoes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-tips/</guid><description>Tender chunks of meat in a rich brown gravy poured over sour cream mashed potatoes, made in a pressure cooker. This recipe is a modification of the Texas Cafe Classics Sirloin Tips Recipe by Mark Rippetoe.
Ingredients Any lean, tough cut of meat (ex. round steak) Unprocessed animal fat of some kind (ex. beef suet, mutton fat) Potatoes Sour cream Butter Milk Shredded cheese of your choice Small amount of flour Beef bouillon (optional) Red wine (optional) Directions Beef Tips in Gravy</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe (meaning cheese and pepper) is not only based but also incredibly simple, ideal for lazy neets and similarly minded people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to wash too many dishes and don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated recipes with too many extra ingredients.
Ingredients Spaghetti Grated Pecorino Romano Peppercorns (you can also use pepper but it will change the flavour) Directions Cook your chosen amount of spaghetti 3-4 minutes under the time on the package according to the directions on the package or however you usually do it.</description></item><item><title>Caesar Salad</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/caesar-salad/</guid><description>Caesar Salad is an easy and delicious meal for lunch or dinner.
Ingredients Romaine Lettuce Grated Parmesan Cheese Croutons Caesar Salad Dressing Directions Prepare a whole head of Romaine Lettuce by chopping off the root and rising thoroughly with water. Dry completely. Once the lettuce is fully dry, put in a mixing bowl with lettuce and the Caesar Salad dressing. Toss to cover each leaf completely. Add croutons.</description></item><item><title>Carbonara</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonara/</guid><description>Carbonara is a simple dish. The quality of your ingredients makes or breaks it. I recommend using the best ingredients you can source. Suggestions: bronze extruded pasta, 24 months aged Parmigiano-Reggiano, 12+ months aged Pecorino Romano, guanciale from the butcher, and organic eggs.
This recipe assumes medium eggs.
⏲️ Prep time: 5 min 🍳 Cook time: 25 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Spaghetti: 320 g | 11 oz Eggs: 5 Guanciale or Smoked Pancetta (cleaned and cubed): 150 g | 5 oz Pecorino Romano or Parmigiano-Reggiano (grated)(optional) Directions Crack the eggs in a bowl but only add the yolks.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Biscuit Potpie Recipe</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-biscuit-potpie/</guid><description>Ingredients 1-2/3 cups frozen mixed vegetables, thawed 1-1/2 cups cubed cooked chicken 1 can (10-3/4 ounces) condensed cream of chicken soup, undiluted 1/4 teaspoon dried thyme 1 cup biscuit/baking mix 1/2 cup whole milk 1 large egg Directions Preheat oven to 400°F (200°C). In a large bowl, combine the vegetables, chicken, soup and thyme. Pour into an ungreased deep-dish 9-in. pie plate. Combine the biscuit mix, milk and egg; spoon over chicken mixture.</description></item><item><title>Chili Con Carne</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chili-con-carne/</guid><description>Ingredients Canned Whole Peeled Tomatoes Red Peppers White Onions Chili Pepper Garlic Ground Beef Kidney Beans Dark Chocolate Chili Powder Tomato Paste Beef Stock (optional) Neutral Oil Cilantro Sugar seasoning cumin paprika chili flakes Directions Brown the beef by adding it to a pot with neutral oil. Start breaking it into small pieces. Allow water to leave the meat. Salt it to expel more water.</description></item><item><title>Croutons</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/croutons/</guid><description>Croutons are an essential addition to many salads. They are delicious and easy to make at home.
Ingredients Hearty White Bread Extra Virgin Olive Oil Spices Directions Preheat oven to 350°F (roughly 180°C). Gently cut slices of white bread into squares with a chef&amp;rsquo;s knife. One to two slices is usually enough for one person. In a large bowl combine olive oil, spices, and bread squares and gently mix to thoroughly season bread.</description></item><item><title>Dried tomato &amp; plum bread spread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/dried-tomato-plum-spread/</guid><description>Quick and simple bread spread.
Ingredients 10 dried plums 1 jar of dried tomatoes 1 tsp of smoked paprika pinch of dried coriander (optional) pinch of chilli (optional, if you like it to be spicy) Directions Put plums in hot water from kettle for couple of minutes, in order to make them softer. After that put plums (without the water) and rest of the ingredients into blender and mix it until you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied.</description></item><item><title>Drunken beans (Pintos Borrachos)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/drunken-beans/</guid><description>Pinto beans cooking with beer, what beer you use can change the dish.
Ingredients 1 small yellow onion 3 gloves of garlic 2 tomatoes. chopped 4 cups of water 1 1/2 cups of pinto beans (can be dried or canned) 1 tbsp oregano 3/4 tsp cumin 2 tbsp chilli powder(depends how hot you like it) 12oz of Beer/dark ale Directions Sauté onions. Add garlic, sauté bit longer. Add tomatoes, water, beans, oregano, cumin, chilli powder, beer and salt, gradually bring to boil.</description></item><item><title>Flammkuchen</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/flammkuchen/</guid><description>A recipe for Flammkuchen a very thin crust pizza-like dish - it originates from Elsass, a French region close to where I grew up. I like the recipe because it takes 10 minutes to prepare and another 10 minutes to bake. It goes well with a green salad as a side.
🍽️ Servings:2 Ingredients 400g Pizza dough (either bought or from Pizza Dough) 1 onion (I prefer the red ones for optical reasons) 150g bacon (you can replace it with mushrooms or other vegetables) 2 big spoons of sour creme or creme fraiche Directions we start by flattening the dough.</description></item><item><title>Instant Tom Yam Kung noodle soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/instant-tom-yam-kung-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Instant noodles with processed spices are quick but not the most healthy. It&amp;rsquo;s important to add fresh veggies and eggs. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick tasty lunch, a life saver when going through a busy period.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 2 people Ingredients 2 packages of vegetable- or tom yam-quick noodles 1 can coconut milk 10 small or 5 big mushrooms 2 eggs A few salad leaves (or practically any veggie you have in the fridge) 1 lime Coriander Directions Put small amount of water and coconut milk to boil.</description></item><item><title>Liver Pate</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/liverpate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/liverpate/</guid><description>Good start for trying to eat more organs. It even tastes very nice. The last step before eating it raw someday.
Ingredients 1lbs./500g liver (chicken, beef, poultry etc.) 1 Cup Carrots 1 Cup Onions 2 Teaspoon Nutmeg 2 Tablespoon Butter or Ghee Directions Cut liver into cubes. Put into a pot and cover with cold water, add 1tsp salt. Bring to a boil and boil for 10-15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Marinated pork steaks</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/marinated-pork-steaks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/marinated-pork-steaks/</guid><description>A tasty simple marinade that fits well with pork.
⏲️ Prep time: 35 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 10 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 3-4 people Ingredients 6 tablespoons olive oil ¼ cup soy sauce ¼ cup of honey Juice from 1 lime 3 peeled cloves garlic 4 ¼ inch thick boneless pork shoulder steaks Directions Mix olive oil, soy sauce, honey and lime juice until you have an even marinade.</description></item><item><title>Matcha Cookies</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/matcha-cookies/</guid><description>Matcha is a type of tea leaf powder that has a beautiful vivid green color. However, it’s different from the “green tea” that you drink with Japanese meals. That’s green tea too, but matcha green tea leaves are grown and harvested differently. The leaves are grown under shade.
Ingredients (for 13 cookies, 8 ~ 9cm in diameter)
115g Unsalted butter 60g Caster sugar 115g Brown sugar 55g Egg 153g Plain flour 12g Matcha powder 2g Baking soda 1g Salt 3g Vanilla extract 70g White coverture chocolate 45g Macadamia nut Directions Melt butter in a bath or microwave.</description></item><item><title>Miso Ginger Pork</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-ginger-pork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/miso-ginger-pork/</guid><description>Ingredients ground pork sushi rice green onion fresh ginger miso paste pickled daikon zucchini or bok choy sesame oil (or olive oil) broth (optional) Directions cook sushi rice slice daikon, and pickle in a quick brine (rice vinegar, sugar, water) dice white parts of green onion, mince green ends for garnish mince fresh ginger chop zucchini or bok choy into half inch (1-1.5 cm) chunks heat up 2 tablespoons sesame oil break up and brown ground pork till almost cooked through salt and pepper the pork add 1/2 cup to 1 cup (250-500 mL) water or broth add white parts of green onion and ginger add miso paste to taste simmer stirring occasionally add zucchini or bok choy, cook al dente serve pork &amp;amp; veggies over bed of rice, garnish with green onion (optional) add some spice!</description></item><item><title>Pancake</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pancake/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 1 Ingredients 200g wheat flour or 100g glutenfree flour 200 ml milk 2 eggs 2 tsp sugar 1 tsp baking soda a little bit of salt Directions Mix all ingredients in a bowl. Let the dough rest for ~15 mins. Heat a pan with a bit butter or oil. For each pancake spread a ladle of dough in the pan and bake them at lower medium temperature until they are brown on both sides.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Dough</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pizza-dough/</guid><description>Here is a simple pizza dough recipe. Basically you use a 2/1 ratio of flour/liquid. If you use other flour like rye, you may need more liquid.
Ingredients 400g flour (basic wheat flour) 200ml lukewarm water 1 pkg (7g) dry yeast 1 spoon olive oil 1 teaspoon salt a teensy bit of sugar (to feed the yeast) Directions Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and knead into a dough.</description></item><item><title>Potato and Eggplant (Aubergine) Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</guid><description>A simple and tasty curry that is easy to customise.
Ingredients 1 large eggplant (aubergine) 2 medium potatoes 3 tbsp olive oil 2 onions (finely sliced) 2 garlic cloves (crushed) 2 tsp garam masala 2 tsp turmeric 2 tsp ground coriander 400 ml can chopped tomatoes 400 ml can coconut milk rice Optional extras carrots red peppers (capsicums) paneer Directions Heat the oven to approximately 200 °C (392 °F).</description></item><item><title>Ragù</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ragu/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 pound tubular dried pasta 1 pound sweet Italian sausage 1 onion, minced 1 carrot, minced 1 celery stalk, minced 28oz (825 ml) can of whole tomatoes 3 tablespoon of tomato paste 1/4 cup fresh parsley 1 sprig of fresh thyme 1 sprig of fresh rosemary grated Parmesan cheese (optional) extra-virgin olive oil Directions Sauté sausage crumbles in a large pan or dutch oven over medium-low heat.</description></item><item><title>Sauerkraut</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sauerkraut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sauerkraut/</guid><description>Sauerkraut is a based lacto-fermented food that is healthy and has a long shelf live.
Ingredients 1 head of cabbage 2-4% sea salt by cabbage weight Directions Prepare and clean as many glass jars as you think you&amp;rsquo;ll need. Chop or shred cabbage and rinse under cold water. Sprinkle with salt. Knead the cabbage with clean hands for about 10 minutes until there is enough liquid to cover it.</description></item><item><title>Älplermagronen (Alpine macaroni)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/aelplermagronen/</guid><description>A swiss favorite, Älplermagronen combines pretty much everything you have at your disposal in your alpine chalet. It&amp;rsquo;s the definition of comfort food for the Swiss.
🍳 Cook time: ~30 minutes 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients ~150g (1/3 lb) bacon cubes 3 onions (medium size) 400g (15 oz) potatoes (firm/waxy) 1 - 2L (1/4 - 1/2 gal) milk 400g (15 oz) macaroni (dry weight) ~150g (1/3 lb) medium soft cheese.</description></item><item><title>Almeirim Stone Soup</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/almeirim-stone-soup/</guid><description>It is truly emblematic of Portuguese cuisine, as it uses all of the ingredients available in order to waste no food.
Ingredients well-washed stone kidney beans or fresh pig&amp;rsquo;s ear (blanched and sliced thin) chouriço negro or firm type of blood sausage mixed meat chouriço or mediterranean smoked sausage pork belly, fatback or bacon potatoes, cubed onions, chopped garlic cloves bay leaf cilantro/coriander, chopped Directions In a saucepan, boil the kidney beans with the pig&amp;rsquo;s ear, sausages, pork belly, onions, garlic and bay leaf in some water and add a well-washed stone.</description></item><item><title>Beef Stroganoff</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/stroganoff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/stroganoff/</guid><description>This is American-style stroganoff.
Ingredients beef chicken stock onions flour butter Worchestershire sauce or something similar dijon or honey dijon mustard egg noodles Directions Dice an onion. Cut beef into bite-size strips. Ground beef can also be used (although not traditional), if beef is compacted into strips of similar size. Season the beef with kosher salt, freshly-ground pepper, or any other desired seasoning. Heat a skillet on high with butter or olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Bitoque - Portuguese Steak with Beer Sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/portuguese-steak-with-beer-sauce/</guid><description>Bitoque (pronounced bee-tok) is a traditional quintessential Portuguese dish, its name comes from being cooked in wood burning ovens in the oil mills. Good in combination with red wine, beer sauce that I am going to also provide the ingredients and directions on how to do, rice, french fries and a salad.
Ingredients sirloin steaks garlic olive oil q.b. (quanto basta – ‘enough’) medium fat milk beer mustard flour eggs Directions Season the steaks with sliced garlic and salt.</description></item><item><title>Bread</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/bread/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a basic loaf of bread. The dough itself can be used however. I&amp;rsquo;ve made buns, rolls, and whole bread loafs using this same exact dough every time without a problem. Eat within 3 days as it will probably be going stale around then (as bread without preservatives and other junk should).
Ingredients 1 1/2 cups warm water 2 and 1/4 teaspoons Active Dry Yeast 1 Tsp sugar 2 Tbsp maple syrup, agave, or honey 1/2 Tbsp salt 3 3/4 cups Unbleached All-Purpose Flour (plus more for rolling / dusting) Directions Proof the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Broiled Trevally</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/broiled-trevally/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/broiled-trevally/</guid><description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a giant trevally, and if you have seen one, that fish looks ugly. So here&amp;rsquo;s a recipe to make it look&amp;mdash;and taste!&amp;mdash;more appealing.
Ingredients giant trevally eggplants squash (or zucchini) carrots onion garlic ginger tomatoes bay leaf olive oil thyme basil butter Directions Dice carrots, eggplant, squash, tomatoes and onions. Place these on a pan. Put basil, thyme, bay leaf, salt, and pepper on each of the fish&amp;rsquo;s side.</description></item><item><title>Carbonade Flamande (Traditional Flemish beef stew)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/carbonade/</guid><description>This one is a delicious slow cooked beef stewed in beer. The smoked bacon is not in the traditional recipe but it&amp;rsquo;s good. Don&amp;rsquo;t add it if you want the real deal.
🍳 Cook time: 4-8 hours 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients beef (chuck, brisket, oxtail&amp;hellip;): 1kg | 2 1/4lb gingerbread: 5 slices brown sugar: 1tbsp brown beer (try to get a strong, tasty one): 1L | 4 cups onions: 400g | 1lb diced smoked bacon: 250g | 1/2lb (optional) mustard butter olive oil thyme cloves (not garlic cloves, just cloves): 5 juniper berries: 5 bay leaves: 2 Directions Cut meat into big chunks Dice onions Sear the meat on high heat in a large stainless or cast iron pot until golden brown, using olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Parmesan</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-parmesan/</guid><description>The recipe that started this very site.
Ingredients chicken breasts tomatoes (San Marzano is best) mozzarella cheese parmesan cheese bread crumbs eggs flour pasta sauce Directions Slice the chicken breasts through their width so that they are as flat as possible. Pound breasts as flat as possible. Add flour to a bowl or basin large enough to fit a breast, add pepper. Crack eggs into another large bowl or basin and whisk them.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Stock or Bone Broth</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-stock-bone-broth/</guid><description>Chicken stock, or &amp;ldquo;bone broth&amp;rdquo; is not a final dish in itself, but is used in many soups and other dishes to add great taste to something otherwise very simple. While it is easy to make, it sells for very expensive in the store, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to know to make by yourself since it can be done very cheaply.
Ingredients a whole raw chicken with organs removed (Drumsticks or thighs alone might suffice if a whole chicken is unavailable.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Wings</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-wings/</guid><description>Perfectly cooked fall off the bone buffalo wings.
Ingredients Chicken wings and drums Enough Frank&amp;rsquo;s RedHot Sauce to marinate and top dress* Reynold&amp;rsquo;s Oven Bag Directions Soak your wings in Franks RedHot overnight Preheat your oven to 350°F (175°C) Transfer wings to the Reynold&amp;rsquo;s bag, seal it, and put it in the oven for an hour Crank up your grill† to high heat Throw the wings on the grill to char the skin and dress with a light top coat of Franks * Not the &amp;ldquo;wing sauce&amp;rdquo; version</description></item><item><title>Chicken, Tomato and Spinach Curry</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tomato-spinach-curry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tomato-spinach-curry/</guid><description>This dish is a very simple and tasty curry that can be made with minimal ingredients, but pairs amazingly with anything else one may want in a curry (i.e. ginger, lemongrass). Note: You may also need a blender / food processor.
Ingredients 500g or 1lb of chicken breast Virgin olive oil (1/2 cup or ~100ml) Fresh tomatoes of any variety (10 - 15 medium sized) Two medium sized onions 250g or 1/2lbs of fresh spinach Curry powder of your favourite variety Red chilies (or red chilli paste) Any extra herbs or spices to your taste Directions Dice your onions, begin to fry in the pot at a medium-low temperature.</description></item><item><title>Eggs</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/eggs/</guid><description>Eggs are great. This page will contain all sorts of &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; ways of having an egg. Feel free to suggest more, as per the instructions on the homepage.
Ingredients eggs butter cheese(optional) milk (optional) Directions Boiled eggs Bring water to boil (about enough to cover the eggs when submerged). Place eggs in water. Keep heat high enough to keep a rolling boil, boil until desired consistency (about 5 or less minutes for soft boiled and very runny, 8 minutes for medium runny, 10+ for hard boiled).</description></item><item><title>French mustard sauce porkchops (Côtes de porc charcutières)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/french-mustard-sauce-porkchops/</guid><description>French bistrot style porkchops with a mustard, white wine and gherkins sauce. Very quick to cook.
🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients porkchops: 4 shallots: 2 gerkins: a dozen medium sized ones white wine: 350ml | 1 1/2 cup brown stock: 100ml | 1/2 cup mustard: 2tbsp butter olive oil Directions Cut the shallots into small dices. Cut the gherkins into long strips. Sear the porkchops on high heat on cast iron or stainless steel pan until golden brown on each side, and cook them through on lower heat.</description></item><item><title>Gnocchi</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/gnocchi/</guid><description>Gnocchi is a pasta based on potato, making it a less bloating alternative to other kinds of pasta. They are substantial and can be roasted in butter and other ingredients.
Ingredients potatoes flour tomato parmesan butter sage or oregano or thyme Directions Boil potatoes (with their skins) until mashable. Slice potatoes in two and scoop them out of their skin. Mash with a potato-masher while adding kosher salt.</description></item><item><title>Oats</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/oats/</guid><description>Oats are great for breakfast. On their own they&amp;rsquo;re pretty bland, but become great when you add some things to the bowl. This recipe offers some suggestions on what to add, but is by no means a comprehensive overview of what you can do with oats.
We cover both rolled and steel cut oats. Instant need not apply.
Ingredients oats water pinch of salt Pick and choose additional ingredients:</description></item><item><title>Pasta (store bought)</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook pasta. TL;DR: you boil it. Pasta is usually eaten with some kind of pasta sauce or used in another dish.
Ingredients pasta basil (optional) butter (optional) Directions Fill a large pot about half or 3/4th full with water. Salt the water profusely. The rule of thumb is that water for boiling pasta should taste as salty as the sea.</description></item><item><title>Pasta sauce</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/pasta-sauce/</guid><description>This is very simple pasta sauce. Unlike modern store-bought sauces, there is no added sugar, only the subtle taste of San Marzano tomatoes.
Ingredients a can of San Marzano tomatoes (or home-grown with some extra pulp) onion or garlic olive oil oregano or basil (Dried or diced) Directions Heat up olive oil on saucepan. Add and roast either diced or grated onion or crushed and sliced garlic until translucent.</description></item><item><title>Rice</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/rice/</guid><description>Rice is easy to make in any pot. The simple use of different spices can change its use or what it accents.
Ingredients rice chicken stock (optional) onion or garlic (optional) lime and cilantro (optional, for a Mexican taste) Directions Add some amount of rice to a pot that has a cover. Add twice as much liquid to the same pot. Water is typical, but for extra flavor, use stock or broth.</description></item><item><title>Slow-cooked Chicken Tacos</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/chicken-tacos/</guid><description>Ingredients chicken breasts two or three onions (preferably red) seasoning: adobo seasoning paprika cheese (either shredded Mexican blend or crumbling cheese) small tortillas lime cilantro, tomato, lettuce, other desired taco contents Directions Quarter two onions and spread on the bottom of a slow-cooker. Place chicken breasts on top of onions. Season slow-cooker contents liberally with adobo seasoning, paprika and any other desired seasonings, squeeze half of a lime too if desired.</description></item><item><title>Traditional beef or lamb stew</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/beef-stew/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a typical Irish stew. This is traditionally made with lamb since it&amp;rsquo;s cheaper however, beef tastes a lot better and is more readily available in North America I&amp;rsquo;ve been told. This is good if you want to feed a family or if you just want to be lazy and eat the same thing for 2 or 3 days. Besides browning the meat this is really just throwing stuff into a pot in a certain order.</description></item><item><title>Tuscan Style Pork Roast</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tuscan-style-pork-roast/</guid><description>An herbaceous pancetta stuffed pork roast with a crispy exterior. Finished with a lemon vinaigrette. Adapted from Binging With Babish whose instructions are notoriously bad.
⏲️ Prep time: 30 minutes 🍳 Cook time: 2 hours 🍽️ Servings: 6-8 people Equipment Food processor Fine mesh strainer Cast iron skillet Butchers twine Ingredients 1 pork Roast 2-3 Tbsp fresh rosemary 8 cloves garlic, minced ⅓ cup high quality olive oil 1 lemon 4 oz pancetta or bacon 1 tsp fresh parsley Directions Preheat oven to 275°F (135°C) Butterfly the roast by cutting into three parts by cutting into the side starting a third of the way up the roast.</description></item><item><title>Tiroler Gröstl</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tiroler-groestl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tiroler-groestl/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 5 Ingredients 1 kg / 2 lbs potatoes 2 red onions 500 g / 1 lbs porkchops 400 g / 14 ounce bacon (smoked) 5 eggs 3 cloves of garlic Ample amount of chopped parsley Marjoram and cumin to taste Directions Clean potatoes and boil with skin. Chop onion, squeeze and mince the garlic.</description></item></channel></rss>