<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tunisian on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/tunisian/</link><description>Recent content in Tunisian on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/tunisian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tajine Maadnous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/tajine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Similar to an Italian frittata or Spanish tortilla, Tunisian tajine maadnous is an easy &amp;amp; delicious egg omelette filled with chicken, parsley, and spices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/tajine-maadnous.webp" alt="tajine maadnous">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 35 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 12&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 lb chicken breasts diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 medium onion chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large potato peeled and diced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 small bunch parsley (about 1.5 cups, chopped, loosely packed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 large eggs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 oz cheese&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="spice-blend">Spice Blend&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 tsp cumin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp turmeric&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp paprika or cayenne pepper if you want some heat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp caraway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Mix the spices together (grinding any whole spices if necessary) and set them aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large frying pan or pot over medium heat, saute the onions in about 1 tbsp of olive oil until tender.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toss chicken with 1/2 of the spice mix. Add this to the pan and brown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the potatoes and the water to the pan. Bring to a gentle simmer, then cook uncovered until potatoes are tender and most of the liquid has evaporated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir chopped parsley into the cooked mixture and set aside to cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 350Â°F (180Â°C), and grease a medium (2 quart/liter) baking pan with the remaining olive oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thoroughly whisk the eggs in a large bowl, then mix in the cheese. Stir in the chicken, potato, and parsley mixture, along with the remaining spice mixture. Stir until well-combined, then pour into the oiled baking dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake for 30-35 minutes, or until set in the center. Allow to cool, and serve warm or at room temperature. Serve with some harissa, if you like.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tunisian Couscous</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/couscous/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/couscous/</guid><description>&lt;p>Credits to creator of recipe, Mike Benayoun , &lt;a href="https://www.196flavors.com/tunisia-tunisian-couscous/">(original recipe)&lt;/a>.
I decided to post it on here to be more available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/android_asset/html/pix/couscous.webp" alt="couscous">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Couscous is a staple in most Maghreb cuisines. It is known as the national dish in Tunisia, but also in Algeria and Morocco, as well as Mauritania and Libya. Tunisian couscous is one of the countless variations of this delicious and versatile dish.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>â²ï¸ Prep time: 20 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ³ Cook time: 1 hr 40 min&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ðŸ½ï¸ Servings: 6&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 lb lamb stew meat , cut into large pieces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 cups couscous fine semolina (or medium)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 onions , finely chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cloves garlic , pressed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 tablespoons tomato paste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons harissa&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 tablespoons ground caraway&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoon ground coriander&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 teaspoon chili powder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 turnips , cut in half&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 medium carrots , peeled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 zucchini , peeled lengthwise, alternately leaving a layer of skin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 small potatoes , peeled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 oz. chickpeas (canned)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 green hot peppers , fried in oil (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Vegetable oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="equipment">Equipment&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tajine pot&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Add Â½ cup (120ml) of oil into a large pan. Fry the onion over medium heat for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the garlic, tomato paste and harissa and continue frying for 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the caraway, coriander, and chili powder. Mix and continue cooking for another 2 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the lamb meat and mix well so that the pieces are covered with the sauce. Cook for 5 minutes stirring regularly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cover with water. Add the turnips and carrots, and cook on low/medium heat for 45 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meanwhile, prepare the couscous semolina as indicated on the package, with boiling water, salt, and oil.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After 45 minutes, add the zucchini, potatoes and chickpeas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cook for at least another 30 to 40 minutes over low to medium heat. Monitor the cooking of the vegetables. If some vegetables are cooked before the meat, remove them from the pan and place them on a serving platter. Proceed in the same way with all the vegetables to prevent them from cooking too much.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 minutes before the end of cooking, get a few ladles of broth (one at a time) and wet the couscous semolina. Mix the semolina well after each ladle until it gets moistened enough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arrange the semolina in a tajine pot. Decorate the dish with the vegetables and the meat all around. Garnish with fried green hot peppers (optional).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>