<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apple on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/apple/</link><description>Recent content in apple on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spiced Apple Pancakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/spiced-apple-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/spiced-apple-pancakes/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 15 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 pancakes Ingredients 1 cup flour 1 large apple, peeled 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp cinnamon (or more to taste) 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp vanilla extract 2/3 cup milk 1 egg Directions In a medium bowl, combine flour, sugar, cinnamon, baking powder, and 1 pinch of salt. Separate the egg yolk and egg white.</description></item><item><title>Apple Chicken</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-chicken/</guid><description>Baked chicken with apples and onions. Suprinsingly good and simple combination.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 40 min 🍽️ Servings: 4 Ingredients Chicken breast or similar. Onions. Nuez moscada. Apples. Potatoes. Cream or creme fraiche. Salt. Pepper. One glass (33c) of wine or cognac. Directions Heat the oven to 200C and prepare an oven tray. Mix the chicken with nuez moscada, salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Apple Pie</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/apple-pie/</guid><description> ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳Cook time: 45 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients Filling 900 g (4-5) golden delicious apples 15 g (1 tbsp) lemon juice 50 g white sugar 65 g brown sugar 5 g (1 tsp) cinnamon 1-2 g nutmeg 15 g cornstarch 15 g ice water 226 g (2 sticks) cold butter, cut into slices Crust 350 g flour 5 g salt 30 g white sugar 225 g butter 50-100 ml ice water Egg Wash 1 egg (optional) 15 g water (optional) Directions Peel and cut the apples into 1-2 inch strips Put the apples in a bowl and mix in the lemon juice, sugar, cinnamon, nutmeg, and cornstarch and let it sit for 15 mins to release water Transfer the filling mixture to a sauce pan and reduce the liquid over medium to low heat for around 15 mins, stirring regularly, then turn off the gas While the filling is sitting / reducing, start the crust by putting the flour, salt, sugar, and pieces of butter in a food processor Run the food processor until it resembles a coarse sand (5-10 seconds) then start dripping in the ice water until the mixture starts to chunk together You&amp;rsquo;ll know when it&amp;rsquo;s done if you can pinch the dough with your hand and it sticks together Preheat oven to 350°F then start making the pie crust Cut the dough in half and roll both halves out with a rolling pin until they are big enough to cover your pie pan (around 9 inch diameter) Put the bottom half dough into the pie pan and cut off the excess dough with a knife Dump the sauce pan full of the filling into the pie pan and even it out Cover the pie filling with the top dough and fold over and tuck in the excess crust Use a fork or your fingers to pinch down the top crust to the bottom crust so you don&amp;rsquo;t have air gaps Optionally you can now brush on the egg wash to make the crust get a shiny golden brown color when it cooks Cut a few slits in the top crust with a knife to give it a nice design and allow for air to release Bake 45 minutes at 350°F or until the crust is brown to your liking and the apples are bubbling inside</description></item></channel></rss>