<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Cooking</title>
    <link>/android_asset/html/tags/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Cooking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Butter Chicken Masala Curry</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/butter-chicken-masala/</guid>
      <description>Butter chicken Masala is one of India&amp;rsquo;s most popular chicken recipes, a mild curry with a tomato-onion-cream base and boneless chicken pieces cooked in it to perfection.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2  Ingredients  Boneless Chicken 1/2lb, cubed Butter Melted 2 tbsp Onions 2 medium-sized, minced Tomato 2 medium-sized, pureed Oil 2 tbsp Lemon juice 1 tbsp Garlic cloves 3, minced/crushed Ginger 1tbsp, minced/paste Garam Masala/Chicken Masala 1 tbsp Cream 4tbsp (or cashew paste) Chilli Powder 1 tbsp Turmeric powder 1/4 tbsp Crushed fenugreek leaves 1/4 tbsp 1 small bunch of coriander leaves / cilantro, for ganish  Directions  In a bowl, mix chicken with salt, pepper, 1/2 tbsp ginger-garlic paste, 1/2 tbsp chili powder, turmeric powder, and lemon juice for the chicken marinade; let marinate for an hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coriander Chicken</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/coriander-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Boneless chicken marinated in a gravy of yoghurt and coriander
 ⏲️ Prep time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 20 min 🍽️ Servings: 3  Ingredients  500g boneless chicken breast 250g fat free yoghurt 250g coriander leaves Mustard oil / Sunflower oil Sugar Ginger Garlic 2 medium onions Green chillies Garam masala 2/3 Cardamom pods 1 Bayleaf 1 Cinnamom stick  Directions  Cut the boneless chicken into small bite sized pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curry sauce</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/curry-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I like to make double this amount and freeze the rest.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 20 min 🍳 Cook time: 60 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  25g butter 1 onion, sliced 2 garlic cloves, sliced Thumb of ginger, sliced 2 tbsp curry powder 1/2 tsp turmeric 1 tbsp malt vinegar 1 star anise 250ml chicken stock 1 tbsp cornflour 2 tbsp water Lemon juice (optional)  Directions  Melt the butter in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garam Masala</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/garam-masala/</guid>
      <description>A spice mixture for most Indian dishes
Ingredients  4 Green Cardamom 2 Black Cardamom 1 tbsp Coriander 2 Cloves 1 tbsp Cumin 1 tbsp Fennel seeds 5/6 Bayleaf 5/6 Black pepper pods 1 Star anise (Optional) Mace (Optional): Mace is a dried flower originating from the Nutmeg plant. Use no more than 3 strands of this flower.  Directions  Star anise and Mace are normally not added to Garam masala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naan Bread</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/naan-bread/</guid>
      <description>A curry serves best with naan that is unleavened bread. Traditionally made in ‘Tandoor or clay oven&#39; but at home, we will be making it in the oven and/or on the stovetop. Naan is not eaten solely but acts as assortments with meat, veggies, or egg items.
 ⏲️ Prep time: 90 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 4  Ingredients  All-purpose flour 3 cups Active dry yeast 1 tbsp Sugar 2 tbsp Warm Milk 1 cup Butter melted 2 tbsp Oil - little to grease  Directions  Put the yeast and sugar to warm milk in a large mixing bowl and stir well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/paneer-tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g cubes paneer 1 onion 1 capsicum 200ml tomato puree 1 tsp red chilli powder 1 tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp coriander powder 1/2 tsp garam masala powder 100ml thick yogurt 1 tsp fenugreek powder dry fenugreek leaves cardamom cumin seeds shaved ginger 20ml garlic paste 1 bowl corn  Directions  Take a glass container, and mix the cubed paneers with half a tea spoon of red chilli powder, turmeric powder, coriander powder, garam masala powder, fenugreek powder, and 50g yogurt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato and Eggplant (Aubergine) Curry</title>
      <link>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/android_asset/html/posts/potato-and-eggplant-curry/</guid>
      <description>A simple and tasty curry that is easy to customise.
Ingredients  1 large eggplant (aubergine) 2 medium potatoes 3 tbsp olive oil 2 onions (finely sliced) 2 garlic cloves (crushed) 2 tsp garam masala 2 tsp turmeric 2 tsp ground coriander 400 ml can chopped tomatoes 400 ml can coconut milk rice  Optional extras  carrots red peppers (capsicums) paneer  Directions  Heat the oven to approximately 200 °C (392 °F).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
