<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>seafood on Offline Cook Book</title><link>/android_asset/html/tags/seafood/</link><description>Recent content in seafood on Offline Cook Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/android_asset/html/tags/seafood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newfoundland Cod Chowder</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/newfoundland-cod-chowder/</guid><description>⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🍳 Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 8 Ingredients 4 Slices Bacon 2 Onions, sliced 1 tsp Savoury 6 Potatoes, peeled and cubed 3 Carrots, sliced 1 1/2 lbs Cod Fillets 1 can Evaporated Milk 2 Tbsp Fresh Parsley or Chives, chopped Directions In a large, heavy saucepan, cook bacon over medium-high heat for about 10 minutes or until crisp. Chop coarsely and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Butter Seafood Pasta</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/seafood-pasta/</guid><description>This is a simple outline of how to cook a creamy seafood pasta with white wine butter sauce.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 min Ingredients spaghetti or fettucine butter heavy cream garlic oregano white wine (Pinot Grigio or Sauvignon Blanc recommended) lemon/lemon juice (optional) red pepper flakes (optional) seafood, choose from: mussels squid shrimp clams lobster Directions Prepare your pasta, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how I recommend to follow these instructions. I choose to make mine al dente because it will continue to cook slightly once we add the sauce.</description></item><item><title>Ceviche</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/ceviche/</guid><description>Ceviche is a South American dish which originated in Peru. The following recipe will only cover the bare minimum ingredients, so feel free to experiment by adding things like garlic, ginger, peppers tomatoes, cilantro, other citrus juices, and anything else you feel might taste good in there.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min Ingredients Seafood Red Onion Lime Juice Directions Slice your onion as thinly as you can then let them all sit in a bowl of cold water for a while.</description></item><item><title>Sardine Cakes</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/sardine-cakes/</guid><description>Can be served with a Spicy Yogurt Sauce as Tapas or Hors D’Oeuvres.
⏲️ Prep time: 10 min 🧊 Chill time: 30 min 🍳 Cook time: 10 min 🍽️ Servings: 15 Ingredients Sardine Fish Cakes 2 tins sardines (~4oz) ½ cup mayonnaise ½ cup Panko breadcrumbs 2 teaspoons Old Bay seasoning 1 egg lemon juice (optional) Spicy Yogurt Sauce ½ cup plain yogurt (whole milk) 1 tablespoon sriracha 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard 1 teaspoon Worcestershire sauce minced garlic (optional) Directions Remove sardines from tin, reserving oil, and place fish in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Lobster bisque</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/lobster-bisque/</guid><description>Creamy french lobster soup perfect for the holidays, you can optionally replace the lobster with any other shellfish.
⏲️ Prep time: 20 🍳Cook time: 30 min 🍽️ Servings: 2 litres Ingredients 1 live lobster that weighs ~750 grams 2 onions 2 carrots 1 shallot 2 garlic cloves cognac 3 tbsp concentrated tomato puree 4 tomatoes 3 tbsp flour 1 glass dry white wine 2 litres fish stock 1 bayleaf 2 twigs of thyme fresh parsley heavy cream olive oil 2 tbsp butter Directions Finely dice the onions, carrots, shallots and garlic and set aside for later.</description></item><item><title>Fried Anglerfish fillet</title><link>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-anglerfish-fillet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/android_asset/html/posts/fried-anglerfish-fillet/</guid><description>This is a simple light-flavoured recipe. Anglerfish (I&amp;rsquo;m referring specifically to the &amp;lsquo;monfish/sea-devil&amp;rsquo; variant) meat is mild, absorbing the butter and subtle flavours of the herbs. Preparing the anglerfish is an involved process that I&amp;rsquo;ll try and explain to the best of my abilities but watching someone do it would be more then helpful.
Ingredients 1 Anglerfish Butter, enough to fry with Chives or green onions Marjoram, fresh herbs are preferable Directions Preparing the fish Turn the creature on its back.</description></item></channel></rss>